<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<body>
    <item>
        <header>Character Features and Creating Characters</header>
        <text><b>Extended Hit Points (XHP)</b>   Extended HP are a measure of a character's ability to turn a direct hit into a graze or a glancing blow with no serious consequences. XHP goes up with level, giving high-level characters more ability to shrug off attacks. Most types of damage reduce XHP. XHP increases as the character gains levels.</text>
        <text>The starting XHP formula is: <font fontName = "secondary">((3 + CON Modifier + COP Increase) X 2)</font>
        </text>
        <text><b>Core Hit Points (CHP)</b>   Core HP measures how much true physical damage a character can withstand. Damage reduces CHP only after all XHP are gone or when a character is struck by a Critical Strike. CHP is equal to CON+2,or uses the Racial Core Hit Point formula for all non-human characters.</text>
        <text>The CHP formula is: <font fontName="secondary">CON SCORE + 2</font>
        </text>
        <text><b>Combat Points</b>   Combat Points are a measurement of how much a character can do in a single round. Each character has 15 Combat Points per round, or uses their Racial Combat Point Score.
        </text>
        <text><b>Focused Skills</b>   This section of a character description denotes how many skills a character can select as focused skills, applying ranks to to them. A character only chooses these skills at 1ˢᵗ-level. A character gains at least 1 skill point per level, even if the character has an INT modifier penalty. A 1ˢᵗ-level character starts with 5 times the number of skill points they receive upon attaining each level beyond the 1ˢᵗ.</text>
        <text>The starting Skill Point formula is: <font fontName="secondary">((3 + INT Modifier + COP Increase) X 5)</font></text>
        <text>The leveling Skill Point formula is: <font fontName="secondary">(3 + INT Modifier + COP Increase)</font></text>
        <text>The Maximum Skill Point ranks for focused skills is: <font fontName="secondary">(Level + 4)</font></text>
        <text>The Maximum Skill Point ranks for unfocused skills is: <font fontName="secondary">((Level + 4) ÷ 2)</font>
        </text>
        <text><b>Base Attack Bonus(BAB)</b>   The character's Base Attack Bonus. Base attack bonuses start at +0.
        </text>
        <text><b>Fortitude/Reflex/Will Base Save Bonus (F/R/W BSB)</b>   The character's Base Save Bonus for Fortitude/Reflex/Will Save rolls. Base attack bonuses start at +0, modified by the specified ability score.
        </text>
        <text><b>Feats</b>   A character may select any feat. Some feats have prerequisites that must be met before a character can select them. All characters receive two feats every level. Humans gain an additional feat at the 1[superscript:st] level.
        </text>
        <text><b>Defense</b>   A character's Defense represents how hard it is for opponents to land a solid, damaging blow on the character. It is the attack roll result that an opponent needs to achieve to hit the character. A character's DEF is equal to: 10 + AGL Mod + Equipment bonus + Size Mod + Movement + Misc Mod
        </text>
        <text><b>Agility Modifier</b>   If a character's agility is high, they are particularly adept at dodging blows or gunfire. If a character's agility is low, they are particularly inept at it. Characters apply their AGL modifier to defense. Sometimes a character can't use their DEX bonus, this is what is what is called being “Flat Footed”.
        </text>
        <text><b>Equipment Bonus</b>   Armor provides Damage Reduction to anyone who wears it, but a character who is proficient in the use of a certain type of armor receives the bonus to DEF. This bonus represents the armor's ability to protect the character from blows. Sometimes a character can't use their equipment bonus to Defense, this is what is called being “Touch”. If an attack will damage the character just by touching them, that character can't add their equipment bonus.
        </text>
        <text><b>Size Modifier</b>   The bigger an opponent is, the easier it is to hit in combat. The smaller it is, the harder it is to hit. Since this same modifier applies to attack rolls a creature doesn't have a hard time attacking another creature of the same size.
        </text>
        <text><b>Movement Modifier</b>   When a combatant moves during combat, they become harder to hit. For every 10 feet beyond the first 30 feet a character moves they gain a +1 bonus to their DEF until their next turn.
        </text>
        <text><b>Miscellaneous Modifiers</b>   Other factors can add to a character's DEF, such as Feats, or Dodge Bonuses. Some feats give a bonus to a character's DEF. Some other DEF bonuses represent actively avoiding blows. These bonuses are called dodge bonuses. Any situation that denies a character their AGL modifier also denies their dodge bonuses.
        </text>
    </item>
</body>