<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<body>
<item>
<header level="0">﻿Dedications
</header>
<text>To Mom: Thanks for giving me encouragement in whatever I wanted to do.
To Awesome Josh and Ashley, Jay, Sam-The Dragon Lover: Thanks for all the months of fun and lessons about the world of Tabletop Games.
To /tg/: Couldn't have done it without the criticisms, advice, suggestions and help.
To /k/: Thanks for all the firearm knowledge. Couldn't have created the firearms list without you all.
To Alex, for giving me the title, bouncing ideas off of you, and giving me a ton of great ideas. Couldn't have done it without you.
To Moose and Craft for their sharp eyes to point out all of the errors that I’ve made, and Craft for his proofreading abilities.
To Conscript Gary for his voice of reason, and his wizardry with charts, graphs, and images.
To Hospes, for his knowledge on bows, and bow accessories, and the rest of the sup/tg/ crew, for those ideas!
To Boots, for the modifiers for melee so that melee can be more awesome,
To Roland, Archer, and Brandon for their services as playtesters, gun suggesters, and think-tankers,
To all those who have helped with this system in their help to make sure that it was as best as it could be,
And finally to all those that read and enjoy this, and may your games be fun, adventurous, and enjoyable.
Written and designed by Sweet Soul Bro !!H5XdMKmBv5G</text>
</item>
<item>
<header level="0">Credits
</header>
<text>This book and system are made and written under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.
All information was found using google from various firearms websites, my own knowledge, and Wikipedia. The Ops and Tactics copyright belongs to Sweet Soul Bro !!H5XdMKmBv5G. All listed firearms are owned by their respective companies, trademarks, copyrights and I do not take to claim any ownership of any. Please don't sue me, I have no monies.
Ops &amp; Tactics created by Sweet Soul Bro !!H5XdMKmBv5G
This document made by an anonymous editor, edited by Sweet Soul Bro !!H5XdMKmBv5G
v6.24 Complete Edition | Compiled  </text>
</item>
</body>