<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<body>
	<item>
		<header level = "0">Firearm Functionality</header>
<box>
<text>Firearm Functionality95.1 Firearm Basics</text>
</box>
		<text>   Once the gun is loaded, the shooter pulls the trigger to firetrigger mechanism moves an internal arm or lever, called the sear, which releases the weapon&#x27;s hammer or firing pin. The hammer springs forward, striking the back of the cartridge where the primer is located. The impact detonates the primer, which in turn ignites the propellant and fires the projectile. With single shot weapons, that is all that happens. The user must then manually cycle the action, which accomplishes three things. First, the empty cartridge case is extracted and ejected from the weapon. Then, the next cartridge in the magazine feeds into the firing chamber, or the user reloads the firearm by hand. Finally, the bolt closes on the chamber, which seals it, cocks the firing pin back, and readies the weapon for firing again. Double shot weapons can be fired twice, one for each barrel, before this must take place. On auto-loading weapons (those that operate semi-automatically or automatically), this process of cycling is carried out by the mechanical action of the weapon. The action cycles by itself, driven either by the recoil force or the pressure from the propellant gases. For semi-automatics, the user simply pulls the trigger again to fire another shot and repeat the cycle, until the magazine is emptied and the weapon must be reloaded. On automatic designs, the action will continue to cycle and fire as long as the trigger is held down or until the weapon runs out of ammunition. Select-fire weapons are those capable of firing in either semi-automatic or automatic mode, as desired. Bolt, Pump, and Lever action weapons require the user to work the action themselves, to remove the used casing, and chamber a new round into the barrel, to be fired again. Single Action firearms require the hammer to be pulled back manually, which prepares for the next shot to be fired.</text>
		<text>   Any firearm that uses a box magazine, or any lever action orTo put a cartridge in the chamber, the weapon is loaded as normal. (Chambering a round is part of the normal loading process.) Then the magazine is removed, an extra bullet or shell is added (to replace the one that was chambered), and the magazine is reinserted. This process takes 12 Combat Points. For lever action and pump action weapons, the weapon is loaded as normal. (Chambering a round is part of the normal loading process). Then an extra bullet or shell is added (to replace the one that was chambered), this process takes 4 Combat Points.</text>
		<text>   Generally, the closer a target is to the shooter, the easier itappears and the more difficult it is to hit. To counteract this difficulty, the use of telescopic scopes has become popular. A telescopic scope gives the shooter a magnified view of a distant target, facilitating aim. It also uses a targeting reticule or cross hair to identify the bullet&#x27;s point of impact. When a scope is fitted to a rifle, it must be zeroed, meaning that it must be adjusted so that the cross hairs accurately show the actual impact point at a given range. This process requires the Personal Weapons Proficiency feat, and 5 bullets or shells, as well as somewhere to test fire the weapon.</text>
		<header level = "1">Handguns</header>
		<text>   A handgun is a firearm designed to have the potential to beway. This characteristic differentiates handguns as a general class of firearms from long guns such as rifles and shotguns (which are usually mounted against the shoulder). Major handgun subtypes are the revolver and pistol, and are split into various subtypes based on size and use.</text>
		<text>   There are handguns that are available to suit nearly anymanufacturing, and low-quality materials are widely produced, while more reliable and sophisticated service weapons that are suitable for more active use form the middle of the market. At the high end are advanced custom pistols, produced for Olympic-class target shooting, exclusive private collections, or specialized forces, such as SWAT.</text>
		<text>   Handguns differ from long guns in the fact that they areand even caliber, can tell quite a lot about a character, and they are generally selected by hand, rather than issued. Handgun selection generally mirrors personal preference out in combat, more so than long guns as a handgun is generally always worn, and only drawn when needed. They are also easier to conceal than a long gun, allowing for a seemingly unarmed appearance when worn with the correct holster and clothing. A handgun should always be chosen carefully, the character&#x27;s personality, backstory, and preference should definitely have some sway and appearance in their choice.</text>
		<text>   A revolver is a repeating firearm that has a cylinderCapacity for a revolver can be as little as 3 rounds, and as many as 10, but 5 and 6 round cylinders are the most common. Revolvers predated semi-automatic pistols, praised in their time for their ability to fire multiple shots without reloading, nor resorting to having multiple barrels to do as such. Revolvers provide an advantage in the fact that a misfiring cartridge does not put a gunfighter out of commission; only a trigger pull is needed to advance to the next round. Revolvers are also generally less complicated on an end user level, being easier to maintain and operate, but much harder to repair. Revolvers, however, usually have low capacities, when compared to autoloading pistols (the highest capacity revolver at 10 rounds, is only the mid-level for an autoloading pistol), and nearly all models are unable to effectively use suppressors.</text>
		<text>   Revolvers themselves fall into various categories based on how</text>
		<text>   Single Action, Double Action, and Double Action Only</text>
		<text>   With a single action revolver (SA), the hammer is manuallyThis action advances the cylinder to the next round and locks the cylinder in place with the chamber aligned with the barrel. The trigger, when pulled, releases the hammer, which fires the round in the chamber. To fire again, the hammer must be manually cocked again. This is called “single action” because the trigger only performs a single action, of releasing the hammer. Because only a single action is performed and trigger pull is lightened, firing a revolver in this way allows most shooters to achieve greater accuracy. Additionally, the need to cock the hammer manually acts as a safety. The Colt Paterson Revolver, the Walker Colt, the Colt Dragoon and the Colt Single Action Army pistol of the American Frontier era are all good examples of this system. A single action revolver can be used to perform fanning attacks, where the supporting hand rapidly cocks the hammer back and the primary hand simply holds the trigger down, allowing for a volley of lead at a cost of accuracy.</text>
		<text>   With a double action (DA) revolver, the stroke of the triggercocked position, the cylinder begins to be indexed to the next round, and then the hammer is released to strike the firing pin. Thus double action means that a cocking action separate from the trigger pull is unnecessary; and every trigger pull will result in a complete cycle. This allows uncocked carry while also allowing draw-and-fire using only the trigger. A longer and harder trigger stroke is the trade-off, but this drawback can also be viewed as a safety feature, as the gun is safer against accidental discharges from being dropped.</text>
		<text>   Most double-action revolvers may be fired in two ways. The firstrevolver; the hammer is cocked with the thumb, which indexes the cylinder, and when the trigger is pulled, the hammer is tripped. The second way is double action.</text>
		<text>   Certain revolvers, called double action only (DAO), lack thecan only be fired in the double action mode. With no way to lock the hammer back, DAO designs tend to have bobbed or spurless hammers, and may even have the hammer completely covered by the revolver&#x27;s frame. These are generally intended for concealed carrying, where a hammer spur could snag when the revolver is drawn. The potential reduction in accuracy in aimed fire or the ability to perform a fanning attack is offset by the increased capability for concealment.</text>
		<text>   Front Loading Revolvers</text>
		<text>   The first revolvers were front loading, and were a bit likeThese were caplocks or “cap and ball” revolvers, because the percussion cap method of priming was the first to be compact enough to make a practical revolver feasible. When loading, each chamber in the cylinder was rotated out of line with the barrel, and charged from the front with loose powder and an oversized bullet. Next, the chamber was aligned with the ramming lever underneath the barrel. Pulling the lever would drive a rammer into the chamber, which sealed it and held the ball and powder securely in place. Finally, the user would place percussion caps on the nipples on the rear face of the cylinder.</text>
		<text>   After each shot, a user was advised to raise his revolverfragments of the spent percussion cap to fall out safely. Otherwise, the fragments could fall into the revolver&#x27;s mechanism and jam it. Caplock revolvers were also vulnerable to “chain fires”, wherein hot gas from a shot ignited the powder in the other chambers. This could be prevented by sealing the chambers with cotton, wax, or grease.</text>
		<text>   Loading a cylinder in this manner was a slow and awkward processsoldiers solved this by carrying multiple revolvers in the field. Another solution was to use a revolver with a detachable cylinder design. These revolvers allowed the shooter to quickly remove a cylinder and replace it with a full one, much like how modern pistols use magazines.</text>
		<text>   Fixed Cylinder Revolvers</text>
		<text>   In many of the first generation of cartridge revolverson which the cylinder revolved was removed, and the cylinder taken from the gun for loading. Later models used a loading gate at the rear of the cylinder that allowed one cartridge at a time to be accessed for loading, while a rod under the barrel could be pressed backwards to extract the fired case. Most revolvers using this method of loading are single action revolvers. The removable-cylinder design is employed in some modern “micro-revolvers” (usually in .22 caliber), in order to simplify their design. These weapons are small enough to fit in the palm of the hand.</text>
		<text>   The loading gate on the original Colt designs (and on nearly allAction Army) is on the right side, which was done to facilitate loading while on horseback; with the revolver held in the left hand, the cartridges can easily be ejected and loaded with the right.</text>
		<text>   Since the cylinder in these revolvers is firmly attached at thefull thickness all the way around, fixed cylinder revolvers are inherently strong designs. Because of this, many modern large caliber hunting revolvers tend to be based on the fixed cylinder design. Fixed cylinder revolvers can fire the strongest and most powerful cartridges, but at the price of being the slowest to load and cannot use speedloaders for loading, as one chamber is exposed at a time to the loading gate.</text>
		<text>   Top Break Revolvers</text>
		<text>   The next method used for loading and unloading cartridgeframe is hinged at the bottom front of the cylinder. Releasing the lock and pushing the barrel down exposes the rear face of the cylinder. In most top break revolvers, this act also operates an extractor that pushes the cartridges in the chambers back far enough that they will fall free, or can be removed easily. Fresh rounds are then inserted into the cylinder. The barrel and cylinder are then rotated back and locked in place, and the revolver is ready to fire.</text>
		<text>   Top break revolvers can be loaded more rapidly than fixed-framedesign is much weaker and cannot handle high pressure rounds. While this design is mostly obsolete today, supplanted by the stronger yet equally convenient swing out design, manufacturers have begun making reproductions of late 19th century designs for use in cowboy action shooting.</text>
		<text>   Swing Out Cylinder Revolvers</text>
		<text>   The last and most modern method of loading and unloading is thecoaxial with the chambers, and the cylinder swings out and down (to the left in most cases). An extractor is fitted, operated by a rod projecting from the front of the cylinder assembly. When pressed, it will push all fired rounds free simultaneously (as in top break models, the travel is designed to not completely extract longer, unfired rounds). The cylinder may then be loaded, singly or again with a speedloader, closed, and latched in place.</text>
		<text>   The pivoting part that supports the cylinder is called thethe method often portrayed in movies and television of flipping the cylinder open and closed with a flick of the wrist can in fact cause the crane to bend over time, throwing the cylinder out of alignment with the barrel. Lack of alignment between chamber and barrel is a dangerous condition, as it can impede the bullet&#x27;s transition from chamber to barrel. This gives rise to higher pressures in the chamber, bullet damage, and the potential for an explosion if the bullet becomes stuck.</text>
		<text>   The shock of firing can also put a great deal of stress on thepoint, the rear of the cylinder. Stronger designs use a lock in the crane as well as the lock at the rear of the cylinder. This latch provides a more secure bond between cylinder and frame, and allows the use of larger, more powerful cartridges. Swing out cylinders are rather strong, but not as strong as fixed cylinders, and great care must be taken with the cylinder when loading, so as not to damage the crane.</text>
		<text>   A single shot pistol is a type of handgun which uses a singlethen fired. A single shot pistol must be reloaded after every shot. Single shot handguns have generally fallen out of favor for revolvers and semi-automatic handguns because of their increased capacity and ease of loading, but still hold some value as last ditch and backup weapons. A semi-automatic pistol is a type of handgun which uses a single chamber and barrel, with a mechanism powered by the previous shot to load a fresh cartridge into the chamber. One round is fired each time the trigger of a semi-automatic pistol is pulled. A semi-automatic pistol harnesses the energy of one shot to reload the chamber for the next, typically via recoil operation, blowback, or gas operation. After a round is fired, the spent casing is ejected and a new round from the magazine is loaded into the chamber, allowing another shot to be fired as soon as the trigger is again pulled.Revolvers</text>
		<text>   A revolver is a repeating firearm that has a cylinderCapacity for a revolver can be as little as 3 rounds, and as many as 10, but 5 and 6 round cylinders are the most common. Revolvers predated semi-automatic pistols, praised in their time for their ability to fire multiple shots without reloading, nor resorting to having multiple barrels to do as such. Revolvers provide an advantage in the fact that a misfiring cartridge does not put a gunfighter out of commission; only a trigger pull is needed to advance to the next round. Revolvers are also generally less complicated on an end user level, being easier to maintain and operate, but much harder to repair. Revolvers, however, usually have low capacities, when compared to autoloading pistols (the highest capacity revolver at 10 rounds, is only the mid-level for an autoloading pistol), and nearly all models are unable to effectively use suppressors.</text>
		<text>   Revolvers themselves fall into various categories based on how</text>
		<text>   Single Action, Double Action, and Double Action Only</text>
		<text>   With a single action revolver (SA), the hammer is manuallyThis action advances the cylinder to the next round and locks the cylinder in place with the chamber aligned with the barrel. The trigger, when pulled, releases the hammer, which fires the round in the chamber. To fire again, the hammer must be manually cocked again. This is called “single action” because the trigger only performs a single action, of releasing the hammer. Because only a single action is performed and trigger pull is lightened, firing a revolver in this way allows most shooters to achieve greater accuracy. Additionally, the need to cock the hammer manually acts as a safety. The Colt Paterson Revolver, the Walker Colt, the Colt Dragoon and the Colt Single Action Army pistol of the American Frontier era are all good examples of this system. A single action revolver can be used to perform fanning attacks, where the supporting hand rapidly cocks the hammer back and the primary hand simply holds the trigger down, allowing for a volley of lead at a cost of accuracy.</text>
		<text>   With a double action (DA) revolver, the stroke of the triggercocked position, the cylinder begins to be indexed to the next round, and then the hammer is released to strike the firing pin. Thus double action means that a cocking action separate from the trigger pull is unnecessary; and every trigger pull will result in a complete cycle. This allows uncocked carry while also allowing draw-and-fire using only the trigger. A longer and harder trigger stroke is the trade-off, but this drawback can also be viewed as a safety feature, as the gun is safer against accidental discharges from being dropped.</text>
		<text>   Most double-action revolvers may be fired in two ways. The firstrevolver; the hammer is cocked with the thumb, which indexes the cylinder, and when the trigger is pulled, the hammer is tripped. The second way is double action.</text>
		<text>   Certain revolvers, called double action only (DAO), lack thecan only be fired in the double action mode. With no way to lock the hammer back, DAO designs tend to have bobbed or spurless hammers, and may even have the hammer completely covered by the revolver&#x27;s frame. These are generally intended for concealed carrying, where a hammer spur could snag when the revolver is drawn. The potential reduction in accuracy in aimed fire or the ability to perform a fanning attack is offset by the increased capability for concealment.</text>
		<text>   Front Loading Revolvers</text>
		<text>   The first revolvers were front loading, and were a bit likeThese were caplocks or “cap and ball” revolvers, because the percussion cap method of priming was the first to be compact enough to make a practical revolver feasible. When loading, each chamber in the cylinder was rotated out of line with the barrel, and charged from the front with loose powder and an oversized bullet. Next, the chamber was aligned with the ramming lever underneath the barrel. Pulling the lever would drive a rammer into the chamber, which sealed it and held the ball and powder securely in place. Finally, the user would place percussion caps on the nipples on the rear face of the cylinder.</text>
		<text>   After each shot, a user was advised to raise his revolverfragments of the spent percussion cap to fall out safely. Otherwise, the fragments could fall into the revolver&#x27;s mechanism and jam it. Caplock revolvers were also vulnerable to “chain fires”, wherein hot gas from a shot ignited the powder in the other chambers. This could be prevented by sealing the chambers with cotton, wax, or grease.</text>
		<text>   Loading a cylinder in this manner was a slow and awkward processsoldiers solved this by carrying multiple revolvers in the field. Another solution was to use a revolver with a detachable cylinder design. These revolvers allowed the shooter to quickly remove a cylinder and replace it with a full one, much like how modern pistols use magazines.</text>
		<text>   Fixed Cylinder Revolvers</text>
		<text>   In many of the first generation of cartridge revolverson which the cylinder revolved was removed, and the cylinder taken from the gun for loading. Later models used a loading gate at the rear of the cylinder that allowed one cartridge at a time to be accessed for loading, while a rod under the barrel could be pressed backwards to extract the fired case. Most revolvers using this method of loading are single action revolvers. The removable-cylinder design is employed in some modern “micro-revolvers” (usually in .22 caliber), in order to simplify their design. These weapons are small enough to fit in the palm of the hand.</text>
		<text>   The loading gate on the original Colt designs (and on nearly allAction Army) is on the right side, which was done to facilitate loading while on horseback; with the revolver held in the left hand, the cartridges can easily be ejected and loaded with the right.</text>
		<text>   Since the cylinder in these revolvers is firmly attached at thefull thickness all the way around, fixed cylinder revolvers are inherently strong designs. Because of this, many modern large caliber hunting revolvers tend to be based on the fixed cylinder design. Fixed cylinder revolvers can fire the strongest and most powerful cartridges, but at the price of being the slowest to load and cannot use speedloaders for loading, as one chamber is exposed at a time to the loading gate.</text>
		<text>   Top Break Revolvers</text>
		<text>   The next method used for loading and unloading cartridgeframe is hinged at the bottom front of the cylinder. Releasing the lock and pushing the barrel down exposes the rear face of the cylinder. In most top break revolvers, this act also operates an extractor that pushes the cartridges in the chambers back far enough that they will fall free, or can be removed easily. Fresh rounds are then inserted into the cylinder. The barrel and cylinder are then rotated back and locked in place, and the revolver is ready to fire.</text>
		<text>   Top break revolvers can be loaded more rapidly than fixed-framedesign is much weaker and cannot handle high pressure rounds. While this design is mostly obsolete today, supplanted by the stronger yet equally convenient swing out design, manufacturers have begun making reproductions of late 19th century designs for use in cowboy action shooting.</text>
		<text>   Swing Out Cylinder Revolvers</text>
		<text>   The last and most modern method of loading and unloading is thecoaxial with the chambers, and the cylinder swings out and down (to the left in most cases). An extractor is fitted, operated by a rod projecting from the front of the cylinder assembly. When pressed, it will push all fired rounds free simultaneously (as in top break models, the travel is designed to not completely extract longer, unfired rounds). The cylinder may then be loaded, singly or again with a speedloader, closed, and latched in place.</text>
		<text>   The pivoting part that supports the cylinder is called thethe method often portrayed in movies and television of flipping the cylinder open and closed with a flick of the wrist can in fact cause the crane to bend over time, throwing the cylinder out of alignment with the barrel. Lack of alignment between chamber and barrel is a dangerous condition, as it can impede the bullet&#x27;s transition from chamber to barrel. This gives rise to higher pressures in the chamber, bullet damage, and the potential for an explosion if the bullet becomes stuck.</text>
		<text>   The shock of firing can also put a great deal of stress on thepoint, the rear of the cylinder. Stronger designs use a lock in the crane as well as the lock at the rear of the cylinder. This latch provides a more secure bond between cylinder and frame, and allows the use of larger, more powerful cartridges. Swing out cylinders are rather strong, but not as strong as fixed cylinders, and great care must be taken with the cylinder when loading, so as not to damage the crane.</text>
		<text>   Single Shot and Semi-Automatic Pistols</text>
		<text>   A single shot pistol is a type of handgun which uses a singlethen fired. A single shot pistol must be reloaded after every shot. Single shot handguns have generally fallen out of favor for revolvers and semi-automatic handguns because of their increased capacity and ease of loading, but still hold some value as last ditch and backup weapons. A semi-automatic pistol is a type of handgun which uses a single chamber and barrel, with a mechanism powered by the previous shot to load a fresh cartridge into the chamber. One round is fired each time the trigger of a semi-automatic pistol is pulled. A semi-automatic pistol harnesses the energy of one shot to reload the chamber for the next, typically via recoil operation, blowback, or gas operation. After a round is fired, the spent casing is ejected and a new round from the magazine is loaded into the chamber, allowing another shot to be fired as soon as the trigger is again pulled.</text>
		<text>   Most types of semi-automatic pistols rely on a removableinside the grip. These magazines can hold anywhere from 3 to 100 rounds, though magazines between 5 and 20 are most common. Semi-automatic pistols provide an advantage in capacity, as they hold two to three times more than a revolver of similar size. Semi-automatic pistols are generally more complex to operate and maintain on an end user level, but easier to repair.</text>
		<text>   Semi-automatic pistols fall into various categories based on</text>
		<text>   Single Action, Double Action/Single Action, Double Action Only,</text>
		<text>   Typically, the first round is manually loaded into the chamberAfter the trigger is pulled and the round is fired, the recoil operation of the handgun automatically extracts and ejects the shell casing and reloads the chamber. This mode of operation generally allows for faster reloading, although semi-automatic pistols are potentially more prone to malfunctions than revolvers due to their more complex design and mechanism.</text>
		<text>   A single action (SA) semi-automatic pistol must be cocked bychambered, by cocking the hammer manually. The famed Colt M1911 is an example of this style of action. All SA semi-automatic pistols exhibit this feature, and automatically cock the hammer when the slide is first “racked” to chamber a round. A round can also be manually inserted in the chamber with the slide locked back. Then the safety can be applied.</text>
		<text>   Standard modern semi-automatic pistols are usually doublestriker may be either thumb-cocked or activated by pulling the trigger when firing the first shot. The hammer or striker is re-cocked automatically during each firing cycle. In double-action/single-action (DA/SA) pistols, the first pull of the trigger requires roughly twice as much pressure as subsequent firings, since the first pull of the trigger also cocks the hammer (if not already cocked by hand). The Beretta 92FS, a full-sized, service, semi-automatic pistol is an example of this style of action. A common mode of carry for DA/SA semi-automatic pistols is with the magazine full, a round chambered, and the gun holstered and uncocked with the external safety off.</text>
		<text>   A Preset Action (PA) is a blend of Single Action (SA), andloading the chamber, the hammer or striker will rest in a partially cocked position. The trigger serves the function of completing the cocking cycle and then releasing the striker or hammer. While technically two actions, it differs from a double action trigger in that the trigger is not capable of fully cocking the striker or hammer. It differs from single action in that if the striker or hammer were to release, it would generally not be capable of igniting the primer. Preset actions also benefit in the fact that the first shot has the same trigger pressure as the subsequent shots, but have a downside where the slide must be racked if the round fails to fire, in order to reset the action.</text>
		<text>   Some modern semi-automatic pistols are double action only (DAO);the hammer, striker, or firing pin, and will additionally release the same to fire a cartridge in one continuous motion. Each pull of the trigger on a DAO semi-automatic pistol requires the same amount of pressure. The Kel-Tec P-32 is an example of a DAO action. DAO semi-automatic pistols are most generally recommended only in the smaller, self-defense, concealable pistols, rather than in target or hunting pistols. A notable exception are Glock pistols which optimize preset triggers (similar to DAO) but the striker is partially cocked back as the slide closes. This allows for significantly shorter trigger pulls than DAO. The trigger spring can be replaced with a lighter one and paired with a low-strength sear connector resulting in lightened trigger pulls to improve a shooter&#x27;s accuracy.</text>
		<text>   Fixed and Removable Magazine</text>
		<text>   Nearly all semi-automatic pistols use a removable magazine,replaced in the pistol. This facilitates a much quicker reload time by carrying around more magazines that have been prefilled with ammunition. In most handguns, even with the magazine removed, it can still be fired if there is a round in the chamber.</text>
		<text>   The fixed pistol magazine generally uses stripper clips or loosemagazine, and then stowed or tossed away. These are generally slower than removable magazine pistols, as the action generally has to be locked back before reloading, and if a character is caught in the middle of reloading, they can not fire. Reloading also has to be done after the firearm has completely expended all of its ammunition (or all of the ammunition has been removed), which doesn&#x27;t allow for topping off rounds in a timely manner.</text>
		<text>   Most types of semi-automatic pistols rely on a removableinside the grip. These magazines can hold anywhere from 3 to 100 rounds, though magazines between 5 and 20 are most common. Semi-automatic pistols provide an advantage in capacity, as they hold two to three times more than a revolver of similar size. Semi-automatic pistols are generally more complex to operate and maintain on an end user level, but easier to repair.</text>
		<text>   Semi-automatic pistols fall into various categories based on</text>
		<text>   Single Action, Double Action/Single Action, Double Action Only,</text>
		<text>   Typically, the first round is manually loaded into the chamberAfter the trigger is pulled and the round is fired, the recoil operation of the handgun automatically extracts and ejects the shell casing and reloads the chamber. This mode of operation generally allows for faster reloading, although semi-automatic pistols are potentially more prone to malfunctions than revolvers due to their more complex design and mechanism.</text>
		<text>   A single action (SA) semi-automatic pistol must be cocked bychambered, by cocking the hammer manually. The famed Colt M1911 is an example of this style of action. All SA semi-automatic pistols exhibit this feature, and automatically cock the hammer when the slide is first “racked” to chamber a round. A round can also be manually inserted in the chamber with the slide locked back. Then the safety can be applied.</text>
		<text>   Standard modern semi-automatic pistols are usually doublestriker may be either thumb-cocked or activated by pulling the trigger when firing the first shot. The hammer or striker is re-cocked automatically during each firing cycle. In double-action/single-action (DA/SA) pistols, the first pull of the trigger requires roughly twice as much pressure as subsequent firings, since the first pull of the trigger also cocks the hammer (if not already cocked by hand). The Beretta 92FS, a full-sized, service, semi-automatic pistol is an example of this style of action. A common mode of carry for DA/SA semi-automatic pistols is with the magazine full, a round chambered, and the gun holstered and uncocked with the external safety off.</text>
		<text>   A Preset Action (PA) is a blend of Single Action (SA), andloading the chamber, the hammer or striker will rest in a partially cocked position. The trigger serves the function of completing the cocking cycle and then releasing the striker or hammer. While technically two actions, it differs from a double action trigger in that the trigger is not capable of fully cocking the striker or hammer. It differs from single action in that if the striker or hammer were to release, it would generally not be capable of igniting the primer. Preset actions also benefit in the fact that the first shot has the same trigger pressure as the subsequent shots, but have a downside where the slide must be racked if the round fails to fire, in order to reset the action.</text>
		<text>   Some modern semi-automatic pistols are double action only (DAO);the hammer, striker, or firing pin, and will additionally release the same to fire a cartridge in one continuous motion. Each pull of the trigger on a DAO semi-automatic pistol requires the same amount of pressure. The Kel-Tec P-32 is an example of a DAO action. DAO semi-automatic pistols are most generally recommended only in the smaller, self-defense, concealable pistols, rather than in target or hunting pistols. A notable exception are Glock pistols which optimize preset triggers (similar to DAO) but the striker is partially cocked back as the slide closes. This allows for significantly shorter trigger pulls than DAO. The trigger spring can be replaced with a lighter one and paired with a low-strength sear connector resulting in lightened trigger pulls to improve a shooter&#x27;s accuracy.</text>
		<text>   Fixed and Removable Magazine</text>
		<text>   Nearly all semi-automatic pistols use a removable magazine,replaced in the pistol. This facilitates a much quicker reload time by carrying around more magazines that have been prefilled with ammunition. In most handguns, even with the magazine removed, it can still be fired if there is a round in the chamber.</text>
		<text>   The fixed pistol magazine generally uses stripper clips or loosemagazine, and then stowed or tossed away. These are generally slower than removable magazine pistols, as the action generally has to be locked back before reloading, and if a character is caught in the middle of reloading, they can not fire. Reloading also has to be done after the firearm has completely expended all of its ammunition (or all of the ammunition has been removed), which doesn&#x27;t allow for topping off rounds in a timely manner.</text>
		<header level = "1">Personal Defense Weapons</header>
		<text>   A personal defense weapon (PDW) is a compact semi-automatic orgun, but firing a (often proprietary) rifle round, giving a PDW better range, accuracy and armor-penetrating capability than sub-machine guns, which fire pistol-caliber cartridges. The class of weapon as it exists today evolved as a hybrid between a sub-machine gun and a carbine, retaining the compact size and ammunition capacity of the former while adding the ammunition power, accuracy and penetration of the latter. For the context of this book, PDWs include sub-machine guns as well as machine pistols.</text>
		<text>   A machine pistol is a handgun-style, often magazine-fed andand normally chambered for pistol cartridges. The term is a literal translation of Maschinenpistole, the German term for a hand-held automatic weapon. While the dividing line between machine pistols and compact sub-machine guns is hard to draw, the term “sub-machine gun” usually refers to larger automatic firearms scaled down from a full-sized machine gun to fire handgun rounds, while the term “machine pistol” usually refers to a weapon built up from a semi-automatic pistol design. Machine pistols, however, break away from this definition with the new arrival of rifle caliber handguns, that are extremely cut down rifles, with a semi-automatic rate of fire, and lacking a stock.</text>
		<text>   In a law enforcement context, machine pistols are used bywhich are operating inside buildings and other cramped spaces, who need a small, concealable weapon with a high rate of fire. Bodyguards from police or government agencies sometimes carry concealed machine pistols when they are protecting high-risk VIPs. Criminal gang members such as narcotics traffickers also use machine pistols, typically guns which have been illegally converted to fire in a fully automatic fashion.</text>
		<text>   In a military setting, some countries issue machine pistols ascrews, helicopter crews, or tank crews. They have also been used in close quarters combat settings where a small weapon is needed.</text>
		<text>   A sub-machine gun is an automatic carbine, designed to firegun with the cartridge of a pistol, which allows for controllable automatic fire in a close setting. Sub-machine guns almost always have stocks, and are used like close ranged rifles.</text>
		<text>   In the early 20th century, experiments were made by convertingmachine pistols. Stocked automatic weapons firing pistol rounds were developed around the same time during World War I, by Italy, Germany, and the United States. The first dedicated designs were developed in the latter stages of World War I both as improvements on earlier stocked pistols, and to offer an advantage in trench warfare. They were popularized in the 1920s and 1930s as weapon of choice of American gangsters and police. Sub-machine guns rose to prominence as a front line close-quarters combat weapon and commando firearm during World War II. They are now widely used by police SWAT, military commando, paramilitary, and counter-terrorism team members for a variety of situations. Sub-machine guns are highly effective in close quarters; their lower-powered pistol cartridges make them generally more controllable in fully automatic fire compared to assault rifles, while their small size and light weight grant maneuverability. However, pistol cartridges generally have low effectiveness against targets protected by body armor or cover, and are short-ranged compared to intermediate and rifle cartridges.</text>
		<text>   Open vs. Closed Bolt</text>
		<text>   A semi or full automatic firearm is said to fire from an opento the rear. When the trigger is pulled the bolt goes forward, feeding a round from the magazine into the chamber and firing it. Like any other self-loading design without an external power supply, the action is cycled by the energy of the shot; this sends the bolt back to the rear, ejecting the empty cartridge case and preparing for the next shot. Generally, open bolt is used for automatic weapons and not for semi-automatic weapons.</text>
		<text>   Compared to a closed-bolt design, open bolt weapons generallybolt, saving on manufacturing costs. In automatic weapons an open bolt helps eliminate the dangerous phenomenon known as “cook-off”, wherein the firing chamber becomes so hot that rounds spontaneously fire without trigger input. Open-bolt designs typically operate much cooler than closed-bolt designs, making them more suitable for constant full automatic weapons such as machine guns.</text>
		<text>   Open bolt weapons are more prone to fire when dropped, and theready position, and so may require an additional ejector door or similar mechanism to exclude dust and dirt. Some open bolt designs can suffer “slamfire”, in which bolt retention fails and the weapon discharges even with no trigger input. Open bolt weapons can not chamber a round in the barrel, and thus are restricted to the amount of the rounds in the magazines. Accuracy can suffer somewhat in an open bolt design, but this is generally less of a concern in automatic weapons.</text>
		<text>   A semi or full-automatic firearm which is said to fire from achamber and the bolt and working parts are forward. When the trigger is pulled the firing pin or striker fires the round, the action is cycled by the energy of the shot sending the bolt to the rear which extracts and ejects the empty cartridge case, the bolt then goes forward feeding a fresh round from the magazine into the chamber, ready for the next shot.</text>
		<text>   Closed bolt designs are more accurate for the first round andparts to inhibit accuracy. The first round sits consistently in the chamber, which allows the topping off of a magazine, for +1 round. The action remaining closed the majority of the time prevents foreign debris from entering the gun.</text>
		<text>   Closed bolt weapons are generally more expensive to make, andseen in semi-automatic weapons, such as handguns, shotguns, and rifles.</text>
		<header level = "1">Rifles</header>
		<text>   A rifle is a firearm designed to be fired from the shoulder,rifling”) cut into the barrel walls. The raised areas of the rifling are called “lands,” which make contact with the projectile, imparting spin around an axis corresponding to the orientation of the weapon. When the projectile leaves the barrel, this spin lends gyroscopic stability to the projectile and prevents tumbling, in the same way that a properly thrown American football or rugby ball behaves. This allows the use of aerodynamically-efficient pointed bullets (as opposed to the spherical balls used in muskets and shotguns) and thus improves range and accuracy. The word “rifle” originally referred to the grooving, and a rifle was called a “rifled gun.” Rifles are used in warfare, hunting and shooting sports.</text>
		<text>   The rifle is the backbone of every modern infantry army, andwere a massive upgrade from the smoothbore muskets, which had troubles with accurate, precise fire because of their barrels. Rifles were initially single shot, muzzle-loading weapons. During the 18th century, breech-loading weapons were designed, which allowed the rifleman to reload while under cover, but defects in manufacturing and the difficulty in forming a reliable gas-tight seal prevented widespread adoption. During the 19th century, multi-shot repeating rifles using lever, pump or bolt actions became standard, further increasing the rate of fire and minimizing the fuss involved in loading a firearm. The problem of proper seal creation had been solved with the use of brass cartridge cases, which expanded in an elastic fashion at the point of firing and effectively sealed the breech while the pressure remained high, then relaxed back enough to allow for easy removal. By the end of the 19th century, the leading bolt action design was that of Paul Mauser, whose action—wedded to a reliable design possessing a five-shot magazine—became a world standard through two world wars and beyond. The Mauser rifle was paralleled by Britain&#x27;s ten-shot Lee-Enfield and America&#x27;s 1903 Springfield rifle models.</text>
		<text>   Rifles are split into categories by their size, accessories,</text>
		<text>   When selecting a rifle, a character should always consider manythe ammunition type, caliber, and accessories they will take use of. Rifles are best complimented with a variety of upgrades, and should take full use of them. Rifles are less personal weapons, more utilitarian weapons that are used and employed when needed, and stowed away when not.</text>
		<text>   Bolt Action</text>
		<text>   Bolt action is a type of firearm action in which the weapon&#x27;sbreech (barrel) with a small handle, most commonly placed on the right-hand side of the weapon. As the handle is operated, the bolt is unlocked, the breech is opened, the spent cartridge case is withdrawn and ejected, the firing pin is cocked (this occurs either on the opening or closing of the bolt, depending on design), and finally a new round/cartridge is placed into the breech and the bolt closed. Bolt action firearms are most often rifles, but there are some bolt action shotguns as well. Examples of this system date as far back as the early 19th century, notably in the Dreyse needle gun. From the late 19th century, all the way through both World Wars, the bolt action rifle was the standard infantry firearm for most of the world&#x27;s militaries.</text>
		<text>   In military and law enforcement use, the bolt action has beenthough the bolt action remains the dominant design in sniper rifles. Bolt action firearms are still very popular for hunting and target shooting. Compared to most other manually operated firearm actions, it offers an excellent balance of strength (allowing powerful chamberings), ruggedness, reliability, and potential accuracy, all with light weight and low cost. The major disadvantage is a marginally lower practical rate of fire than other manual repeating firearms, such as lever action and pump action, and a far lower practical rate of fire than semi-automatic weapons, but this is not an important factor in many types of hunting and target shooting.</text>
		<text>   Lever Action</text>
		<text>   Lever action is a type of firearm action which uses a levertrigger guard itself) to load fresh cartridges into the chamber of the barrel when the lever is worked. Most lever action firearms are rifles, but lever action shotguns and a few pistols have also been made. One of the most famous lever action firearm is undoubtedly the Winchester rifle, but many manufacturers—notably Marlin and Savage—also produce lever action rifles.</text>
		<text>   While lever action rifles were (and are) popular with huntersmilitary. One significant reason for this was that it is harder to fire a lever action from the prone position (compared to a bolt-action rifle), and while nominally possessing a greater rate of fire than bolt-action rifles, lever action firearms are also generally fed from a tubular magazine, which limits the ammunition that can be used in them. Pointed center fire Spitzer bullets, for example, can cause explosions in a tubular magazine, as the point of each cartridge&#x27;s projectile rests on the primer of the next cartridge in the magazines. The tubular magazine may also have a negative impact on the harmonics of the barrel, which limits the theoretical accuracy of the rifle. A tubular magazine under the barrel also pushes the center of gravity forward, which alters the balance of the rifle in ways that are undesirable to some shooters. However there are some lever rifles, such as the Winchester Model 1895 which saw service with the Russian Army in World War I, that use a box magazines.</text>
		<text>   Due to the higher rate of fire and shorter overall length thanthis day for sporting use, especially short- and medium-range hunting in forests, scrub, or bushland. Lever action firearms have also been used in some quantity by prison guards in the United States, as well as by wildlife authorities/game wardens in many parts of the world. An additional advantage over typical bolt-action rifles is the lack of handedness: lever actions like pump-actions are frequently recommended as ambidextrous in sporting guidebooks.</text>
		<text>   Pump Action</text>
		<text>   A pump action rifle is one in which the handgrip can be pumpedto chamber a fresh one. It is much faster than a bolt-action and somewhat faster than a lever action, as it does not require the trigger hand to be removed from the trigger whilst reloading.</text>
		<text>   The cycling time of a pump action is quite short, often lessgives a pump action the ability to cycle rounds of widely varying power that a gas or recoil operated firearm would fail to cycle. The simplicity of the pump action relative to a semi-automatic design also leads to improved durability and lower cost. It has also been noticed that the time taken to work the action allows the operator to identify and aim on a new target, avoiding a “spray and pray” usage. An advantage of the pump action over the bolt-action is its ease of use by both left- and right-handed users: like lever actions, pump-actions are frequently recommended as ambidextrous in sporting guidebooks.</text>
		<text>   Like most lever action rifles, most pump action rifles do notcartridges have to be inserted individually into the firearm, which can take more time to reload.</text>
		<text>   Self Loading</text>
		<text>   A semi-automatic, or self-loading rifle is a weapon whichafter firing—assuming cartridges remain in the weapon&#x27;s feed device or magazines. Typically, this includes extracting and ejecting the spent cartridge case from the weapon&#x27;s firing chamber, re-cocking the firing mechanism, and loading a new cartridge into the firing chamber. Although automatic weapons and selective fire firearms do the same tasks, semi-automatic firearms do not automatically fire an additional round until the trigger is released and re-pressed by the person firing the weapon.</text>
		<text>   While all basic firearm actions require the action to be cycledautomatic and selective fire actions are differentiated from other forms such as pump-action, bolt action, or lever action firearms by eliminating the need to manually cycle the weapon after each shot. For example, to fire ten rounds from a semi-automatic firearm or a selective fire weapon set to fire semi-automatically, the action would initially be cycled to load the first round and the trigger would need to be pulled ten times (once for each round fired). For the other forms, the weapon&#x27;s mechanism would require cycling manually prior to firing the next round. An automatic or a selective fire weapon set to fire automatically would be able to fire continuously as long as the trigger is held until the magazine or feed device runs out of ammunition.</text>
		<text>   Advantages of this type of action is that the weapon can firebreak sights on the target in order to ready another round.</text>
		<text>   The disadvantage are that a self loading weapon is almostand requires more maintenance.</text>
		<text>   A carbine is a longarm similar to, but shorter than, a rifle.same ammunition at a lower velocity due to a shorter barrel length, and as such, the range for carbines is usually less than their rifle counterparts.</text>
		<text>   The smaller size and lighter weight of carbines makes themjungle warfare, or when deploying from military vehicles. The disadvantages of carbines relative to rifles include inferior long-range accuracy and a shorter effective range. Being larger than a submachine gun, they are harder to maneuver in tight encounters where superior range and stopping power at distance are not great considerations. Firing the same ammunition as rifles gives carbines the advantage of standardization over those personal defense weapons (PDWs) that require proprietary cartridges.</text>
		<text>   One of the more unusual classes of carbine is the pistol caliberbecame common. These were developed as &quot;companions&quot; to the popular revolvers of the day, firing the same cartridge but allowing more velocity and accuracy than the revolver.</text>
		<text>   The primary advantages of a pistol caliber carbine are increasedsight radius), relatively low muzzle blast/flash/recoil, higher muzzle velocity and energy of a longer barrel for increased wounding potential and penetration (depending on the particular load used), and greater adaptability for easily accepting accessories such as optics, weapon lights, and lasers.</text>
		<text>   One less-noted advantage of PCCs is their lower muzzle reportwhen fired, they are less likely to cause permanent hearing damage when fired indoor without hearing protection - this can be an important consideration during home defense situations.</text>
		<text>   Compared to &quot;regular&quot; carbines/rifles (such as those in .223 Remeffective range, more pronounced trajectory, less power, and less effectiveness against body armor.</text>
		<text>   Carbines are issued to high-mobility troops such asmounted, supply, or other non-infantry personnel whose roles do not require full-sized rifles. Carbine rifles go well with tactical slings, or patrol slings, and the same accessories that would be outfitted on a full size rifle.</text>
		<text>   An assault rifle is an automatic rifle that Uses an intermediatestandard infantry weapons in most modern armies. Assault rifles are categorized in between light machine guns, which are intended more for sustained automatic fire in a light support role, and sub-machine guns, which fire a pistol cartridge rather than a rifle cartridge.</text>
		<text>   The term assault rifle is a translation of the German wordposition&quot;). The name was coined by Adolf Hitler to describe the Maschinenpistole 43, subsequently renamed Sturmgewehr 44, the firearm generally considered the first assault rifle that served to popularize the concept and form the basis for today&#x27;s modern assault rifles.</text>
		<text>   The translation assault rifle gradually became the common termStG 44. In a strict definition, a firearm must have at least the following characteristics to be considered an assault rifle: it must be an individual weapon with provision to fire from the shoulder (i.e. a buttstock); It must be capable of selective fire, It must have an intermediate-power cartridge: more power than a pistol but less than a standard rifle or battle rifle, its ammunition must be supplied from a detachable magazine rather than a feed-belt, and it should at least have a firing range of 300 meters (1000 feet). Rifles that meet most of these criteria, but not all, are technically not assault rifles despite frequently being considered as such. For example, semi-automatic-only rifles that share designs with assault rifles are not assault rifles, as they are not capable of switching to automatic fire and thus are not selective fire capable, and are noted as target rifles. Belt-fed weapons or rifles with fixed magazines are likewise not assault rifles because they do not have detachable box magazines.</text>
		<text>   The term &quot;assault rifle&quot; is often more loosely used forparticularly arms that fall under a strict definition of the battle rifle, or semi-automatic variant of military rifles such as AR-15s.</text>
		<text>   The US Army defines assault rifles as “short, compact,power between sub-machinegun and rifle cartridges.”</text>
		<text>   A battle rifle is a military service rifle that fires a fullof battle rifle is usually given to post-World War II select fire infantry rifles such as the H&amp;K G3, the FN FAL, or the M14, this term can also apply to older military bolt action or semi-automatic rifles such as the Mauser 98k or the M1 Garand. The battle rifle&#x27;s power and long-range accuracy are intended to engage targets at long distances, but this comes with a trade-off of length and weight that make it relatively cumbersome in close-quarter combat.</text>
		<text>   Recently, however, there has been a general backlash againsttheir having less range, penetration, and power than battle rifles. Recent conflicts in desert environments have underscored the need for greater range while developments in body armor have created a need for more powerful munitions. A consequence of this was the creation of the Squad Designated Marksman program in the U.S. Army and the Squad Advanced Marksman in the U.S. Marine Corps. The role of the designated marksman is to fill the &quot;marksmanship gap&quot; between the rifleman and the sniper. Instead of relying on the use of smaller, lighter weapons with a higher rate of fire to hit a target, these programs place greater emphasis on marksmanship training, allowing the squad to take advantage of the greater range and power of heavier weapons. This has marked the return of battle rifles in the form of marksman rifles, which are discussed next section.</text>
		<text>   Target rifles are semi-automatic rifles that use a varyingto the heavier battle rifle cartridges. Target rifles may retain and appear to be exactly like assault and battle rifles, even down to having part and magazine compatibility, but target rifles have a semi-automatic rate of fire only.</text>
		<text>   Assault rifles, battle rifles, and target rifles go well with aof a wide variety of upgrades.</text>
		<text>   A designated marksman rifle (DMR) is the weapon used by soldiersbetween a regular infantryman and a sniper and DMRs have been developed with this middle ground in mind.</text>
		<text>   These rifles have to be effective, in terms of accuracy andassault rifles, but do not require the extended range of a dedicated sniper rifle.</text>
		<text>   DMRs, however, often share some basic characteristics withthe DMs unit. DMRs may have an attached telescopic sight, quickly deployed stabilizing bipod to allow optimized accuracy and low-recoil in temporarily fixed situations or an adjustable stock. They will, though, generally retain semi-automatic firing capability (more rapid than bolt-action sniper rifles) and a larger magazine capacity of 10, 20, or 30 rounds depending on the firearm in question.</text>
		<text>   In military and law enforcement terminology, a sniper rifle is aat longer ranges than other small arms. A typical sniper rifle is built for optimal levels of accuracy, fitted with a telescopic sight and chambered for a military centerfire cartridge. The term is often used in the media to describe any type of accurized firearm fitted with a telescopic sight that is employed against human targets, although &quot;sniping rifle&quot; or &quot;sniper&#x27;s rifle&quot; is the technically correct fashion to refer to such a rifle.</text>
		<text>   The military role of a sniper, dates back to the turn of thedevelopment. Advances in technology, specifically that of telescopic sights and more accurate manufacturing, allowed armies to equip specially trained soldiers with rifles that enable them to deliver precise shots over greater distances than regular infantry weapons. The rifle itself could be based on a standard rifle (at first, a bolt action rifle); however, when fitted with a telescopic sight, it becomes a sniper rifle.</text>
		<text>   Modern Sniper Rifles can be divided into two classes: Military</text>
<list type="unordered">
<text>Military Sniper rifles aimed at military service are often designed for very high durability, range, reliability, sturdiness, serviceability, and repairability under adverse environmental and combat conditions, at the sacrifice of a small degree of accuracy. Military snipers and sharpshooters may also be required to carry their rifles and other equipment for long distances, making it important to minimize weight. Military organizations often operate under strict budget constraints, which influences the type and quality of sniper rifles they purchase.</text>
<text>Law Enforcement Sniper rifles built or modified for use in law enforcement are generally required to have the greatest possible accuracy, more than military rifles, but do not need to have as long a range. As law enforcement-specific rifles are usually used in non-combat (often urban) environments, they do not have the requirement to be as hardy or portable as military versions; nevertheless they may be smaller, as they do not need very long range. Some of the first sniper rifles designed specifically to meet police and other law-enforcement requirements were developed for West German police after the Munich massacre at the 1972 Summer Olympics. Many police services and law enforcement organizations (such as the U.S. Secret Service) now use rifles designed for law enforcement purposes.</text>
</list>
		<text>   An Anti-materiel rifle is a rifle designed to destroy at hardother combatants. Anti-materiel rifles are similar in form and appearance to modern sniper rifles and can often serve in that role, though they are usually chambered for cartridges more powerful than are normally required for neutralizing a human and can operate at a greater range. In general, anti-materiel rifles are chambered for 12.7x99mm NATO (.50 BMG), 12.7x108mm Russian, 14.5x114mm Russian, and 20mm cartridges. The large cartridges are required to be able to fire projectiles containing usable payloads such as explosives, armor-piercing cores, and incendiaries.</text>
		<text>   Due to the considerable size and weight of anti-materiel rifles3-man or larger teams become a necessity. The recoil produced by the employed cartridges dictates that these rifles are designed to be fired from the prone position. Bipods and muzzle brakes are used as accessories to employ these rifles as comfortably and accurately as possible. Firing several 12.7x99mm NATO, 12.7x108mm Russian, or larger calibers from the standing position or in a kneeling position would be very uncomfortable for the operator.</text>
		<text>   Bipods are mandatory, and various telescopic sights, tacticalanti-materiel rifles.</text>
		<header level = "1">Shotguns</header>
		<text>   A shotgun (also known as a scattergun and peppergun, ordesigned to be fired from the shoulder, which uses the energy of a fixed shell to fire a number of small spherical pellets called shot, or a solid projectile called a slug. Shotguns come in a wide variety of sizes, ranging from .22 inch bore up to 2 inch bore, and in a range of firearm operating mechanisms, including breech loading, single-barreled, double or combination gun, pump action, bolt, and lever action, semi-automatic, and even fully automatic variants.</text>
		<text>   A shotgun is generally a smoothbore firearm, which means thatfirearms, such as the musket, were widely used by armies in the 18th century. The direct ancestor to the shotgun, the blunderbuss, was also used in a similar variety of roles from self defense to riot control. It was often used by cavalry troops due to its generally shorter length and ease of use, as well as by coachmen for its substantial power. However, in the 19th century, these weapons were largely replaced on the battlefield with breechloading rifled firearms, which were more accurate over longer ranges. The military value of shotguns was rediscovered in the First World War, when American forces used 12 Gauge pump action shotguns in close-quarters trench fighting to great effect. Since then, it has been used in a variety of roles in civilian, law enforcement, and military applications.</text>
		<text>   The shot pellets from a shotgun spread upon leaving the barrel,which means that the energy of any one ball of shot is fairly low. In a hunting context, this makes shotguns useful primarily for hunting birds and other small game. However, in a military or law enforcement context, the large number of projectiles makes the shotgun useful as a close quarters combat weapon or a defensive weapon. Shotguns are also used for target shooting sports such as skeet, trap, and sporting clays.</text>
		<text>   Shotguns are widely used as a support weapon by police forces.much training, an officer will probably be able to hit targets at close to intermediate range, due to the “spreading” effect of buckshot. This is mainly a myth, due to the fact that the spread of shotgun at 25 feet, averages 8 inches, being very capable of missing a target. Some police forces are replacing shotguns in this role with carbine rifles such as AR-15s. Shotguns are also used in roadblock situations, where police are blocking a highway to search cars for suspects. Law enforcement agencies often use riot shotguns, especially for crowd and riot control where they may be loaded with less-lethal rounds. Shotguns are also often used as breaching devices to defeat locks.</text>
		<text>   The downside to shotguns, is that the shot quickly expends itsweapons, and even less-than-desirable medium range weapons. Shotguns, unlike any other weapon in Ops and Tactics, have their range penalties affect both their total damage, as well as their attack bonus.</text>
		<text>   Shotguns, like rifles, are separated by their actions.</text>
		<text>   Break Action</text>
		<text>   For most of the history of the shotgun, the break action breechthree subtypes: the traditional “side-by-side” shotgun features two barrels mounted one beside the other (as the name suggests), the “over-and-under” shotgun has the two barrels mounted one on top of the other, and the single barrel shotgun. Side-by-side shotguns were traditionally used for hunting and other sporting pursuits (early long barreled side-by-side shotguns were known as Fowling Pieces for their use hunting ducks and other birds), whereas over and under shotguns are more commonly associated with sporting use (such as clay pigeon/skeet shooting). Both types of double-barrel shotgun are used for hunting and sporting use, with the individual configuration largely being a matter of personal preference. Single barrel shotguns can be used for either use as well, but the single shot doesn&#x27;t permit a user to participate in certain types of clay shooting.</text>
		<text>   Most break action shotguns have two triggers, allowing the userdifferent loads, or fire both barrels at the same time, for twice the load at a target. The downside to having two separate triggers is that the user must shift their hand in order to be able to manipulate each trigger. A newer style is to have a single trigger that fires one barrel first, then the other, in a predetermined sequence, that is reset when the action is broken and reloaded. The advantage to this is that the user doesn&#x27;t have to shift their grip in order to fire quickly, but looses the ability to fire both barrels at once.</text>
<list type="unordered">
<text>Side-by-Side (SxS) shotguns have −1 attack penalty when aiming at the same target on the second shot, but a +1 attack bonus when aiming at a target adjacent to the first.</text>
<text>Over-and-Under (OxU) shotguns have no attack bonus or penalty.</text>
</list>
		<text>   In pump action shotguns, a sliding forearm handle (the pump)one while cocking the hammer or striker as the pump is worked. A pump gun is typically fed from a tubular magazine underneath the barrel, which also serves as a guide for the pump. The rounds are fed in one by one through a port in the receiver, where they are lifted by a lever called the elevator and pushed forward into the chamber by the bolt. A pair of latches at the rear of the magazine hold the rounds in place and facilitate feeding of one shell at a time. If it is desired to load the gun fully, a round may be loaded through the ejection port directly into the chamber, or cycled from the magazine, which is then topped off with another round. Well-known examples include the Winchester Model 1897, Remington 870, and Mossberg 500/590.</text>
		<text>   Pump action shotguns are common hunting, fowling, and sporting28 inches. They can also easily be used with an empty magazine as a single shot weapon, by simply dropping the next round to be fired into the open ejection port after the spent round is ejected. Pump action shotguns with shorter barrels and no barrel choke (or very little) are highly popular for use in home defense, military and law enforcement, and are commonly known as riot guns. The minimum barrel length for shotguns in most of the U.S. is 18” and this barrel length is the primary choice for riot shotguns. The shorter barrel makes the weapon easier to maneuver around corners and in tight spaces, though slightly longer barrels are sometimes used outdoors for a tighter spread pattern or increased accuracy of slug projectiles. Home defense/law enforcement shotguns are usually chambered for 12 gauge shells, providing maximum shot power and the use of a variety of projectiles such as 00 Buckshot, rubber, beanbag, and slug shells, but 20 gauge (common in bird-hunting shotguns) or .410 (common in youth-size shotguns) are also available in defense-type shotgun models allowing easier use by novice shooters.</text>
		<text>   A riot shotgun has many advantages over a handgun or rifle.Parabellum, .38 Special, .357 Magnum, .40 S&amp;W, .45 ACP and similar), a shotgun has far more power and damage potential, allowing a “one-shot stop” that is more difficult to achieve with typical handgun loads. Compared to a rifle, riot shotguns are easier to maneuver due to the shorter barrel, still provide better damage potential at indoor distances (generally 3-5 meters/yards), and reduce the risk of “overpenetration”; that is, the bullet or shot passing completely through the target and continuing beyond, which poses a risk to those behind the target through walls. The wide spread of the shot reduces the importance of shot placement compared to a single projectile, which increases the effectiveness of “point shooting” - rapidly aiming simply by pointing the weapon in the direction of the target. This allows easy, fast use by novices.</text>
		<text>   Pump action shotguns lacking a trigger disconnector can bedepressed whilst cycling the action. This permits a user to rapidly spray shells onto a target area and perform slamfire attacks.</text>
<box>
<text>Pump action shotguns have no attack bonus or penalty.  Lever Action</text>
</box>
		<text>   Lever shotguns, while less common, were popular in the lateprime examples. Initially very popular, demand waned after the introduction of pump action shotguns at the turn of the century, and production was eventually discontinued in 1920.</text>
		<text>   One major issue with lever actions (and to a lesser extent pumpor similar fragile materials (modern hulls are plastic or metal). As a result the loading of shells, or working of the action of the shotgun, could often result in cartridges getting crushed and becoming unusable, or even damaging the gun.</text>
		<text>   Lever shotguns have seen a return to the gun market in recent(chambering the .410 bore shotgun shell and using the action of the Winchester Model 94 series lever action rifle, hence the name), and a handful of other firearm manufacturers producing versions of the Winchester Model 1887/1901 designed for modern 12 Gauge smokeless shotshells with more durable plastic casings.</text>
		<text>   Autoloading</text>
		<text>   Gas, inertia, or recoil operated actions are other populargenerally referred to as autoloaders or semi-automatics. Instead of having the action manually operated by a pump or lever, the action automatically cycles each time the shotgun is fired, ejecting the spent shell and reloading a fresh one into the chamber. The first successful semi-automatic shotgun was John Browning&#x27;s Auto-5, first produced by Fabrique Nationale beginning in 1902. Other well-known examples include the Remington 1100, Benelli M1, and Saiga-12.</text>
		<text>   Some, such as the Franchi SPAS-12 and Benelli M3, are capablepopular for two reasons; first, some jurisdictions forbid the use of semi-automatic actions for hunting, and second, lower-powered rounds, like many less lethal cartridges, have insufficient power to reliably cycle a semi-automatic shotgun.</text>
		<text>   Autoloading shotguns also encompasses shotguns that are fully</text>
		<header level = "1">Machine Guns</header>
		<text>   A machine gun is a fully automatic mounted or portable firearm,ammunition belt or large-capacity magazine, typically at a rate of several hundred rounds per minute.</text>
		<text>   Machine guns are generally categorized as machine guns orbut is generally used when mounted on a stand or fired from the ground on a bipod. Light machine guns are small enough to be fired and hand held like a rifle, but the gun is more effective when fired from a prone position, while general purpose machineguns are almost always too heavy to be fired and held like a rifle, and are near required to be fired with support. The difference between machine guns and autocannons is based on caliber, with autocannons using calibers larger than 16mm.</text>
		<text>   Man-portable machine guns are split into two categories: lightautomatic weapons, automatic weapons used to give infantry squads a portable source of automatic, focused fire, that can be carried and maintained by one member of the unit, while general purpose machine guns, which can be used by one person, usually benefit greatly by having other soldiers help in the aspect of reloading, barrel changing, and carrying ammunition, because of the weight.</text>
		<text>   The machine gun&#x27;s primary role in modern ground combat is tothe enemy to take cover and reducing the effectiveness of his fire. This either halts an enemy attack or allows friendly forces to attack enemy positions with less risk. Because of this, most machine guns do not even posses a selector switch, and fire in automatic only mode.</text>
		<text>   Machine guns that used linked ammunition can sometimes equip</text>
		<header level = "1">Grenade Launchers, Rocket Launchers, and Mortars</header>
		<text>   A grenade launcher or grenade discharger is a weapon thatgreater distances than a soldier could throw it by hand. Grenade launchers can either come in the form of standalone weapons (either single-shot or repeating) or attachments mounted under the barrel of a rifle. Some rifles have been designed to fire rifle grenades, either from their muzzle or from a detachable muzzle-mounted launcher.</text>
		<text>   Most grenade launchers are man-portable, shoulder-fired weaponsmounted on armored vehicles. The most common grenade round in use by modern militaries is the 40 mm fragmentation grenade, which is effective against a wide range of targets including infantry and lightly armored vehicles. The ability of the grenade launcher to loft payloads in a high arc has resulted in many specialty grenades such as less-lethal sponge grenades.</text>
		<text>   A rocket launcher is any device that launches areference to mechanisms that are portable and capable of being operated by an individual. Weapon systems that fall into this category include the shoulder-launched missile weapon, the wider international term for any weapon that fires a rocket-propelled projectile at a target, yet is small enough to be carried by a single person, and fired while held on one&#x27;s shoulder. However, the term bazooka, is also often used for any shoulder-launched rocket weapon.</text>
		<text>   Specific types of rocket launchers within this group includetype of shoulder-launched anti-tank weapon designed by the Soviet Union; the anti-tank guided missile, a guided missile primarily designed to hit and destroy heavily-armored tanks and other armored fighting vehicles; and the man-portable air-defense systems, which provides shoulder-launched surface-to-air missiles.</text>
		<text>   A mortar is an indirect fire weapon that fires explosiveranges, and high-arcing ballistic trajectories. It is typically muzzleloading. A mortar is relatively simple and easy to operate. A modern mortar consists of a tube into which gunners drop a purpose-designed bomb. The tube is generally set at between 45 and 85 degrees angle to the ground, with the higher angle giving shorter firing distances. The bomb has no cartridge case; the propellant is attached to the bomb&#x27;s fins. When it reaches the base of the tube it hits a firing pin, which detonates the propellant and fires the projectile.</text>
		<text>   Mortars are portable, and usually used by infantry units. Thethe flexibility of small numbers, and mobility. Mortars are able to fire from the protection of a trench. In these aspects the mortar is an excellent infantry support weapon, as it can be transported over any terrain and is not burdened by the logistical support needed for artillery.</text>
		<text>   Backblast is a cone-shaped area behind a rocket launcher wherearea is dangerous to others, who may be burned by the gases or exposed to overpressure caused by the explosion. In confined spaces, common in urban warfare, even the operators themselves may be at risk.</text>
		<text>   All rocket launchers when fired, create a 10&#x27; cone directly</text>
	</item>
</body>