<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<body>
	<item>
		<header level = "0">Firearms Manufacturers</header>
<box>
<text>Firearms Manufacturers  Below listed is a list of manufacturers of firearms, and the histories behind the company.</text>
</box>
		<text>   Accu-Tek firearms are manufactured by Excell Industries,are generally low cost—perfect for those on a tight budget.</text>
		<header level = "1">Accuracy International</header>
		<text>   Accuracy International is a specialist British firearmssniper rifles, which are some of the most highly prized precision rifles around. The Arctic Warfare Super Magnum currently holds the record for the longest confirmed kill.</text>
		<header level = "1">American Derringer</header>
		<text>   American Derringer Corp is a Texas company, reviving the oldthem into modern calibers, such as .38 Special and .357 Magnum. The derringers are highly prized by collectors as each one is crafted by hand.</text>
		<header level = "1">AMT</header>
		<text>   Arcadia Machine &amp; Tool was a firearms manufacturer fromoften clones of existing firearms. Plagued by quality and reliability problems, the company went bankrupt and the assets and trademark were acquired by IAI (Irwindale Arms Incorporated).</text>
		<header level = "1">ArmaLite</header>
		<text>   ArmaLite is the name of a small arms engineering facilityFairchild Engine and Airplane Corporation. ArmaLite was responsible for small arm designs that evolved into many of the infantry weapons in service worldwide today, including the M16 assault rifles and the M4 carbine. The original ArmaLite ceased all operations in the early 1980s, and ArmaLite&#x27;s successor, ArmaLite, Inc. is currently located in Geneseo, Illinois. The company changed many hands, before landing in the hands of a former U.S. Army Ordnance officer, who now manufacturers a number of AR-15 and AR-10 based rifles, as well as a .50 caliber anti-materiel rifle.</text>
		<header level = "1">Astra</header>
		<text>   Astra was a Spanish weapons manufacturer founded on July 17,Pedro Unceta. First located in the city of Eibar, the stronghold of the Basque arms industry, the company moved in 1913 to Guernica. They produced various copies of more famous guns, such as the Mauser Broomhandle and the Browning Vest pocket pistol.</text>
		<header level = "1">Barrett Firearms Manufacturing</header>
		<text>   Barrett Firearms Manufacturing is an American manufacturer offor the single purpose of building semi-automatic rifles chambered for the powerful 12.7×99mm NATO (.50 BMG) ammunition, originally developed for and used in M2 Browning machine guns. Barrett began his work in the early 1980s and the first working rifles were available in 1982, hence the designation M82. Barrett designed every single part of the weapon personally and then went on to market the weapon and mass produce it out of his own pocket. He continued to develop his rifle through the 1980s, and developed the improved M82A1 rifle by 1986. Their most recognizable rifles are the Barrett M82 and the M95 anti-materiel rifles, firing the .50 BMG round. They also have produced assault rifles and machine guns.</text>
		<header level = "1">Benelli Arms</header>
		<text>   Benelli Arms is an Italian firearm manufacturer founded in 1967,used by military, law enforcement, and civilians all over the world. Particularly famous is the Benelli M3 12 gauge, used extensively by American SWAT teams, and the Benelli M4, used extensively by various organizations, including the USMC and the U.S. Army. Benelli also manufactures target pistols and shotguns for hunting and competition use, which are considered to be some of the best shotguns made.</text>
		<header level = "1">Pietro Beretta</header>
		<text>   Beretta is an Italian firearms manufacturer founded in 1526.enforcement, and military purposes. It is also known for manufacturing shooting clothes and accessories. Beretta is the oldest active firearms manufacturer in the world. Beretta is known for its broad range of firearms: side-by-side shotguns, over-and-under shotguns, hunting rifles, assault rifles, sub-machine guns, lever and bolt action rifles, single and double action revolvers and semi-automatic pistols. The model Beretta 92FS was the primary sidearm of the United States Army, Marine Corps, Air Force, the United States Border Patrol and the United States Immigration and Naturalization Services, designated the M9 pistol, and was the former sidearm of various large police departments, including the Los Angeles Police Department and the Los Angeles Sheriff&#x27;s Department, as well as fictional organizations, such as the Raccoon City Police Department. Other famous models include their newer line of handguns, the Px4 series, its carbine counterpart, the Cx4, and the machine pistol variant of the 92FS, the 93R. Beretta currently owns Benelli Firearms as well as their subsidiary Stoeger.</text>
		<header level = "1">Bersa</header>
		<text>   Bersa is an Argentine arms manufacturer located in the city ofenthusiasts for producing high quality guns at very reasonable prices and it spends very little money on advertisement. While strong and well built, nicely engineered, accurate, visually appealing and very reliable, Bersa handguns are not on par with the most prestigious brands (such as SIG or Beretta) when it comes to finishing. However, firearms made by such companies can cost twice as much or more compared to a Bersa pistol in the same caliber and with similar features. The Argentine company is often influenced by the German firearms manufacturer Walther in the design of its handguns; the Thunder 22, 32 and 380 are basically clones of the famous Walther PP and PPK, while the Thunder 9 and 40 are somewhat similar in appearance and some mechanical aspects to the Walther P88.</text>
		<header level = "1">Bond Arms</header>
		<text>   Bond Arms Inc. is a firearms manufacturer located in Granbury,Bond. The company became incorporated as Bond Arms in 1995 and was licensed by the BATFE as a firearms manufacturer and dealer. Bond Arms is the largest manufacturer of derringers in the firearms industry, popular for having two-shot derringers in calibers from .22 Long Rifle and .25 ACP up to .410 Bore and .45 Long Colt.</text>
		<header level = "1">Browning Arms Company</header>
		<text>   Browning Arms Company is a maker of firearms, bows and fishingfirearms, including shotguns, rifles, pistols, and rimfire firearms and sport bows, as well as fishing rods and reels.</text>
		<text>   The company was founded to market the sporting designs of JohnNearly all of John Browning&#x27;s designs have been manufactured by other companies, including Winchester, Colt, Remington, Fabrique Nationale de Herstal of Belgium, and Miroku. Browning is currently a fully owned subsidiary of Fabrique Nationale de Herstal (FN). Browning Arms Company is best known for the Browning BPS shotgun, the A-Bolt rifle, X-Bolt rifle, the Auto-5 semi-automatic shotgun, the BAR semi-automatic rifle, and the Hi-Power 9mm pistol. Browning also manufactures a set of trap shotguns in the Cynergy series.</text>
		<header level = "1">Bushmaster Firearms</header>
		<text>   Bushmaster Firearms International is a manufacturer andthe United States. Bushmaster&#x27;s product line revolves around semi-automatic pistol and rifle variants of the AR-15 design. Bushmaster is currently the best-selling brand for AR type firearms in the United States. Bushmaster is part of the Freedom Group, owned by Cerberus Capital Management.</text>
		<header level = "1">Calico</header>
		<text>   Calico Light Weapons Inc. is a privately held firearmsestablished in 1982 in Bakersfield, California, and released its first production weapon in 1985. Calico was sold in 1990 but remained in Bakersfield. The company was sold again in 1991 to the original concept designer, and in 1998 operations were moved to Sparks, Nevada, where replacement parts for existing weapons were produced. In 2006, Calico was sold once again, and moved to Hillsboro, Oregon, where full production of firearms resumed. Calico implemented a CNC machining process and upgraded materials used in manufacture. Additionally, there were minor redesigns of some production models to increase durability and reliability. Calico produces a line of pistols and pistol-caliber carbines which feature a top-mounted, helical-feed, high-capacity (50 or 100 round) magazine that ejects spent shells from a port in the bottom.</text>
		<header level = "1">Charter Arms</header>
		<text>   Charter Arms Co. is an American manufacturer of revolvers thatCharter Arms produced revolvers chambered in calibers .22 Long Rifle, .22 Winchester Magnum, .32 Long, .32 H&amp;R Magnum, .327 Federal Magnum, .357 Magnum, .38 Special and .44 Special. The most famous revolvers manufactured by Charter Arms are the .44 Special Bulldog and .38 Special Bulldog Pug.</text>
		<header level = "1">Cobray</header>
		<text>   The Cobray Company was a manufacturer of sub-machine guns andnon-lethal 37 mm launchers. They produced a copy of the Armsel Striker 12, the MAC-10, and MAC-11, in both full and semi-automatic only firing modes.</text>
		<header level = "1">Colt</header>
		<text>   Colt&#x27;s Manufacturing Company is a US firearms manufacturer,Colt. Colt is best known for the engineering, production, and marketing of firearms over the later half of the 19th and the 20th century. Colt&#x27;s earliest designs played a major role in the popularization of the revolver and the shift away from earlier single-shot pistols. While Sam Colt did not invent the revolver concept, his designs resulted in the first very successful ones.</text>
		<text>   The most famous Colt products include the Walker Colt, Singleworked for Colt for a time, and came up with a design for a semiautomatic pistol, which debuted as the Colt M1900 pistol and eventually evolved into the Colt M1911 pistol. Though they did not develop it, for a long time Colt was primarily responsible for all M16 rifle production, as well as of many derivative firearms. The most successful and famous of these are numerous M16 carbines, including the Colt Commando family and the M4.</text>
		<header level = "1">CZ</header>
		<text>   CZUB (Ceská zbrojovka Uherský Brod) was established in 1936 as atown of Uherský Brod in Czechoslovakia, now in the Czech Republic. They manufacture a wide line of handguns and machine pistols, the most popular being the Cz 75 9mm pistol, as well as a number of surplus handguns, such as the CZ-82 pistol.</text>
		<header level = "1">Daewoo</header>
		<text>   S&amp;T Daewoo (formerly Daewoo Precision Industries) is a Southfirearms equip most frontline units of the Republic of Korea Armed Forces. They produce licensed copies of the M1911 handgun, the USAS-12 automatic shotgun, and the K1, 2, and 3 series of rifles.</text>
		<header level = "1">FN</header>
		<text>   Fabrique Nationale d&#x27;Herstal—self identified as FN Herstal andfirearms manufacturer located in Herstal, Belgium. FN is a subsidiary of the Belgian Herstal Group, which also owns U.S. Repeating Arms Company (Winchester) and Browning Arms Company. FN Herstal is the parent company of two United States entities: FN Manufacturing and FNH USA. FN Manufacturing, located in Columbia, South Carolina, is the manufacturing branch of FN Herstal in the United States, producing firearms such as the M249 and M240 machine guns and M16 rifle, among others. FNH USA, located in McLean, Virginia, is the sales and marketing branch of FN Herstal in the United States. Firearms designed and/or manufactured by FN include the Browning Hi-Power, Five-seveN, FAL, FNC, F2000, P90, M2 Browning, MAG, and Minimi. FN Herstal&#x27;s firearms are used by the armed forces of over 100 countries.</text>
		<header level = "1">Franchi</header>
		<text>   Luigi Franchi S.p.A. is an Italian manufacturer of firearms,the military SPAS-12 and SPAS-15 and the sporting-type long-recoil action AL-48. Franchi are renowned for their semi-automatic shotguns and are a division of Benelli. Franchi remained a family business since its founding until 1987, when it was acquired by the industrial conglomerate Socimi, based in Milan; with the bankruptcy of Socimi in 1993, Franchi was acquired by the Beretta Holdings which is the current owner.</text>
		<header level = "1">Glock</header>
		<text>   Glock Ges.m.b.H. (trademarked as GLOCK) is a weaponsafter its founder, Gaston Glock. While the company is best known for its line of striker-fired polymer-framed pistols, it also produces field knives, entrenching tools, and apparel.</text>
		<text>   Glock handguns are used by armed forces and law enforcementenforcement agencies. Glock handguns are also very popular with civilians for personal protection and practical shooting, and the company sponsors a competitive shooting team which travels worldwide. Glock produces more than two dozen models of handguns in seven different calibers.</text>
		<header level = "1">HK</header>
		<text>   Heckler &amp; Koch (HK) is a German defense manufacturing companythe SA80, MP5, G3, G36, HK 416, MP7, the USP series of handguns, and the high-precision PSG1. All firearms made by HK are named by a prefix and the official designation, with suffixes used for variants.</text>
		<text>   HK has a history of innovation in firearms, such as the use offlashlights on handguns. HK also developed modern polygonal rifling, noted for its high accuracy, increased muzzle velocity, and barrel life. Not all of its technologically ambitious designs have translated into commercially successful products (for instance, the advanced but now abandoned G11 assault rifle, which fired caseless high-velocity ammunition). HK produces a whole range of small arms, from pistols to grenade launchers and machine guns. In its extensive product range, HK has used most of the operating systems for small arms: blowback operation, short-recoil, roller-delayed blowback, gas-delayed blowback, and gas operation.</text>
		<header level = "1">Hämmerli</header>
		<text>   Hämmerli is a Swiss manufacturer of firearms aimed mostly atergonomics, but these come at a high price.</text>
		<header level = "1">Henry Repeating Arms</header>
		<text>   Henry Repeating Arms is a firearms manufacturing company thatRepeating Arms takes its name from Benjamin Tyler Henry, the inventor who patented the first repeating rifle in 1860. The company also produces bolt action and pump-action rimfire rifles as well as a new generation of the AR-7 takedown rifle, now known as the Henry US Survival rifle, which was originally designed for the United States Air Force. The Henry Golden Boy is the company&#x27;s signature model, featuring a Brasslight receiver and octagonal barrel. A larger caliber centerfire version is known as the Henry Big Boy.</text>
		<header level = "1">Hi-Point</header>
		<text>   Hi-Point Firearms is a firearms manufacturer based in Mansfield,.380 ACP, .40 S&amp;W and .45 ACP. The semi-automatic pistols are polymer-framed and generally regarded as simple, inexpensive handguns, which trade-off aesthetics for lower manufacturing cost, and ruggedness.</text>
		<header level = "1">Israel Military Industries</header>
		<text>   Israel Military Industries Ltd. (IMI) is an Israeli weaponstechnology mainly for Israeli security forces (especially the IDF), although its small arms are very popular throughout the world. Popular firearms include the world famous Desert Eagle family of handguns, Uzi, Negev LMG, and the Galil and Tavor assault rifles.</text>
		<header level = "1">Intratec</header>
		<text>   Intratec was a firearms company based in Miami, Florida. TheInterdynamic USA, an offshoot of Swedish firearms manufacturer Interdynamic AB. Due to the lack of firearm market in Sweden, Interdynamic AB set up a subsidiary in the United States to sell the KG-9. This company eventually became Intratec and continued to sell variants of the KG-9 which was renamed to TEC-9. It went out of business in 2001 under pressure of lawsuits and the anti-gun movement.</text>
		<header level = "1">Ithaca Gun Company</header>
		<text>   The Ithaca Gun Company is a firearms manufacturer of rifles andbuilding firearms based on expired Remington patents, as well as their model of the M1911 .45 ACP handgun and M3 grease gun for the US during World War II. Its 12 gauge shotguns were the standard and are still in use today by some departments. Popular firearms include the various versions of the Ithaca 37 pump action shotgun and the M3 Grease Gun.</text>
		<header level = "1">IZHMASH</header>
		<text>   The Izhevsk Machine building Plant is a Russian weaponsTsar Alexander I, and is now one of the largest corporations in its field. It manufactures the famous Kalashnikov series of assault rifle, along with a host of other Russian arms, including medium cannons, missiles, and guided shell. They have manufactured such iconic arms as the Mosin-Nagant, SKS-45, SVT-40, the Saiga series of rifles and shotguns, and the entire series of AK rifles, including the AK-47, AKM, AK-101, AK-103, and AK-12.</text>
		<header level = "1">IZHMEKH</header>
		<text>   The Izhevsk Mechanical Plant is a major russian firearmsarms. After the end of World War II it continued producing firearms, both for military and hunting applications, and later high-tech weapons and civilian machinery. Notable and popular firearms include the “Baikal” shotguns and the Makarov pistol.</text>
		<header level = "1">Jimenez Arms, Bryco Arms, Jennings Firearms</header>
		<text>   Jimenez Arms, also known as “J.A.”, is an American firearmsin August 2004 using the molds and machinery from bankrupt Bryco Arms and currently makes five models of firearm, the J.A.-NINE a, J.A.-380, J.A.-22, J.A.-32 ,and the J.A.-25, which are all low cost, affordable firearms.</text>
		<header level = "1">Kahr Arms</header>
		<text>   Kahr Arms is an American small arms manufacturer specializing incartridges, including .380 ACP, 9x19mm, .40 S&amp;W, and .45 ACP. Kahr pistols feature polymer or stainless steel frames, single-stack magazines, and double-action-only striker firing actions. Company headquarters is in Blauvelt, New York and the Kahr manufacturing facility is located in Worcester, Massachusetts. The Kahr K9 is a popular backup weapon with the New York City police officers, even to this day. Popular firearms include the aforementioned Kahr K9 and K40, as well as their various polymer versions of their handguns, the PM Series.</text>
		<header level = "1">Kel-Tec</header>
		<text>   Kel-Tec is a US manufacturer of firearms based in Cocoa,rifles and shotguns, touted as the third largest manufacturer of handguns in all of the United States. Notable firearms include the P-11, the Sub-2000, and the SU-16 Series of rifles, as well as the PLR-16, a long range rifle based on the SU 16, and the PMR30 handgun, the RFB rifle and the KSG Shotgun.</text>
		<header level = "1">Korth</header>
		<text>   Korth is a manufacturer of high end revolvers, and autoloadinghandguns are very limited and are high end, custom, usually one of a kind pieces of work.</text>
		<header level = "1">Marlin Firearms</header>
		<text>   Marlin Firearms Co. formerly of North Haven, Connecticut, was acaliber rimfire rifles. In the past, the company made shotguns, derringers and revolvers. Marlin owned the firearm manufacturer H &amp; R Firearms, and was owned by Remington Arms, part of the Freedom Group.</text>
		<text>   Marlin Firearms was issued a patent for their specialtyinstead of the standard ballard or cut rifling. This has lead to their increased accuracy with factory ammunition, but on the downside, makes them less accurate with handloaded ammunition, because of the bullet diameter. Popular firearms include the Marlin Model 20 bolt action rifle, the Marlin 1879 and the Marlin Model 336 lever action rifles.</text>
		<header level = "1">O.F. Mossberg &amp; Sons</header>
		<text>   O.F. Mossberg &amp; Sons (commonly known as Mossberg) is an Americanand firearm accessories. From the 1940s through the 1960s, it also produced a line of .22 caliber target and sporting rifles. Mossberg also soon produced gun racks, golf clubs, campers and sailboats, while maintaining the core sporting firearms business. The company has remained a family-owned business to this day, and is the oldest family-owned firearms manufacturer in America. Popular firearms include their flagship products, the Mossberg 500 and 590 pump action shotguns, the both being used currently by the U.S. Marine Corp and the U.S. Army, and the Mossberg 930 semi-auto shotgun.</text>
		<text>   Mossberg also owns a subsidiary called Maverick Arms, aimed at athese being the Maverick 88 pump action shotgun.</text>
		<header level = "1">Norinco</header>
		<text>   Norinco (China North Industries Corporation) is a multi-marketvehicles (trucks, cars, and motorcycles), machinery, optical-electronic products, oil field equipment, chemicals, light industrial products, explosives and blast materials, civil and military firearms and ammunition, known for producing copies of popular firearms. Popular firearms include their copies of the 1911A1, Sig P226 and P220, AK-47 and AKM, M14, Cz75, as well as their own production firearms, the QBZ series of assault rifles, made for the People&#x27;s Liberation Army.</text>
		<header level = "1">North American Arms</header>
		<text>   North American Arms is a US company, headquartered in Provo,specialize in pocket pistols that are barely three to four inches in length. Popular firearms include the NAA mini revolver, and the NAA Guardian.</text>
		<header level = "1">Para-Ordnance</header>
		<text>   Para-Ordnance is a Canadian firearms manufacturer founded infactory in Scarborough, Ontario, Canada. The company originally started out manufacturing sub-machine gun paintball guns, but soon transitioned to the manufacturing of handguns.</text>
		<text>   Para-Ordnance is the originator of the high magazine capacityfor the law enforcement, military, and civilian markets. The company has created a true double-stack 1911 pistol, in addition to single- and double-stack pistols in .45 ACP, .40 S&amp;W, 9mm, and .38 super calibers. Para pistols have found a variety of uses, including competition, law enforcement, concealed carry, and general target shooting. Popular firearms include the P14-45, the P18-9, and the P16-40 handguns.</text>
		<header level = "1">Remington Arms</header>
		<text>   Remington Arms Company, Inc. was founded in 1816 by Eliphaletoldest company in the United States which still makes its original product, and is the oldest continuously operating manufacturer in North America. It is the only U.S. company which produces both firearms and ammunition domestically, and is the largest U.S. producer of shotguns and rifles.</text>
		<text>   Remington has produced a number of iconic firearms, such as thelaw enforcement agencies, the Model 700 bolt action rifle, the basis for the M24 SWS, used by the United States Army as their standard sniper rifle, and the Model 1100 series of Semi-automatic Shotguns.</text>
		<header level = "1">Rheinmetall AG</header>
		<text>   Rheinmetall AG is a German automotive and defense company withlong tradition of making guns and artillery pieces. The company is also involved in a variety of advanced metal-working and milling technologies, allowing it to provide special high-quality components for small arms in addition to heavy weapon production.</text>
		<text>   Popular weapons include the MG3 machine gun and the 120mm M1</text>
		<header level = "1">Royal Small Arms Factory Enfield</header>
		<text>   The Royal Small Arms Factory (RSAF) was a UK government-ownedgenerally known as the Lea Valley. The factory produced British military rifles, muskets, and swords from 1816. It closed in 1988, but some of its work was transferred to other sites. Popular and famous firearms include the FAL battle rifle, L85 assault rifle, Sten sub-machine gun, and the Lee-Enfield bolt action rifle.</text>
		<header level = "1">Sturm, Ruger &amp; Co., Inc.</header>
		<text>   Sturm, Ruger &amp; Company was founded by William B. Ruger andin Southport, Connecticut. Just prior to their partnership, Bill Ruger had successfully duplicated two Baby Nambu pistols in his garage, from a captured Nambu that he acquired from a returning US Marine, at the close of World War II. When it came to designing their first auto pistol, Ruger decided to incorporate the looks of the German 9mm Luger and the American Colt Woodsman into their first commercially produced .22 caliber pistol, which became so successful that it launched the entire company.</text>
		<text>   Ruger has been under fire with the firearms community for hishonest man needs more than ten rounds” and would not sell high capacity magazines to civilians. Despite this, Ruger firearms are still some of the most prized firearms to this day. Popular firearms include the Ruger Mark II and III, SP101, 10/22, and the famous Mini-14.</text>
		<header level = "1">Smith &amp; Wesson</header>
		<text>   Smith &amp; Wesson a manufacturer of handguns and rifles in theMassachusetts. Founded in 1852, Smith &amp; Wesson&#x27;s pistols and revolvers have become standard issue to police and armed forces throughout the world. They are also used by sport shooters and have been featured in numerous Hollywood movies. Smith &amp; Wesson has been known for the many types of ammunition it has introduced over the years, and many cartridges bear the company&#x27;s name.</text>
		<text>   Popular firearms are numerous, including the Model 10, Model 36,of autoloading S&amp;W handguns, such as the 59, 669, and the 5906.</text>
		<header level = "1">SIG Sauer</header>
		<text>   SIG Sauer GmbH is the German representative of Switzerland-basedSchweizerische Industrie Gesellschaft (SIG) in 2000. SIG Sauer Inc. was established in 1985 with the name Sigarms to import and distribute SIG firearms into the United States, although it now also has some manufacturing capabilities. Since 2000 it has been a separate entity.</text>
		<header level = "1">Springfield Armory, Inc.</header>
		<text>   Springfield Armory, Inc. is a firearms manufacturer and importerlargest firearms marketers of imported firearms in the United States. They import the HS2000, which they market as the XD series of handguns, and produce semi-automatic copies of the M14 rifle, named the M1A, as well as copies of the M1911A1 handgun, in various calibers.</text>
		<header level = "1">Stoeger Industries</header>
		<text>   Stoeger Industries is a manufacturer and importer of firearmsIndustries&#x27; headquarters are in Accokeek, Maryland, United States. Stoeger is a wholly owned subsidiary of Benelli, which in turn is owned by Italian firearms manufacturer Beretta. Popular firearms include the Stoeger Cougar, a licensed copy of the Beretta 8000, and the M2000, a semi-automatic shotgun.</text>
		<header level = "1">Steyr Mannlicher</header>
		<text>   Steyr Mannlicher is a firearms manufacturer based in the city ofmanufacturing conglomerate, it became independent when the conglomerate was broken in 1990.</text>
		<text>   Steyr has produced the AUG for the Austrian army, and is quitelength barrel.</text>
		<header level = "1">Taurus</header>
		<text>   Forjas Taurus is a manufacturing conglomerate based in Portocompany now consists of divisions focusing on firearms, metals manufacturing, plastics, body armor, helmets, and civil construction.</text>
		<text>   Taurus produces a number of variants on popular manufacturers,the firearms industry for pushing the envelope on designs, producing a 5 shot revolver that fires .410 bore shotgun shells, and the first revolver with a polymer frame, as well as various revolvers chambered for rounds traditionally thought of as autoloader rounds, such as 9x19mm, .40 S&amp;W, .45 ACP, and even some rifle rounds, such as the .30 Carbine.</text>
		<text>   Popular firearms include their variant on the 1911, the PT92, aof handguns, as well as their revolver that fires both .410 bore shotgun shells and .45 Long Colt rounds, the Taurus Judge.</text>
		<header level = "1">Walther Arms</header>
		<text>   Carl Walther GmbH Sportwaffen or Walther is a German armsdevelopment of pistols.</text>
		<text>   Popular firearms include the PPK and the P99—both pistolsstandard-issue sidearm of the German military in World War II.</text>
	</item>
</body>