<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<body>
	<item>
		<header level = "0">Snipers</header>
<text><b>Snipers</b></text>
		<text>   These rules are instructions and hints involved with playing aapplicable gear they should and do use, and the aspects of snipers in games from both a player and GM standpoint.</text>
		<header level = "1">What is a Sniper?</header>
		<text>   A sniper is a highly trained marksman who operates alone, in athe enemy and engage targets from concealed positions or distances exceeding the detection capabilities of enemy personnel. These sniper teams operate independently, with little combat asset support from their parent units.</text>
		<text>   Snipers come in two forms: Military Snipers and Police Snipers.</text>
		<text>   Military Snipers</text>
<box>
<text>Military snipers are the generators of the definition of sniper. expert knowledge in snipercraft. Marksmanship is important, but their job usually entails being out in the field, watching and giving intelligence back to the main base and other squads, as well as providing overwatch and cover. Snipercraft, such as stealth, camouflage, movement, tracking and moving without being tracked, deep survival, and most importantly, patience, are heavily trained and have strict requirements that must be passed in training before a soldier can be called a sniper.</text>
</box>
		<text>   Police Snipers</text>
<box>
<text>Police snipers are a much newer breed of sniper, compared to on intelligence, and high risk engagements. They are usually covered by other officers when they are engaging a target, which negates the necessity for a lot of aspects that military snipers focus on. What they do focus on is marksmanship, and neutralizing a target in high risk situations. Another aspect that is unique to police snipers is the fact that they are often patrol officers, who perform all of the duties expected of a patrol officer, in addition their S.W.A.T. and sniper duties when they are called on.</text>
</box>
		<header level = "1">Sniper Basics</header>
		<text>   A sniper is no good without tools. The first and foremostrarely an off-the-shelf model, instead tuned and customized to that particular sniper&#x27;s requirements and taste. It will have at least a 3× telescopic sight. It can be bolt action or semi-automatic, with semi-automatic becoming more popular. It is also chambered in a common, high-powered cartridge, such as the 7.62x51mm, 5.56x45mm, .338 Lapua Magnum, or .300 Winchester Magnum. Snipers should also invest in upgrades that increase the range and accuracy of their rifle, such as the heavy barrel upgrade, match barrel upgrade, and ergonomic stock upgrade.</text>
		<text>   Snipers should also invest in a good sidearm, since the mainranges. A good handgun or compact machine pistol makes a proper sidearm.</text>
		<text>   A sniper should place themselves and strive to have a majorityto maximize their effectiveness.</text>
		<header level = "1">Playing a Sniper and GMing for a Sniper</header>
		<text>   Playing a sniper is vastly different from any other style ofsome time to setup and prepare for the oncoming battle. Instead of choosing a spot within the battlefield, a sniper will sit off-grid, at a specified distance from the battlefield, usually at a high vantage point if possible. For the purpose of ranging shots, a token will be placed on the corner of the battle map that represents the sniper&#x27;s location, from that distance. Any shots taken by the sniper will be calculated from that spot, adding the distance the sniper is away from that point to the total range.</text>
		<text>   Snipers and spotters are also not apart of the standardspotters can choose to either be placed at the top of the Initiative, or the bottom, acting either before everyone else, or after everyone has.</text>
		<text>   Game Masters should be encouraged to give snipers plenty to do;hard to reach or difficult targets. Sniping and spotting can be a boring but important job and it&#x27;s the job of the GM to make sniping interesting and fun.</text>
	</item>
</body>