<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<body>
	<item>
		<header level = "0">Weapons in Use</header>
<box>
<text>Weapons in Use  This chapter talks about the general trends that firearms have followed throughout the years, as well as trends that generally follow for the armed citizen. In most campaigns, players should be free to choose the weapons for their characters; however, if they don&#x27;t know what to choose, this section can provide some useful advice depending on what kind of campaign or setting is being played. The information in this chapter, and more broadly, this book, focuses on the United States and its firearm laws. For other countries, similar firearms should be used, but they might not be as common for some types of characters. For instance, in the UK, a bartender might have a bat over a shotgun, but an armored car guard will probably be armed along the same lines as their US counterpart.</text>
</box>
		<header level = "1">Local and State Law Enforcement</header>
		<text>   Local and State Law Enforcement encompasses the major uniformedeverything from petty thief and indecency calls, all the way to statewide drug rings and murder sprees. They generally do not contact federal agencies (or are contacted by federal agencies), unless the case becomes a federal case, that is, crosses state lines. They will often call in federal agencies for guidance and assistance on things that are out of their scope, such as profiling.</text>
		<text>   A small police station is a station that has less than 20 swornrestrictions are generally lax, usually consisting of caliber requirement for the selected handgun (from 9x19mm up to .45 ACP), and the requirement that the officer or deputy be able to qualify and display proper use and maintenance of their weapon. Because of their size, officers and deputies are heavily stressed to carry a backup weapon. Police stations and sheriffs departments of this size generally do not have their own SWAT team, and usually have to ask a larger, nearby department, for assistance. Service handgun habits for departments of this size span the entire department, from the rookie patrol officer or deputy, all the way up to the chief or sheriff.</text>
		<text>   The armory may include between 1-5 extra boxes of JHP ammunition3-5 12 Gauge pump action shotguns of assorted manufacturer.</text>
		<text>   Examples of these police stations and sheriff&#x27;s departmentssmall college.</text>
		<text>   A medium police station is a station that has between 21-100firearms, though the requirement that the officer or deputy be able to qualify and display proper use and maintenance of their weapon still applies. Popular firearms for police stations and sheriff&#x27;s departments for their officers and deputies include the Glock series in 9x19mm, .45 ACP, and .40 S&amp;W, the Smith and Wesson 59 Series and the M&amp;P Series in 9x19mm and .40 S&amp;W, The SIG P229 in .40 S&amp;W, the Springfield Armory GI 1911A1 in .45 APC, and the XD in .40 S&amp;W and .45 ACP, and the Beretta 92FS in 9x19mm and the Px4 in 9x19mm, .40 S&amp;W and .45 ACP. In addition to their sidearm, they often carry an expendable or fixed baton, pepper spray or for more well funded departments, a taser, at least two reloads for their sidearm, a multitool or pocket knife, a small flashlight, a pair of handcuffs, and a radio. They are also issued a ballistic vest, or receive a stipend to pay for one. Detectives and investigators will generally carry the same firearms issued to the officers, though older detectives grandfathered in before the widespread use of automatics will carry their .38 Special and .357 Magnum revolvers, such as the Colt Detective Special and the Smith and Wesson Model 36, as well as a pair of handcuffs. Higher officers, such as the captains, majors and chiefs, pull double duty and are out on the street just as much as they are in the office, carrying what suits them.</text>
		<text>   The SWAT team is usually comprised of various officers who workthe standard officers, SWAT team members generally carry personalized handguns, that have been fitted to their specific needs. The SWAT team, when on a mission is equipped with shotguns such as the Mossberg 590A1 and Remington 870 Police, sub-machine guns such as the HK MP5A4 and MP5A5, UMP9, UMP40, and UMP 45, and bolt action rifles such as the Remington 700P, as well as a single entry shield. A SWAT team in a department of this size will also have tear gas and smoke grenades.</text>
		<text>   The armory will have 10-15 extra boxes of JHP ammunition forboxes of 12 Gauge 00 buckshot ammo, and 5-8 boxes of 12 Gauge non-lethal beanbag and rubber ball ammo. The armory will also have between 5-25 spare handguns that have not been issued or are spares, with extra magazines for these handguns, as well as 6-10 12 Gauge pump action shotguns, usually of an unformed nature, the most common being the Mossberg 500 and the Remington 870 Express.</text>
		<text>   Examples of these police stations and sheriff&#x27;s departmentsat a large university.</text>
		<text>   A large police station is a station that has over 100 sworn instringent on their specific firearms, sticking to strictly issued firearms for its personnel. They follow the same trends a medium-sized police station would in choice of firearms and issued equipment, though the requirement that the officer or deputy be able to qualify and display proper use and maintenance of their weapon still applies. Detectives and investigators will generally carry the same firearms issued to the officers. Higher officers, such as the captains, majors and chiefs, are usually confined to clerical and managerial work, and as such, do not make it a habit to carry a weapon while on duty.</text>
		<text>   The SWAT team in a large station is comprised of dedicatedwork. Because of their area of coverage, they are mostly active answering calls where their forces are needed, and when not doing so, are undergoing training to keep their skills sharp until their services are needed. SWAT team members generally are relaxed from the strict requirements that other officers are imposed about their sidearms, allowing to choose a sidearm to fit their specific needs. The SWAT team would have the same equipment as a medium-sized department, just more of it, but would also possess shotguns such as the Mossberg 930 Tactical, Remington 1100, and Benelli M1014, carbine rifles such as the Colt M4, H&amp;K G36K, designated marksman rifles such as the H&amp;K PSG1 and M14 SWS, and even grenade launchers such as the H&amp;K M320, as well as multiple entry shields and riot shields. A SWAT team in a department of this size will also have tear gas, smoke, sting, stun and even concussion grenades. Departments such as these also have weapons dedicated for purely non-lethal engagement, and will have multiple .68 Cal. paintball markers and 18mm LL for subduing a subject without firearms.</text>
		<text>   The armory for a large police department will have hundreds ofammunition will be JHP issued for duty. The armory will also not only have a multitude of spare firearms and magazines, but will possess its own staff of armorers dedicated to repairing, maintaining, and cataloging said firearms.</text>
		<text>   Examples of these police stations and sheriff&#x27;s departmentsPolice Department, the Los Angeles Police Department, the Chiciago Police Department, the Atlanta Police Department, and the Los Angeles County Sheriff&#x27;s Department.</text>
		<text>   Park rangers hold a special place in law enforcement, in theassociated with law enforcement. In addition to enforcing park regulations and laws, they are charged with educating the various visitors of the parks which can be as simple as weather forecast and giving directions, to complex as giving full guided tours that talk about the park&#x27;s ecology, history, and demonstrations. They are also charged with watching for forest fires and answering emergency calls and dispatching help to those in need.</text>
		<text>   Because of their somewhat remote nature, most park rangers carrysetting, with revolvers chambered in .44 Magnum or .454 Casull, or autoloaders chambered in .45 ACP or 10mm Auto, to stop large animals such as bears and mountain lions. They also generally have a shotgun or rifle in their vehicle, as well as a complete medical kit, a map of the area, a compass, flashlight, blankets, water and food rations.</text>
		<header level = "1">Federal Agencies</header>
		<text>   Federal agencies are agencies that investigate crimes that arethat involve multiple states. They generally do not bother themselves with local petty crime, but will get involved with larger crimes, as well as lend assistance, manpower, and firepower to local agencies who need it.</text>
		<text>   The Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) is a governmentalserves as both a federal criminal investigative body and an internal intelligence agency (counter intelligence).</text>
		<text>   The current issued sidearm for special agents is the Glock 22 ortheir first qualification, they will be issued either a Glock 17 or Glock 19 to aid in their next qualification. The Glock 26, Glock 23, and Glock 27 are authorized as backup weapons. Special agents are authorized to purchase and qualify with the Glock 21 for duty carry.</text>
		<text>   Special agents of the FBI Hostage Rescue Team and FBI SWAT teamsACP.</text>
		<text>   The HRT and SWAT team maintains a stock of H&amp;K MP5/10A3 andflashlights, red dot sights, and a vertical foregrip, as well as Colt M16A3, M4 and M4A1, M14, and M40A1 rifles. They also have access to Barret M82A1 Anti-materiel rifles, M79 grenade launcher, Tasers, and stun grenades when needed.</text>
		<text>   The Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives (ATF)States Department of Justice. Its responsibilities include the investigation and prevention of federal offenses involving the unlawful use, manufacture, and possession of firearms and explosives; acts of arson and bombings; and illegal trafficking of alcohol and tobacco products. The ATF also regulates via licensing the sale, possession, and transportation of firearms, ammunition, and explosives in interstate commerce.</text>
		<text>   The currently issued sidearm for special agents is the Glock 22</text>
		<text>   The United States Marshals Service (USMS) is a United StatesDepartment of Justice. The Marshals Service is part of the executive branch of government, and is the enforcement arm of the United States federal courts. The U.S. Marshals are responsible for the protection of court officers and buildings and the effective operation of the judiciary. The service also assists with court security and prisoner transport, serves arrest warrants, and seeks fugitives.</text>
		<text>   The current issued sidearm for Marshals is the Glock 22 or Glock9x19mm, .40 S&amp;W, .45 ACP, or .357 Magnum backup or full sized handgun, providing they pay the full cost and qualify with it.</text>
		<text>   While on assignment, Marshals will also carry ArmaLite AR-15 andshotguns.</text>
		<text>   The Special Operations Group (SOG) is issued the Springfield</text>
		<text>   The Federal Air Marshal Service (FAMS) is a United StatesTransportation Security Administration (TSA) of the United States Department of Homeland Security (DHS). The Air Marshal Service is meant to promote confidence in civil aviation by effectively deploying federal air marshals (FAMs) to detect, deter, and defeat hostile acts targeting the United States.</text>
		<text>   The current issued sidearm for Air Marshals is the SIG P229,</text>
		<text>   The Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA) is a federal lawtasked with combating drug smuggling and use within the United States. Not only is the DEA the lead agency for domestic enforcement of the Controlled Substances Act, sharing concurrent jurisdiction with the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) and Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE), it also has sole responsibility for coordinating and pursuing U.S. drug investigations abroad.</text>
		<text>   The current issued sidearm for Special Agents is the Glock 22 orM&amp;P chambered in .40 S&amp;W as well. The Glock 23, and Glock 27 in .40 S&amp;W are authorized as backup weapons. The H&amp;K UMP40 is the standard SMG, and the Remington 870 Police is the standard shotgun. Agents also have begun to use the RRA CAR A4 Tactical, that has been upgraded to fire fully automatic as well. Special Agents can also use their personal firearms, but all must be approved by the DEA firearms office before use.</text>
		<text>   U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) is a federal lawSecurity (DHS), responsible for identifying, investigating, and dismantling vulnerabilities regarding the nation&#x27;s border, economic, transportation, and infrastructure security. The largest components within ICE are Homeland Security Investigations (HSI) and Enforcement &amp; Removal Operations (ERO).</text>
		<text>   ICE HSI Special Agents and ERO Officers and Agents are issuedsidearm. They also may be assigned the Remington Model 870 Police shotgun, the Steyr AUG rifle, or the Colt M4 carbine. Agents and officers assigned to a Special Response Team (SRT) are specifically assigned the Colt M4 Carbine while some operators may also carry the H&amp;K MP5A4 or MP5A5 sub-machine gun, although these are being replaced by the H&amp;K UMP40 chambered in .40 S&amp;W.</text>
		<text>   The United States Secret Service is a United States federal lawof Homeland Security. The sworn members are divided among the Special Agents and the Uniformed Division. Until March 1, 2003, the Service was part of the United States Department of the Treasury. The U.S. Secret Service has two distinct areas of responsibility; Treasury roles, covering missions such as prevention and investigation of counterfeiting of U.S. currency and U.S. treasury securities, and investigation of major fraud, and protective roles, ensuring the safety of current and former national leaders and their families, such as the President, past Presidents, Vice Presidents, presidential candidates, and foreign embassies.</text>
		<text>   Secret Service Special Agents are issued the SIG P229, chamberedAgents are also trained on the H&amp;K MP5K, MP5K-PDW, MP5A4 and MP5A5 sub-machine gun, the Remington 870 Police shotgun, and the FN P90 Sub-machine gun.</text>
		<text>   The United States Postal Inspection Service (USPIS) is the lawjurisdiction is defined as &quot;crimes that may adversely affect or fraudulently use the U.S. Mail, the postal system, or postal employees.&quot; The mission of the U.S. Postal Inspection Service is to support and protect the U.S. Postal Service, its employees, infrastructure, and customers by enforcing the laws that defend the nation’s mail system from illegal or dangerous use.</text>
		<text>   Postal Inspectors are issued the SIG P229, chambered in .40 S&amp;WPostal Inspectors are issued a Remington 870 Police shotgun along with their service sidearm. </text>
		<header level = "1">The Underworld</header>
		<text>   The underworld encompasses the world of crime that exists as alords, mafia bosses, and set leaders, who control and run the lower soldiers and gang members.</text>
		<text>   This group encompasses singular criminals, petty thieves,fingers directly in the crime, though most of their crime is either opportunistic, or for profit.</text>
		<text>   Low level criminals don&#x27;t have a specific group of firearms:shot pistol from World War 2 to a fully automatic assault rifle. As a general rule, these criminals generally use melee weapons for their ease of acquisition, lack of restriction, simplicity in use, and sometimes their added benefit of plausible deniability. When they do carry firearms, they prefer any gun that can be concealed, and is available. Because of their criminal records, they can not go and purchase a firearm from a legal dealer, instead opting for illegal street deals, or stealing a firearm. Poor quality firearms are common.</text>
		<text>   This group is a level above the unstructured criminal, andleader. These groups generally deal purely in profit, often coming from the same neighborhood or of a similar race, creed, or lifestyle. They usually also have a mutualistic interest: money, and work together because of it, and the chaos and criminalistic activity they cause is merely a byproduct. They usually wear identifying colors or pieces of clothing, such as certain colors, or even leather jackets or vest with the club&#x27;s insignia.</text>
		<text>   Outlaw motorcycle gangs are atypical of this behavior, as theand the criminal enterprise is a means to live, in order to continue the life of chaos.</text>
		<text>   Smaller street gangs are generally equipped with concealableacquire, use, and replace, while the larger gangs may possess heavier firepower such as automatic weapons such as assault rifles, and even anti-materiel rifles.</text>
		<text>   Gang leaders generally prefer to keep their hands clean of anylower ranking gang members, but will generally carry a smaller concealable handgun of decent to high quality, such as the Kahr handgun series, the Walther PP Series, the SIG P290 and P238, and the Glock 26, 27, and 28. These are usually tucked away inside briefcases, bags, and under suit jackets.</text>
		<text>   A drug cartel is a criminal organization developed with theoperations. They can range from an agreement between two street gangs to work together, all the way up to interstate and even international, multi-billion dollar formal industries.</text>
		<text>   While they have a similar structure to a common street gang,agencies. Most soldiers in a drug cartel are trained in the various arts of asymmetrical warfare, close-quarters combat, weapons handling and maintenance, and some have even received explosives handing and training. Most of this training comes from legitimate state training, which the knowledge is then passed down from a dissenting police officer.</text>
		<text>   Weapons carried by the cartel include, but are by no meansevery make and model, AT4 and M72 LAW rocket launchers, M79 grenade launchers, and even Barret M82B anti-materiel rifles. </text>
		<text>   Assassins are people who commit a targeted murder. Hitmen are</text>
		<text>   Assassins and hitmen&#x27;s method of killing can range frominvolved, they prefer to either fire from a long distance, using a high-powered rifle with a scope and possibly a suppressor, or close range with a suppressed handgun, or machine pistol. They also use a melee weapon, a knife usually, for truly quiet kills.</text>
		<text>   Gunrunners and arms traffickers are people who smugglearms, acquired legally or otherwise, to anyone who has the cash and need. Arms traffickers and gunrunners should not be confused with people who sell firearms for legal commerce, such as a legally operating gun store.</text>
		<text>   Because of their nature of business, they have the bestsuch. Gunrunners are generally heavily armed, either by choice or simply by having stock, usually with a few handguns and an assault rifle or two, as well as grenades, explosives, magazines, ammunition, and anything else their customers would like to sample. They also have a tendency to wear body armor, in order to avoid getting killed by their own merchandise.</text>
		<text>   Insurgents and terrorist armament depends completely on theircrude, homemade firearms, while well-funded and equipped insurgents will use everything from fully automatic rifles to rocket launchers. Because of their nature, any weapon is viable for a terrorist or insurgent.</text>
		<header level = "1">Civilian Forces</header>
		<text>   Civilian forces encompass regular people who have a mind toso as a part of a job, but are not law enforcement, or regular citizens who prefer to have their protection and safety in their hands.</text>
		<text>   Armored cars are popular target for professional bank thieves,generally equipped with a ballistic vest, a uniform, and a handgun, that they must purchase themselves, but do receive a stipend for it. Popular firearms span far and wide, but they most often keep full-sized handguns in a tactical holster, with a pump action or automatic shotgun in the truck.</text>
		<text>   Bars are often the starting scenes for rowdy behavior, and assuch as a Mossberg 500 or Remington 870 Police under the bar for serious altercations, but many bartenders have begun to opt for a full sized handgun, because of their maneuverability and size. They also will have melee weapons, such as a bat, to deal with less rowdy, but still problematic, patrons.</text>
		<text>   Shopkeepers generally follow the same rules as bartenders, butjob. The level of armament of the shop is completely dependent on the shopkeeper&#x27;s views, as well as what they sell. A gun store is guaranteed to have an armed shopkeeper, while a fine china store in a wealthy neighborhood may go without firearms, electing to call the authorities instead.</text>
		<text>   A mercenary is a person who takes part in an armed conflict, whoto take part in the hostilities essentially by the desire for private gain and, in fact, is promised, by or on behalf of a party to the conflict, material compensation substantially in excess of that promised or paid to combatants of similar ranks and functions in the armed forces of that party”. Most mercenaries in the modern age are employees of private security firms such as Blackwater, Xe Services, Triple Canopy, Armour Group, PBE, and Dyncorp.</text>
		<text>   Mercenaries are generally armed the same, or more usually,body armor, weapons, vehicles, and ammunition, provided by the company they work for. This equipment is generally on loan from the company while they perform their services, though it isn&#x27;t uncommon for a mercenary to carry their own personal sidearm. The type of handgun a mercenary carries is completely dependent on their personal preference but .45 ACP, .40 S&amp;W, and .357 Magnum are the most popular calibers.</text>
		<text>   Bodyguards are equipped just as mercenaries, though because ofweapons in lieu of semi-automatic rifles and carbines, as well as concealed handguns.</text>
		<text>   The weapon a hunter carries depends on the personal preferenceanimals, a light birdshot is generally preferred in a shotgun, modified with a choked barrel. Varmint hunters will choose something with a smaller caliber, such as .22 Long Rifle or .17 HMR. Hunters of larger game will prefer high powered rifles chambered in calibers such as 7.62x51mm or .30-06 Springfield, or shotguns with slug barrels, loaded with slugs. A hunter may also choose to carry a crossbow, or bow and arrow, for a silent kill.</text>
		<text>   Security guards are charged with over-watching an area, usuallyfirearms, rather to observe and report, and call the authorities if anything does happen. They are usually given a flashlight and possibly a can of pepper spray.</text>
		<text>   Local militia members are armed depending on their funding, andarmed with self-loading rifles such as the Ruger Mini 14, and Mini 30, while well-funded militias will have AR-15s and FALs. Because of their semi-organized nature, firearms will rarely be universal across the members, many using what they can afford or even get their hands on.</text>
		<text>   The armed citizen&#x27;s armament can vary extremely widely. Usuallysuch as firearms from makers such as S&amp;W, Kahr, Glock, H&amp;K or Ruger, to name a few. A small few will also carry backup firearms as well. Less well off citizens will have less expensive firearms, such as Hi points, Jimenez, and SCCYs.</text>
		<header level = "1">Militaries Around the World</header>
		<text>   This section covers the basic issued equipment for the variousoften issue a host of other support equipment, such as MREs, MOLLE gear, and tools to achieve their missions.</text>
		<text>   The armed forces of the United States all issue M4A1s and M16A4sdepending on the soldier&#x27;s duties. Specialty units and soldiers are issued M249 light machine guns, M320 and M203 grenade launchers, M110 SASS designated marksman rifles, M40A3 and M24A3 sniper rifles, M82 anti-materiel rifles, AT4 and Javelin rocket launchers, and MP5 sub-machine guns. Soldiers are also issued M9 handguns, which are functionally identical to Beretta 92FS handguns, but they are being phased out for the newer M17 handguns, which are Sig-Sauer P320 full-size handguns in 9x19mm. The USMC also has a store of M1911 and Glock 19 handguns that are used by select groups, but these weapons are few and far in-between, often given to special forces groups. The Criminal Investigations divisions such as CID and NCIS are issued Sig-Sauer P228 handguns in 9x19mm, while military police are issued M9s or M17s. Mossberg 590A1 and Remington 870 shotguns are often used both by military police for response, and by infantry for breaching. The M1014 is also issued for breaching, but this is primarily used by the USMC. Various types of grenades are used by all branches, with fragmentation, smoke and stun grenades being the most common. Survival knives are issued as well.</text>
		<text>   The armed forces of Canada issue M4A1s and M16A4s with ironthe soldier&#x27;s duties. Specialty units and soldiers are issued FN Minimi light machine guns, M320 and M203 grenade launchers, M110 SASS designated marksman rifles, M40A3 and M24A3 Sniper rifles, M82 Anti-materiel rifles, AT4 and Javelin rocket launchers, MP5 sub-machine guns. Soldiers are also issued Browning Hi-Power handguns. Various types of grenades are used by the Canadian Armed Forces, with fragmentation, smoke and stun grenades being the most common. Survival knives are issued as well.</text>
		<text>   The United States Coast Guard issues M4A1s with various opticshandguns chambered in .40 S&amp;W. Flare guns and flotation vests are also standard issue due to their work in and around the water.</text>
		<text>   The PLA Ground forces issues the Norinco QBZ Type 95 rifle andused as a squad automatic weapon. They also issue the Norinco QSZ 92 handgun, but these handguns are primarily for officers.</text>
		<text>   The Israeli Defense Force primarily issues the IMI Tavor seriesM16A4 for various secondary roles such as security duty and conscription duty. They also issue the M24A3 to snipers, and have the IMI Negev as their squad automatic weapon. Galils are also common in both secondary roles and primary roles. Jericho 941 handguns are also issued to select personnel. Various types of grenades are used by the IDF, with fragmentation, smoke and stun grenades being the most common. Survival knives are issued as well.</text>
<box>
<text>The British Army and the SAS are both issued the L85A2 rifle, as Specialist roles will receive the Accuracy International AWP rifle. Their issued handgun is the Browning Hi-Hower, usually given to officers. AT4 anti-tank weapons and M320 grenade launchers are also common. Various types of grenades are used by both the British Army and the SAS, with fragmentation, smoke, and stun grenades being the most common. Survival knives are issued as well.</text>
</box>
	</item>
</body>