<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<body>
    <item>
        <header level="1">Carbines</header>
        <text>   Carbine rifles are almost always Large, chambered in intermediate rifle cartridges, such as .223 Remington/5.56x45mm, or full power rifle cartridges such as .308 Winchester/7.62x51mm NATO, with magazines ranging from 10 to 35 rounds. There also exist a subsection called the pistol caliber carbine, which shoots pistol caliber rounds, such as the 9x19mm, and is always semi-automatic, as a fully automatic pistol carbine is a sub-machine gun. All Carbine rifles are crafted with a fixed stock. When crafting a weapon with automatic fire, the creator can choose what rate of fire the automatic fires at.
        </text>
        <table>
            <tr>
                <header textAlign="center">Type</header>
                <header textAlign="center">Magazine</header>
                <header textAlign="center">Caliber</header>
                <header textAlign="center">Range</header>
                <header>Firing Modes</header>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text textAlign="center">Pump Action Carbine¹</text>
                <text textAlign="center">Internal: +1 TN for every
round over 5 (Max 8)
Box Mag: +2 TN for every
round over 10 (Max 40)</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+2 TN per category
(2nd-9th category)</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+1 TN for every 5'
over 25' (Max 80')</text>
                <text>—</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text textAlign="center">Lever Action Carbine¹</text>
                <text textAlign="center">Internal: +1 TN for every
round over 5 (Max 8)
Box Mag: +2 TN for every
round over 10 (Max 40)</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+2 TN per category
(2nd-9th category)</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+1 TN for every 5'
over 25' (Max 80')</text>
                <text>—</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text textAlign="center">Self-loading Carbine¹</text>
                <text textAlign="center">Internal: +1 TN for every
round over 5 (Max 8)
Box Mag: +2 TN for every
round over 10 (Max 40)</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+2 TN per category
(2nd-9th category)</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+1 TN for every 5'
over 25' (Max 75')</text>
                <text><b>Semi-automatic</b> Free
<b>Fully Automatic</b> +9 TN
<b>2 Round Burst</b> +12 TN
<b>3 Round Burst</b> +14 TN</text>
            </tr>
        </table>
        <text>1 A character can choose to craft a firearm to take the same kind of magazines from a preexisting Carbine Rifle. If the character does this, they do not have to add the TN to the firearm's total level, but the firearm must use the same caliber of ammunition that the corresponding magazine and firearm uses.</text>
        <text textAlign="center">Table 17: Gunsmithing - Carbine
        </text>
        <header level="1">Assault, Battle, and Target Rifles</header>
        <text>   Assault rifles are Large weapons, chambered in intermediate rifle cartridges such as .223 Remington/5.56x45mm or 7.62x39mm, that have an automatic rate of fire and a stock. Battle rifles are Large weapons chambered in a full power rifle cartridge, such as the .308 Winchester/7.62x51mm NATO, that have an automatic rate of fire, and a stock. Target rifles fall into both of these categories, but lack the automatic firepower. Ranges are conclusive to rifles, spanning from 65-110'. All Assault, Battle and Target Rifles are crafted with a fixed stock.When crafting a weapon with automatic fire, the creator can choose what rate of fire the automatic fires at.
        </text>
        <table>
            <tr>
                <header textAlign="center">Type</header>
                <header textAlign="center">Magazine</header>
                <header textAlign="center">Caliber</header>
                <header textAlign="center">Range</header>
                <header>Firing Modes</header>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text textAlign="center">Pump Action Carbine¹</text>
                <text textAlign="center">Internal: +1 TN for every
round over 5 (Max 8)
Box Mag: +2 TN for every
round over 10 (Max 40)</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+2 TN per category
(6th-9th category)</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+1 TN for every 5'
over 45' (Max 120')</text>
                <text>—</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text textAlign="center">Lever Action Carbine¹</text>
                <text textAlign="center">Internal: +1 TN for every
round over 5 (Max 8)
Box Mag: +2 TN for every
round over 10 (Max 40)</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+2 TN per category
(6th-9th category)</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+1 TN for every 5'
over 45' (Max 120')</text>
                <text>—</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text textAlign="center">Self-loading Carbine¹</text>
                <text textAlign="center">Internal: +1 TN for every
round over 5 (Max 8)
Box Mag: +2 TN for every
round over 10 (Max 40)</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+2 TN per category
(6th-9th category)</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+1 TN for every 5'
over 45' (Max 120')</text>
                <text><b>Semi-automatic</b> Free
<b>Fully Automatic</b> +9 TN
<b>2 Round Burst</b> +12 TN
<b>3 Round Burst</b> +14 TN</text>
            </tr>
        </table>
        <text>1 A character can choose to craft a firearm to take the same kind of magazines from a preexisting Assault, Battle or Target Rifles. If the character does this, they do not have to add the TN to the firearm's total level, but the firearm must use the same caliber of ammunition that the corresponding magazine and firearm uses.</text>
        <text textAlign="center">Table 18: Gunsmithing - Assault, Battle, or Target Rifle
        </text>
        <header level="1">Designated Marksman Rifles</header>
        <text>   Designated Marksman Rifles are semi-automatic, or selective fire rifles that have been optimized for medium long range engagement. As such, they generally have optics, bipods, and a stock that allows them to steady, as well as being chambered in a full sized rifle cartridge. All Designated marksman Rifles are crafted with a fixed stock. When crafting a weapon with automatic fire, the creator can choose what rate of fire the automatic fires at.
        </text>
        <table>
            <tr>
                <header textAlign="center">Type</header>
                <header textAlign="center">Magazine</header>
                <header textAlign="center">Caliber</header>
                <header textAlign="center">Range</header>
                <header>Firing Modes</header>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text textAlign="center">DMR¹</text>
                <text textAlign="center">Box Mag: +2 TN for every
round over 10 (Max 30)</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+2 TN per category
(7th-9th category)</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+4 TN per every 5'
over 85' (Max 130 feet)</text>
                <text><b>Semi-automatic</b> Free
<b>Fully Automatic</b> +10 TN
<b>2 Round Burst</b> +13 TN
<b>3 Round Burst</b> +16 TN</text>
            </tr>
        </table>
        <text>1 A character can choose to craft a firearm to take the same kind of magazines from a preexisting Designated Marksman Rifles. If the character does this, they do not have to add the TN to the firearm's total level, but the firearm must use the same caliber of ammunition that the corresponding magazine and firearm uses.</text>
        <text textAlign="center">Table 19: Gunsmithing - Designated Marksman Rifle
        </text>
        <header level="1">Bolt Action and Sniper Rifles</header>
        <text>   Sniper rifles and Bolt Action Rifles are nearly identical in construction, being bolt action rifles purpose built for long range target engagement. Where they differ is deployment. All Sniper rifles will have optics. Ranges vary widely, but they are at least 80 feet. Bolt Action and Sniper rifles are crafted with a fixed stock.
        </text>
        <table>
            <tr>
                <header textAlign="center">Type</header>
                <header textAlign="center">Magazine</header>
                <header textAlign="center">Caliber</header>
                <header textAlign="center">Range</header>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text textAlign="center">Bolt Action or Sniper Rifle¹</text>
                <text textAlign="center">Internal: +1 TN for every
round over 3 (Max 10)
Box Mag: +2 TN for every
round over 3 (Max 10)</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+2 TN per category
(2nd-9th category)</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+1 TN per every 5'
over 80' (Max 170')</text>
            </tr>
        </table>
        <text>1 A character can choose to craft a firearm to take the same kind of magazines from a preexisting Bolt Action or Sniper Rifles. If the character does this, they do not have to add the TN to the firearm's total level, but the firearm must use the same caliber of ammunition that the corresponding magazine and firearm uses.</text>
        <text textAlign="center">Table 20: Gunsmithing - Bolt Action or Sniper Rifle
        </text>
        <header level="1">Anti-materiel Rifles</header>
        <text>   Anti-materiel rifles are semi-automatic rifles chambered in a heavy caliber, such as .50 BMG or 20mm. These weapons are almost always Huge in size and require bipods in order to use properly. They can be bolt action or semi automatic, but ranges are at least 150 feet. All anti-materiel rifles are crafted with a bipod and a fixed stock. When crafting a weapon with automatic fire, the creator can choose what rate of fire the automatic fires at.
        </text>
        <table>
            <tr>
                <header textAlign="center">Type</header>
                <header textAlign="center">Magazine</header>
                <header textAlign="center">Caliber</header>
                <header textAlign="center">Range</header>
                <header>Firing Modes</header>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text textAlign="center">Anti-materiel Rifle¹</text>
                <text textAlign="center">Internal: +5 TN for every
round over 2 (Max 5)
Box Mag: +2 TN for every
round over 3 (Max 10)</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+1 TN per category
(10th-11th category)</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+1 TN per every 10'
over 120' (Max 450')</text>
                <text><b>Bolt Action</b> Free
<b>Semi-automatic</b> Free
<b>Fully Automatic</b> +15 TN
<b>2 Round Burst</b> +20 TN
<b>3 Round Burst</b> +25 TN</text>
            </tr>
        </table>
        <text>1 A character can choose to craft a firearm to take the same kind of magazines from a preexisting Anti-materiel Rifles. If the character does this, they do not have to add the TN to the firearm's total level, but the firearm must use the same caliber of ammunition that the corresponding magazine and firearm uses.</text>
        <text textAlign="center">Table 21: Gunsmithing - Anti-materiel Rifle
        </text>
    </item>
</body>