<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<body>
    <item>
        <header>Craft (Mechanical) Trained Only</header>
        <text>   This skill allows a character to build mechanical devices from scratch, including engines and engine parts, weapons, and other gadgets. When building a mechanical device from scratch, the character describes the kind of device they want to construct, then the GM decides whether the device fits the definition of a simple, moderate, complex, or advanced compared to current technology.
        </text>
        <header level="1">Simple</header>
        <text>   This category includes items such as simple mechanical components, single mode detonators, and simple tools. The TN for these items is 15, the WP cost for a simple device will not exceed 4, and the time taken to build it will not exceed 2 hours.</text>
        <text>   This category can also be used to combine two firearm magazines into one larger magazine, adding the capacity of the magazines together. Any firearm that uses this magazine has a -6 to stealth.
        </text>
        <header level="1">Moderate</header>
        <text>   This category includes items such as mechanical locks, components for an engine, single/double shot and bolt action firearms, and complex tools. The TN for these items is 20, the WP cost for a moderate device will not exceed 11, and the time taken to build it will not exceed 12 hours.
        </text>
        <header level="1">Complex</header>
        <text>   This category includes items such as car engines, and Lever/pump/Single action firearms, and. The TN for these items is 25, the WP cost for a complex device will not exceed 25, and the time taken to build it will not exceed 24 hours.
        </text>
        <header level="1">Advanced</header>
        <text>   This category includes items such as jet engines, complete automobiles, and Semi-automatic, Automatic, and select-fire firearms. The TN for these items is 30, the WP cost for a complex device will not exceed 500, and the time taken to build it will not exceed 60 hours.
        </text>
        <header level="1">Special</header>
        <text>   A character without a mechanics tool kit takes a −6 penalty on Craft (Mechanical) checks.</text>
        <text>   A character with 7 ranks in Knowledge (Physical Sciences) can choose Craft (Mechanical) to receive a +2 synergy bonus. If the character chooses Craft (Mechanical), they cannot apply the synergy bonus to any other skill.</text>
    </item>
</body>