<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<body>
	<item>
		<header level = "0">Attack Actions</header>
<box>
<text>Attack Actions</text>
</box>
<table>
<tr><header textAlign="center">Action</header><header textAlign="center">CP Cost</header></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Standard Melee Attack, Diminutive to Small Weapons</text><text textAlign="center">3</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Standard Melee Attack, Medium to Large Weapons</text><text textAlign="center">4</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Standard Melee Attack, Huge and larger Weapons</text><text textAlign="center">5</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Trip Attack</text><text textAlign="center">8</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Knockout Blow</text><text textAlign="center">12</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Disarm Attack</text><text textAlign="center">9</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Coup de Grâce</text><text textAlign="center">12</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Melee Attack Modifiers</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Fighting Defensively</text><text textAlign="center">+1</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Light Attack</text><text textAlign="center">−1</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Heavy Attack</text><text textAlign="center">+2</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Full Attack</text><text textAlign="center">+7</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Aggressive Attack</text><text textAlign="center">+2</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Thrust Attack</text><text textAlign="center">+1</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Swipe Attack</text><text textAlign="center">+1</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Other Attack Actions</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Reaction</text><text textAlign="center">7</text></tr>
</table>
		<header level = "1">Ranged Attacks</header>
		<text>   With a ranged weapon, a character can shoot or throw at anyline of sight. A target is in line of sight if there are no solid obstructions between the character and the target. The maximum range for a thrown weapon is five range increments. For weapons that fire projectiles, it is ten range increments.</text>
<box>
<text>If a character shoots or throws a ranged weapon at a target that penalty on their attack roll because the character has to aim carefully to avoid hitting the ally. Two characters are engaged in melee if they are enemies and they are adjacent to one another. An unconscious or otherwise immobilized character is not considered engaged unless they are actually being attacked. If the target is so big that part of it is 10&#x27; or farther from the nearest ally the character can avoid the −4 penalty even if it is engaged in melee with an ally.</text>
</box>
<box>
<text>Attaching a telescopic sight to a weapon changes how attacks are Points acquiring their target. If the character changes targets or otherwise loses sight of the target, they must reacquire the target to gain the benefit of the scope. Any character attempting to attack a target within the weapon&#x27;s first range increment suffers a −4 penalty to their attack roll.</text>
</box>
		<text>   A bow can be pulled back and readied in three different</text>
<list type="unordered">
<text>Light Pull Light pulls have −1 damage die and the range is reduced by 5&#x27;.</text>
<text>Medium Pull Medium pulls have no bonuses or penalties to damage.</text>
<text>Heavy Pull Heavy pulls have +1 damage die and the range is increased by 10&#x27;.</text>
</list>
		<text>   The most basic form of attack with a firearm is a single shot.target. The Personal Firearms Proficiency feat allows a character to make this sort of attack without penalty. If a character isn&#x27;t proficient in personal firearms they take a −4 penalty on attacks with that type of weapon. A multi-shot attack is any attack that fires more than one round or shell. As with all forms of ranged weapons, attacking with a firearm while within a threatened square provokes an AoO. All firearms deal ballistic damage and have a critical threat range of 16-18 unless otherwise noted.</text>
		<text>   SA</text>
<box>
<text>Single Action requires the hammer to be pulled back before firing internal magazines are considered semi-automatic firearms. All Single Action firearms gain a +1 attack bonus on all single shot and potshot attacks. Single Action firearms with cylinders cost +1 Combat Points when performing a single shot attack.</text>
</box>
<box>
<text>Double Action/Single Action where the first shot is a heavy DA/SA firearms are considered semi-automatic firearms. All single shot attacks after the first gain a +1 attack bonus. The first shot has no bonus or penalty, but the hammer may be cocked back for 1 Combat Points, giving a +1 attack bonus for the first shot.</text>
</box>
<box>
<text>Double Action is similar to DA/SA but every shot is a heavy semi-automatic firearms. The hammer is exposed and can be cocked back for 1 Combat Points, gaining a +1 attack bonus on single shot attacks.</text>
</box>
<box>
<text>Double Action Only is similar to DA but the hammer can not be semi-automatic firearms.</text>
</box>
<box>
<text>Preset Action, the action is at half-cock giving a light trigger firearms. All single shot attacks have a +1 attack bonus.</text>
</box>
<box>
<text>The firearm has a lever that must be worked after each shot. but −1 Combat Points when performing single shot attacks. Lever action firearms can perform single shot and potshot attacks.</text>
</box>
<box>
<text>The firearm has a pump on the forearm that is worked back and single shot and potshot attacks.</text>
</box>
<box>
<text>A subset of pump action. Firearms with this have no disconnect </text>
</box>
<box>
<text>The firearm has a bolt that must be worked after each shot, shot attacks have a +1 attack bonus, but cost +1 Combat Point. Bolt action firearms can perform single shot and potshot attacks.</text>
</box>
<box>
<text>Each pull of the trigger reloads the firearm. It is synonymous semi-automatic firearms.</text>
</box>
<box>
<text>Stands for burst fire, in 2RB and 3RB variants. 2RB Stands for 2 fire attacks, and 3RB stands for 3 round burst, which allows the firearm to perform 3 round burst fire attacks.</text>
</box>
<box>
<text>Stands for fully automatic where the firearm will continue to perform autofire, suppressive fire, sweepfire, sprayfire, or burst fire attacks. Slow autofire means the weapon has a slow rate of fire. Slow autofire fires less rounds per second, giving a more controllable rate of fire. Slow autofire can perform single shot attacks or potshot attacks. Medium autofire has a standard rate of fire. It has no penalties or bonuses to its attacks. Fast autofire fires more rounds per second, putting more bullets downrange. It has a -2 attack penalty to all autofire, suppressive fire, burst fire, sweepfire, and sprayfire attacks, but gains +1 dice damage on all autofire, suppressive fire, burst fire, sweepfire and sprayfire attacks.</text>
</box>
		<text>   Single</text>
<box>
<text>The firearm can only hold a single round and must be reloaded and potshot attacks.</text>
</box>
<box>
<text>The firearm has two triggers that can be depressed at the same perform two single attacks, such as single shot or potshots.</text>
</box>
<box>
<text>The bolt locks back and slams forward with every pull of the shot attacks, a −1 penalty for all multi-shot attacks and -1 Combat Point when reloading. They can&#x27;t have a round chambered and can&#x27;t be cycled without firing a round.</text>
</box>
<box>
<text>The bolt is closed on a full chamber.</text>
</box>
<box>
<text>Multishot attacks have an attack penalty based on the caliber&#x27;s or +1 added to its recoil penalty.</text>
</box>
<box>
<text>Example: 10mm Auto FMJ does 2d6+4 damage and has a recoil penalty zero from the die size.</text>
</box>
<table>
<tr><header textAlign="center">Damage</header><header textAlign="center">Penalty</header></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">1d</text><text textAlign="center">−1</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">2d</text><text textAlign="center">−2</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">3d</text><text textAlign="center">−4</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">4d</text><text textAlign="center">−5</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">5d</text><text textAlign="center">−6</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">6d</text><text textAlign="center">−8</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">7d</text><text textAlign="center">−9</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">8d</text><text textAlign="center">−10</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">9d</text><text textAlign="center">−12</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">10d</text><text textAlign="center">−15</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">11d</text><text textAlign="center">−16</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">12d</text><text textAlign="center">−18</text></tr>
</table>
<table>
<tr><header textAlign="center">Damage</header><header textAlign="center">Penalty</header></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">None/d1</text><text textAlign="center">+5</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">d2</text><text textAlign="center">+3</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">d3</text><text textAlign="center">+2</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">d4</text><text textAlign="center">+1</text></tr>
</table>
<box>
<text>When calculating recoil penalties, a character uses (Strength before coming up with the final penalty. Regardless of circumstances the maximum value for the recoil penalty is +0.</text>
</box>
		<text>   Firearms are anything but close ranged weapons, they&#x27;re designedof this, many firearms are unwieldy to use in close quarters. A character takes a −6 penalty on all ranged attacks against an adjacent creature when any of the below situations are met:</text>
<list type="unordered">
<text>Shotguns</text>
<text>Any non sawn-off barrel and any stock that isn&#x27;t a pistol grip, or folded folding stock.</text>
<text>Assault, Battle, Target, Sniper, Anti-Material, Or Designated Marsksman Rifles</text>
<text>Any stock that isn&#x27;t a pistol grip, or folded folding stock.</text>
<text>Machine Guns</text>
<text>Any</text>
<text>Rocket Launchers and Grenade Launchers</text>
<text>Any</text>
</list>
		<text>   Often a character will have two or more different types ofor necessity. The error range from ammunition only applies when it is the ammunition you&#x27;re firing. As a general rule the last round put into the magazine or firearm is the first out.</text>
		<text>   For the purpose of damage dice increases and decreases, themodified. In the case of a tie, the non-ballistic damage is the one that is modified. All damage dice are counted for the purpose of determining how many dice to use.</text>
<box>
<text>Example: 5.7x28mm AP does 2d4-1 ballistic damage and 2d4 piercing attack using this caliber, the attack would gain +3 piercing damage dice.</text>
</box>
		<text>   Some fire modes can increase the amount of damage dice that arethe caliber, including any modifiers from ammunition types, are used to calculate. These damage dice are added onto the base damage the caliber has, and not included in any calculations for when calculating bonuses to damage or damage dice from ammunition. </text>
		<text>   A single shot is the firing of a weapon at center mass of aarea. If a ranged weapon has a semi-automatic or single rate of fire it may be used to single shot. With firearms, the size of the firearm affects how many Combat Points it takes to perform a single shot attack. </text>
<list type="unordered">
<text>Diminutive to Small sized Firearms 7 Combat Points</text>
<text>Medium to Huge sized Firearms 8 Combat Points</text>
<text>Gargantuan and Larger sized 9 Combat Points</text>
</list>
<list type="unordered">
<text>Single Action (SA) All single action firearms gain a +1 attack bonus on all single shot and potshot attacks. Single action firearms with cylinders cost +1 Combat Point when performing a single shot attack.</text>
<text>Double Action/Single Action (DA/SA) All single shot attacks with double action/single action firearms after the first attack gain a +1 attack bonus. The first shot has no bonus or penalty, but the hammer may be cocked back for 1 Combat Point, giving a +1 attack bonus for the first shot.</text>
<text>Double Action (DA) Double action firearms can have their hammer cocked back for 1 Combat Point, gaining a +1 attack bonus on single shot attacks.</text>
<text>Preset Action (PA) All single shot attacks with a preset action have a +1 attack bonus.</text>
<text>Lever Action Attacks with a lever action cost 3 Combat Points more when firing from a prone position, but 1 Combat Point less when performing single shot attacks.</text>
<text>Bolt Action All single shot attacks with a bolt action have a +1 attack bonus, but cost 1 Combat Point more.</text>
<text>Open Bolt Open bolt firearms have a −2 attack penalty for single shot attacks, a −1 attack penalty for all multi-shot attacks, and cost 1 Combat Point less when reloading. They can&#x27;t have a round chambered and can&#x27;t be cycled without firing a round.</text>
<text>Telescopic Sights Telescopic sights require 6 Combat Points to acquire the sight before they can fire.</text>
</list>
		<text>   A potshot is the firing a single shot of a weapon in the generalweapon has a semi-automatic or single rate of fire it may be used to potshot. The character targets a specific creature and makes an attack roll with a −6 penalty. If the attack is successful the character may roll the standard damage. Using this attack fires a single round or shell and can only be done if the weapon has at least one in it. Potshots, for the purpose of feats, attacks, and other effects, are considered single shot attacks. The Combat Point cost for potshot attacks can not be reduced below 1 Combat Point cost.</text>
		<text>   A no-miss shot is an attack where the character places thedirectly in front of the item to be shot, and then pulls the trigger. When performing a no-miss shot against a target, the defending character gets an AoO. If this AoO is successful the no-miss shot is thwarted and the attacker wastes the Combat Points spent on the attack, but the firearm is not fired. If the AoO is unsuccessful the character can roll damage. A character must be adjacent to the target in order to perform a no-miss shot.</text>
		<text>   When a character wishes to use a called shot action ingains an attack roll bonus equal to the penalty of the called shot when they perform their AoO.</text>
		<text>   If a ranged weapon has two barrels that can be firedfirearm is fired as if it were a single shot and if the attack succeeds, the character rolls the damage twice. Double-fire uses 2 rounds of ammunition and can only be used if the weapon has 2 rounds of ammunition in it. Double-fire can also be used for underbarrel grenade launchers, mounted tasers and underbarrel firearms. When double-firing using them, there is a −4 to the attack roll for each weapon and each attack is rolled separately.</text>
		<text>   Autofiring is firing a loosely controlled burst of automaticweapon has an automatic rate of fire a character may set it on autofire. Autofire affects an area and everyone and all objects in it, not a specific creature or object. The character targets a 10&#x27; by 10&#x27; area and makes an attack roll; the targeted area has an effective DEF of 10. The recoil penalty for autofire is the CRP−7. If the attack succeeds, every creature within the affected area must make a Reflex Saving Throw [TN15]. If they succeed they take half of the weapon&#x27;s damage. Autofire uses a number of rounds dependent on the rate of fire of the gun. Slow ROF consumes 8 rounds, Medium ROF consumes 10 rounds, and Fast ROF consumes 12 rounds and can only be used if the weapon has enough rounds in it. Fast ROF gains +1 damage dice and a -2 attack penalty when attacking. Autofire can not perform called shot attacks.</text>
		<text>   Bump Fire</text>
<box>
<text>Bump firing a firearm is using the recoil of a semi-automatic for bump fire is the CRP−8. In all other respects, bump firing is the same as autofire using Medium ROF.</text>
</box>
<box>
<text>Suppressive fire is firing a tight controlled burst of automatic automatic weapon. If a ranged weapon has an automatic rate of fire, a character may use it for suppressive fire. The character makes an autofire attack as normal. If the attack succeeds they can elect to continue firing in that specific area. Any creature that enters the area immediately takes the weapon&#x27;s damage for every 5&#x27; square they step into that is currently being suppressed. Every creature that steps within the affected area must make a Will Saving Throw [TN18]. If they succeed they are Shaken for 1d3 rounds. If they fail they are Rattled for 1d3 rounds. The character performing suppressive fire can shift the area suppressed at 5&#x27; per 3 Combat Points and it takes 9 Combat Points to either sustain the suppressive fire or end it. Suppressive fire uses a number of rounds dependent on the rate of fire of the gun. Slow ROF consumes 8 rounds, Medium ROF consumes 10 rounds, and Fast ROF consumes 12 rounds and can only be used if the weapon has enough rounds in it for two consecutive uses of an autofire attack. When giving suppressive fire to an area, a character is considered flat footed. Fast ROF gains +1 damage dice and a -2 attack penalty when attacking. Supressive fire can not perform called shot attacks.</text>
</box>
<box>
<text>Sweeping fire is firing a loosely controlled burst of automatic has an automatic rate of fire a character may use it to sweeping fire. The character fires in a cone, with the total length of the cone being the ½ range increment of the weapon, rounded down to the nearest 5&#x27; up to 40&#x27; total. The recoil penalty for sweepfire is the CRP−10. If the attack succeeds against any targets caught in the arc the character may roll their damage as normal on all characters hit. Sweeping fire uses a number of rounds dependent on the rate of fire of the gun. Slow ROF consumes 12 rounds, Medium ROF consumes 15 rounds, and Fast ROF consumes 18 rounds and can only be used if the weapon has enough rounds in it. Fast ROF gains +1 damage die and a -2 attack penalty when attacking. Sweeping fire can not perform called shot attacks.</text>
</box>
<box>
<text>Sprayfiring is firing a loosely controlled burst of automatic weapon has an automatic rate of fire, a character may use it to sprayfire. The character targets a specific creature. The recoil penalty for sprayfire is the CRP−10. If the attack succeeds, the character gains +4 damage dice for the attack. Sprayfire uses a number of rounds dependent on the rate of fire of the gun.Slow ROF consumes 8 rounds, Medium ROF consumes 10 rounds, and Fast ROF consumes 12 rounds and can only be used if the weapon has enough rounds in it. Fast ROF gains +1 damage dice and a -2 attack penalty when attacking. Sprayfire can not perform called shot attacks.</text>
</box>
		<text>   Burst fire is firing a small burst of bullets at a specificcharacter may use it to burst fire. The character targets a specific creature and makes an attack roll. The recoil penalty for a two-round burst is the CRP−2. The recoil penalty for a burst with three or more rounds is the CRP−4. If the attack succeeds the character may roll their damage with extra damage dice depending on how many damage dice were rolled originally and the type of burst fire.</text>
		<text>   The dice are always the same type as used in the originalof fire of the gun. Medium ROF consumes 5 rounds, and Fast ROF consumes 6 rounds and can only be used if the weapon has enough rounds in it. However, if the firearm has a 2 or 3 round burst setting, firing a burst expends two or three rounds or shells instead of the ROF round requirements and can be used if the weapon has two or three rounds or shells in it. Slow ROF is not able to burst fire.</text>
<list type="unordered">
<text>2 Round Burst For damage with two or less dice the character gains +1 die. For three or more dice the character gains +2 dice plus 1 extra die for every three dice beyond the first three.</text>
<text>3 or 5 Round Burst For damage with two or less dice the character gains +2 dice. For three or more dice the character gains +3 dice plus 1 extra die for every three dice beyond the first three.</text>
<text>6 Round Burst For damage with two or less dice the character gains +3 dice and a -2 attack penalty. For three or more dice the character gains +4 dice plus 1 extra die for every three dice beyond the first three, and a -2 attack penalty.</text>
</list>
		<text>   Double tapping is quickly firing two bullets from a semisemi-automatic rate of fire it may be used to double tap. The character targets a specific creature and makes an attack roll. The recoil penalty for a double tap is the CRP−3. If the attack is successful the character gains extra damage dice based on the amount of damage dice they roll originally. For damage with two or less dice the character gains +1 die. For three or more dice the character gains +2 dice, plus 1 extra die for every three dice beyond the first three. The dice are always the same type as used in the original damage. Using this attack fires two bullets or shells and can only be done if the weapon has two bullets or shells in it. Ammunition that increases or decreases damage dice should be included when calculating the damage of the weapon for the purpose of how many damage dice the weapon has.</text>
		<text>   Fanning is a revolver shooting technique in which one hand holdsthe cylinder and hits the firing pin, in that order, allowing for rapid fire of a single action weapon. If a revolver has a single action rate of fire it can be used to perform a fanning attack. The character targets a specific creature, declares if they&#x27;re going to use two or three bullets or shells, and makes an attack roll. The recoil penalty for a two-round fan is the CRP−2. The recoil penalty for a three-round fan is the CRP−4. If the attack is successful the character may roll their damage with extra damage dice depending on the damage of the round and how many rounds they fired. The dice are always the same type as used in the original damage. Using this attack fires two or three bullets or shells and can only be done if the weapon has two or three bullets or shells in it.</text>
<list type="unordered">
<text>2 Round Fan For damage with two or less dice the character gains +1 die. For three or more dice the character gains +2 dice plus 1 extra die for every three dice beyond the first three.</text>
<text>3 Round Fan For damage with two or less dice the character gains +2 dice. For three or more dice the character gains +3 dice plus 1 extra die for every three dice beyond the first three.</text>
</list>
		<text>   A slamfire is a premature discharge of a firearm that occurs asslamfire rate of fire can perform a slamfire attack. The character targets a specific creature, declares if they&#x27;re going to use two or three bullets or shells, and makes an attack roll. The recoil penalty for a two-round slamfire is the CRP−4. The recoil penalty for a three-round slamfire is the CRP−5. If the attack is successful, the character may roll their damage with extra dice depending on the damage of the round and how many rounds they fired. The dice are always the same type as used in the original damage. Using this attack fires two or three bullets or shells and can only be done if the weapon has two or three bullets or shells in it.</text>
<list type="unordered">
<text>2 Round Slamfire For damage with two or less dice the character gains +1 die. For three or more dice the character gains +2 dice plus 1 extra die for every three dice beyond the first three.</text>
<text>3 Round Slamfire For damage with two or less dice the character gains +2 dice. For three or more dice the character gains +3 dice plus 1 extra die for every three dice beyond the first three.</text>
</list>
		<text>   An explosive is a weapon that effects all creatures and objectsconcussion when detonated. Its effect is broad enough that it can hurt characters just by going off close to them. Some explosives, such as grenades, can be thrown and explode when they land. Others are planted with fuses or timers and go off after a preset amount of time elapses.</text>
<box>
<text>Grenade launchers, shotguns using explosive shells, and rocket thrown grenades or they can be used to target a specific target. The square has an effective DEF of 10. If a specific target is targeted the defense of the target will be used and the attacker takes a −2 to their attack roll. If the target is hit it takes 1d6 Bludgeoning damage as well as any damage the grenade or rocket does. If the target is missed by a grenade the grenade continues for a single range increment in the direction it was fired until it either reaches the single range increment or collides with an object. If the target is missed with a rocket the rocket continues for three range increments in the direction it was fired or until it collides with an object. When either of these happen the grenade or rocket explodes as normal. All targets beyond the intended target get a Reflex Saving Throw [TN16] to dodge the grenade and a Reflex Saving Throw [TN40] to dodge the rocket. If the target fails the Reflex Saving Throw they are hit with the grenade or rocket.</text>
</box>
		<text>   A splash weapon is a ranged weapon that breaks apart on impact,creatures or objects. Most splash weapons consist of liquids in breakable containers. To attack with a splash weapon, make a ranged touch attack against the target. Thrown splash weapons require no weapon proficiency. A hit deals damage to the target twice and splash damage to all other creatures within 5&#x27; of the target. A character can instead target a specific 5&#x27; square, including a square occupied by a creature. Use the rules for thrown explosives. However, if a character targets a square, all creatures within 5&#x27; are dealt the splash damage. If the character misses the target (whether aiming at a creature or a square) check to see where the weapon lands using the rules for thrown explosives. After determining where the object landed, it deals splash damage to all creatures within 5&#x27;.</text>
		<text>   An attack with a thrown explosive is a ranged attack madeaction. If the square is within one range increment (thrown weapons have a range increment of 10&#x27;), you do not need to make an attack roll. If the target square is more than one range increment away make an attack roll. The square has an effective DEF of 10. Thrown explosives require no weapon proficiency. If the attack succeeds the explosive lands in the targeted square. If the character misses the target the explosive lands in a square nearby in a random direction. Roll a d12 and consult the diagram below to determine where the explosive lands.</text>
		<text>   After the explosive&#x27;s landing point is determined, it deals its</text>
<box>
<text>Explosives often reach out past their original blast radius and 5&#x27; outside of the blast radius per 10&#x27;. Any target caught in the wounding radius must make a Fortitude Saving Throw [TN16 (+1 per 10&#x27; of blast radius)] or be knocked prone, and a Reflex Saving Throw [TN15 (+1 per 10&#x27; of blast radius)] or take full damage. If the character passes the Reflex Saving Throw, they take half of the damage of the explosive. Only explosives that cause damage can have a wounding radius.</text>
</box>
<box>
<text>Grenades normally take 1 turn to detonate after they are thrown, spend the Combat Points it would take to throw a grenade to instead hold it at the ready, throwing it at the very beginning of their next turn. Regardless of if they throw the grenade or not, it still goes off where it is. A character can not perform any other actions but movement while they are cooking off a grenade.</text>
</box>
		<text>   The blast radius shows the range of squares that an explosivethe effect as “moving” from the targeted square following the same rules as characters for diagonal movement, with the first square counting for the first 5&#x27; of that “movement”. Below are references for both cones and blast radius. </text>
<box>
<text>Unlike aimed weapons, explosives generally hit multiple areas of GM rolls a d% to determine the locations the character is hit. The d% is rolled for every damage die that is given by the explosive to a maximum of 10. Regardless of the rolls, the character is always hit in the chest. Do not reroll if the character is hit in the same place more than once.</text>
</box>
<table>
<tr><header textAlign="center">Location</header><header textAlign="center">D% roll</header></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Chest</text><text textAlign="center">1-10</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Left Arm and Hand</text><text textAlign="center">11-32</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Right Arm and Hand</text><text textAlign="center">33-54</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Left Leg and Foot</text><text textAlign="center">55-76</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Right Leg and Foot</text><text textAlign="center">77-98</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Head</text><text textAlign="center">99-100</text></tr>
</table>
<box>
<text>When calculating Extremity damage, treat the damage from the the exact same time. The damage amount is not multiplied by the amount of locations hit.</text>
</box>
		<text>   An attack with a mortar is a ranged attack made against aby a creature. If the square is within the first range increment the mortar takes 5 rounds to land. Every range increment after the first reduces the rounds it takes to land by 1 to a minimum of 1. The square has an effective DEF of 10. If the attack succeeds the shell lands in the targeted square. If the character misses the target the shell lands in a square nearby in a random direction. Consult Table: Miss Locations. Mortars have a maximum range increment of 5.</text>
		<header level = "1">Melee Attacks</header>
		<text>   With a normal melee weapon, a character can strike any enemycharacter. The Combat Point cost for attacking with a weapon is dependent on the size of the weapon.</text>
		<text>   A character can try to trip an opponent or otherwise knock himan opponent who is one size category larger than the character, the same size, or smaller.</text>
		<text>   Making a Trip Attack</text>
		<text>   Make an unarmed melee touch attack against the target. If thecheck or STR check (whichever has the higher modifier). If the attacker and the target are different sizes, the larger combatant receives a bonus on the STR check of +4 per difference in size category. The target receives a +4 stability bonus on their check if they have more than two legs or is otherwise exceptionally stable. If the attacker wins, they trip the target. If the attacker loses, the target may immediately react and make a STR check opposed by the character&#x27;s AGL check or STR check to try to trip the character. A tripped target is prone.</text>
		<text>   Tripping with a Weapon</text>
		<text>   Some weapons, such as the chain and the whip, can be used totrip attempt the character can drop the weapon to avoid being tripped.</text>
		<text>   As a melee attack, a character may attempt to disarm theirthey knock the opponent&#x27;s weapon out of their hands and to the ground. If the character attempting to disarm is unarmed, the character will end up with the weapon in their hand. If a character is attempting to disarm the wielder of a melee weapon, follow the steps outlined here. Disarming the wielder of a ranged weapon is slightly different.</text>
		<text>   Step One</text>
		<text>   The attacker provokes an AoO from the target they are trying to</text>
		<text>   Step Two</text>
		<text>   The attacker and the target make opposed attack rolls with theircombatant with the larger weapon receives a bonus on the attack roll of +4 per difference in size category. If the target is using a weapon in two hands they get an additional +4 bonus. Also, if the combatants are different sizes the larger combatant receives a bonus on the attack roll of +4 per difference in size category.</text>
		<text>   Step Three</text>
		<text>   If the attacker beats the target&#x27;s attack roll the target isthey have the weapon now. If the attacker was armed, the target&#x27;s weapon is on the ground at the target&#x27;s feet. If the attacker fails the disarm attempt the target may immediately react and attempt to disarm the character with the same sort of opposed melee attack roll. The opponent&#x27;s attempt does not provoke an AoO from the character. If the opponent fails to disarm, the attacker does not get a free disarm attempt against the opponent.</text>
		<text>   Ranged Weapons</text>
		<text>   To disarm an opponent wielding a ranged weapon the characteropponent&#x27;s hand (see Attack an Object). If the weapon is held in two hands, it receives a +2 bonus to its DEF. If the character&#x27;s attack succeeds, the ranged weapon falls to the ground or winds up in the character&#x27;s hands (if the character made the attack unarmed). This kind of disarm attempt provokes an AoO, but if the character fails the target does not get to make a disarm attempt against him or her.</text>
		<text>   Grabbing Objects</text>
		<text>   A character can also use disarm to snatch away an object worn byabove), except for the following.</text>
		<text>   Attack of Opportunity</text>
<box>
<text>If the target&#x27;s AoO inflicts any damage, the attempt to grab the </text>
</box>
<box>
<text>If the object is well secured or otherwise difficult to grab from the object is poorly secured or otherwise easy to snatch or cut away, the attacker gets a +4 bonus.</text>
</box>
<box>
<text>Failing an attempt to grab an object doesn&#x27;t allow the target to </text>
</box>
		<text>   A character can choose to fight defensively while making a meleeattack in a round to gain a +2 dodge bonus to DEF against all melee attacks in the same round.</text>
		<text>   A character can choose to attack lightly when making a meleedoes so they reduce the Combat Point cost by 1 and take a −3 damage penalty on the attack.</text>
		<text>   A character can choose to attack heavily, throwing more of theirthe Combat Point cost by 2 and gains a +2 damage bonus to the attack.</text>
		<text>   A character can choose to full attack, throwing nearly all ofincrease the Combat Point cost by +7. This attack provokes an AoO against all enemies within range and grants 2 additional damage dice and a +4 bonus to damage.</text>
		<text>   A character can choose to attack aggressively, where theirdamage. If the attack is successful the struck character must move to any adjacent space of their choosing that is not adjacent to their attacker. Moving like this does not provoke any AoO. The attack also suffers a −2 attack penalty.</text>
		<text>   A character can choose to make a thrusting attack with aweapon deals piercing damage instead of slashing damage but takes a −2 damage penalty to the attack. Only swords and knives may use this attack.</text>
		<text>   A character can choose to make a swiping attack with a piercingslashing damage instead of piercing damage but takes a −2 damage penalty to the attack. Only spears, rapiers and knives may use this attack.</text>
		<text>   A reaction is an action where a character prepares for anBracing, Stumbling, or Predicting an enemy&#x27;s melee attack. The character declares which reaction they will prepare, and against which enemy. After they declare what kind of reaction and against which enemy, their turn immediately ends, and they are unable to make any more actions for that turn. If they are attacked by the selected enemy&#x27;s melee attack, they roll a Saving Throw that corresponds with the action. The TN is Opposing Attack Roll − 5. </text>
		<text>   Parry</text>
		<text>   Parrying is a reaction where where a character uses theirReflex Saving Throw the character is granted a +1 to their DEF, per Reflex Saving Throw Result/2, rounded down. The bonus lasts for all melee attacks until the next turn.</text>
		<text>   Brace</text>
		<text>   Bracing is a reaction where a character prepares for thecharacter is granted Damage Reduction to a single type of damage of their choice, equal to 1 per Fortitude Saving Throw Score/2, rounded down. The bonus lasts for all melee attacks until the next turn.</text>
		<text>   Predict</text>
		<text>   Predicting is a reaction where a character anticipates an attackWill Saving Throw the character gains one AoO against the attacking opponent per two attacks the opponent attempts immediately after the opponent is done attacking.</text>
		<text>   Stumble</text>
		<text>   Stumbling is a reaction where where a character uses a shield orfooting. On a successful Reflex Saving Throw, the character knocks the opposing attacking opponent to a kneeling position if they are standing, or to a prone position if they are kneeling. A character can choose which attack on which they stumble, but can only attempt to stumble once per round.</text>
		<text>   Striking for damage with punches, kicks, and head butts is muchdeals non-lethal damage and unarmed strikes use touch attack defense, instead of normal defense. Unarmed strikes count as small melee weapons for purposes of two-weapon attack penalties and so on. An unarmed attack is considered an attack made with a small weapon.</text>
		<text>   A helpless foe, who is bound, sleeping, unconscious, orcan sometimes approach a target who is unaware of their presence, get adjacent to the target, and treat them as helpless. If the target is in combat or some other tense situation and therefore in a state of acute awareness and readiness or if the target can use their AGL bonus to DEF then that target can&#x27;t be considered unaware. Any reasonable precaution taken by a target including stationing bodyguards, placing their back to a wall, or being able to make Perception checks also precludes catching that target unaware and helpless.</text>
		<text>   Regular Attack</text>
		<text>   A helpless defender has an effective DEF of 5 + their sizenot adjacent to the target, the character can attack as normal and gain a +2 bonus on the attack roll. If the character is attacking with a melee weapon, or with a ranged weapon from an adjacent square, the character can attack as normal.</text>
		<text>   Coup de Grâce</text>
		<text>   A character can use a melee weapon to deliver a coup de grâce tothat they are adjacent to the target. The character automatically hits and scores a critical strike. If the defender survives the damage they still must make a Fortitude Saving Throw [TN10 + damage dealt] or die. Delivering a coup de grâce provokes AoO from threatening foes because it involves focused concentration and methodical action. A character can&#x27;t deliver a coup de grâce against a creature that is immune to critical strikes.</text>
		<text>   A character can make an unarmed attack or use a melee weaponhelpless foe. A character can also use a melee weapon that deals lethal damage but the character takes a −4 penalty on any attempt to deal non-lethal damage with the weapon. The target has an effective DEF of 5 + their size modifier. If the character hits, the target immediately loses all of their XHP due to a non-lethal attack. Delivering a knockout blow provokes an AoO from threatening foes because it involves focused concentration and methodical action. A character can&#x27;t deliver a knockout blow against a creature that is immune to critical strikes.</text>
		<text>   Grappling means wrestling and struggling hand-to-hand. There are</text>
		<text>   Grabbing</text>
		<text>   Normally a grab is just the first step to starting a grapple. Ifher the character doesn&#x27;t actually start a grapple. However, sometimes all a character wants to do is grab the target.</text>
		<text>   Holding</text>
		<text>   Once a character has established a hold they are involved in aincluding damaging the opponent or pinning the opponent.</text>
		<text>   Grapple Checks</text>
		<text>   When a character is involved in a grapple they will need to makegrapple check is something like a melee attack roll. A character&#x27;s attack bonus on a grapple check:</text>
		<text>   BAB + FOC modifier + AGL modifier + Grapple modifier</text>
		<text>   Grapple Modifier</text>
		<text>   A creature&#x27;s size works in its favor when grappling if thatSmall or smaller size is at a disadvantage because of its size when grappling. Instead of using a creature&#x27;s size modifier on a grapple check (as would be done for a melee or ranged attack roll), use the appropriate grapple modifier from Table: Grapple modifier.</text>
<table>
<tr><header textAlign="center">Size (Example)</header><header textAlign="center">Grapple Modifier</header></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Colossal (blue whale [90&#x27; long])</text><text textAlign="center">+16</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Gargantuan (gray whale [40&#x27; long])</text><text textAlign="center">+12</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Huge (elephant)</text><text textAlign="center">+8</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Large (lion)</text><text textAlign="center">+4</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Medium-size (person)</text><text textAlign="center">+0</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Small (German shepherd)</text><text textAlign="center">−4</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Tiny (housecat)</text><text textAlign="center">−8</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Diminutive (rat)</text><text textAlign="center">−12</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Fine (horsefly)</text><text textAlign="center">−16</text></tr>
</table>
		<text>   Starting a Grapple</text>
		<text>   To start a grapple a character first needs to grab and holdmaking an unarmed melee attack. Follow these steps:</text>
		<text>   Step 1: Attack of Opportunity and Grab</text>
<box>
<text>A character provokes an AoO from the target they are trying to step 2. </text>
</box>
<box>
<text>Make an opposed grapple check. If the character succeeds, he has grapple. </text>
</box>
<box>
<text>Once the grapple has been established, the character can execute </text>
</box>
		<text>   While a character is grappling, their ability to attack others</text>
		<text>   No Threatened Squares</text>
<box>
<text>A character doesn&#x27;t threaten any squares while grappling.  Flat-footed</text>
</box>
		<text>   No Movement</text>
<box>
<text>A character cannot move while held in a grapple.  If the Character is Grappling</text>
</box>
		<text>   Damage the Opponent</text>
<box>
<text>Make an opposed grapple check; if the character succeeds, they weapon.</text>
</box>
<box>
<text>Make an opposed grapple check; if the character succeeds, both for all attacks; however, the opponent is not considered helpless. A pinned character can&#x27;t take any action except to attempt to escape from the pin. A character can&#x27;t pin any creature more than two size categories larger than itself. </text>
</box>
<box>
<text>Make an opposed grapple check. If the character succeeds, they the character, the grapple check result has to beat all their individual check results to escape. Opponents don&#x27;t have to try to hold a character if they don&#x27;t want to. Alternatively, the character can make an Acrobatics check opposed by the opponent&#x27;s grapple check to escape from the grapple. This is an attack action that the character may only attempt once per round.</text>
</box>
<box>
<text>Make an opposed grapple check. If the character succeeds, they Opponents don&#x27;t have to try to keep the character pinned if they don&#x27;t want to. The character is considered prone. Alternatively, a character can make an Acrobatics check opposed by the opponent&#x27;s grapple check to escape from the pin. This is an attack action that the character may only attempt once per round.</text>
</box>
<box>
<text>A character can draw a small or smaller weapon or object for the </text>
</box>
<box>
<text>A character can attack with a Small or smaller weapon while weapons while grappling. A character can also use small or smaller objects against a character they are grappling against, which requires an opposed grapple check. If the opponent is pinned, they can use the object against the opponent without an opposed grapple check.</text>
</box>
		<text>   If the target is already grappling someone else a character cantarget doesn&#x27;t get an AoO against the character and the character&#x27;s grab automatically succeeds. The character still has to make a successful opposed grapple check and move in to be part of the grapple.</text>
		<text>   If multiple enemies are already involved in the grapple thecheck.</text>
		<text>   Multiple Grapplers</text>
		<text>   Several combatants can be in a single grapple. Up to foursize category smaller than the character count as a half creature each; creatures that are one size category larger than the character count as two creatures; and creatures two or more size categories larger than the character count as four creatures.</text>
		<text>   When involved in a grapple with multiple opponents, theThe exception is an attempt to escape from the grapple; to escape, a character&#x27;s grapple check must beat the check individual results of all opponents.</text>
		<text>   Making an unarmed attack against an armed opponent provokes ancharacter&#x27;s attack. An unarmed attack does not provoke AoO from other foes, nor does it provoke an AoO from an unarmed foe.</text>
		<header level = "1">“Armed” Unarmed Attacks</header>
		<text>   Sometimes a character or creature attacks unarmed but the attacknatural physical weapons, for example, counts as armed. Being armed counts for both offense and defense; not only does a creature not provoke an AoO when attacking an armed foe, but a character provokes an AoO from that creature if the character makes an unarmed attack against it. An “armed” unarmed attack is considered an attack made with a small weapon.</text>
		<text>   An unarmed strike from a Medium-size character deals 1d3+POWunarmed strike will deal lethal damage before the character makes their attack roll, but the character takes a −4 penalty on the attack roll because they have to strike a particularly vulnerable spot to deal lethal damage.</text>
		<header level = "1">Called Shot</header>
		<text>   When a character attacks they are usually targeting center masstarget a specific extremity, such as an arm or leg, they may do so. Making a called shot invokes a −6 penalty for an arm or leg, a −7 penalty for a hand or foot, or a −9 penalty for the head.</text>
		<text>   If the character is hit anywhere during a called shot attackweapon and that weapon does more than 3 points of damage to that extremity then the character takes extremity damage. Called shot attacks ignore all armor Damage Reduction unless the targeted area is armored.</text>
		<header level = "1">Attacking with Two Weapons</header>
		<text>   If the character wields a second weapon in their off hand thevery difficult, however. When using both weapons in the same attack action, the character takes a −6 penalty on the regular attack or attacks with their primary hand and a −10 penalty on the attack with their off hand. A character fighting with two weapons only has to spend the Combat Points as if attacking with one weapon, but the Combat Point cost is increased by 1, for the largest weapon used.</text>
<table>
<tr><header textAlign="center">Circumstances</header><header textAlign="center">Primary Hand Melee Weapon</header><header textAlign="center">Primary Hand Ranged Weapon</header><header textAlign="center">Off Hand</header></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Normal penalties</text><text textAlign="center">−6</text><text textAlign="center">−6</text><text textAlign="center">−10</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Off-hand melee weapon is small or smaller</text><text textAlign="center">−4</text><text textAlign="center">−5</text><text textAlign="center">−8</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Two-Weapon Melee Fighting feat</text><text textAlign="center">−4</text><text textAlign="center">−6</text><text textAlign="center">−4</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Two-Weapon Ranged Fighting feat</text><text textAlign="center">−6</text><text textAlign="center">−5</text><text textAlign="center">−7</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Improved Two-Weapon Melee Fighting feat</text><text textAlign="center">−2</text><text textAlign="center">−6</text><text textAlign="center">−4</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Improved Two-Weapon Ranged Fighting feat</text><text textAlign="center">−6</text><text textAlign="center">−4</text><text textAlign="center">−4</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Off-hand melee weapon a is small or smaller and Two-Weapon Melee</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Off-hand melee weapon is Small or smaller and Improved Two-Weapon</text></tr>
</table>
	</item>
</body>