<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<body>
	<item>
		<header level = "0">Environments</header>
<text><b>Environments</b></text>
		<header level = "1">Darkness and Light</header>
		<text>   It&#x27;s a rare mission that doesn&#x27;t end up in the dark somewhere the radius that a light source illuminates and how long it lasts. The light sources listed are for light being broadcast in a circle from their origin.</text>
<table>
<tr><header textAlign="center">Item</header><header textAlign="center">Light</header><header textAlign="center">Duration</header></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Candle</text><text textAlign="center">10&#x27;</text><text textAlign="center">12 hours</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Torch</text><text textAlign="center">20&#x27;</text><text textAlign="center">2 hours</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Lantern</text><text textAlign="center">40&#x27;</text><text textAlign="center">1 day</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Match</text><text textAlign="center">10&#x27;</text><text textAlign="center">1 round</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Lighter</text><text textAlign="center">10&#x27;</text><text textAlign="center">1 hour</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Road Flare</text><text textAlign="center">40&#x27;</text><text textAlign="center">1 hour</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Chemical Light Stick</text><text textAlign="center">10&#x27;</text><text textAlign="center">6 hours</text></tr>
</table>
<box>
<text>Darkness and light levels are sectioned off into four levels, </text>
</box>
<list type="unordered">
<text>Shadows Shadow light means that there are shadows that are cast, usually by a singular, weak light source. All targets within shadow light have 20% concealment.</text>
<text>Near Total Darkness Near total darkness means that there is a light source, but it may be far away, or extremely weak. All targets within near total darkness light have 40% concealment.</text>
<text>Total Darkness Total darkness means there is no light source whatsoever to illuminate the area. All targets within total darkness light have 50% concealment.</text>
</list>
<box>
<text>Darkness and sight can be modified in a number of ways. Below are through racial abilities, or through equipment.</text>
</box>
<list type="unordered">
<text>Thermal Vision Thermal vision works by viewing the heat signatures of various objects in relation to the objects around them, making warmer objects such as creatures stand out. Thermal vision negates all vision penalties for darkness and smoke with regard to people, creatures, and objects warmer than the surrounding scenery, within it&#x27;s stated range.</text>
<text>Low Light Vision Low light vision is the ability to recognize color and read in near total darkness, within it&#x27;s stated range. It functions as standard vision in shadows, or near total darkness.</text>
<text>Darkvision Darkvision is the ability to see in total darkness, but only in black and white, within it&#x27;s stated range. </text>
<text>Blindsight Blindsight is the ability to perceive targets and fight in total lack of visibility through environment such as smoke or total darkness, or through a lack of sight from blindness. It has a range of 35&#x27;.</text>
</list>
<box>
<text>Temperature Ranges: Extremely Cold, Very Cold, Cold, Mild, Hot, </text>
</box>
		<header level = "1">Catching on Fire</header>
		<text>   Characters exposed to open flames might find their clothes,are allowed a Reflex Saving Throw [TN15] to avoid this fate. If a character&#x27;s clothes or hair catch fire, they take 2d6 points of fire damage immediately. In each subsequent round, the burning character must make another Reflex Saving Throw. Failure means they take another 2d6 points of fire damage that round. Success means that the fire has gone out. That is, once the character succeeds at the Saving Throw, they are no longer on fire. A character on fire may automatically extinguish the flames by jumping into enough water to douse him or herself. If no body of water is at hand, rolling on the ground or smothering the fire with blankets or the like permits the character another Saving Throw with a +4 bonus.</text>
		<header level = "1">Starvation and Thirst</header>
		<text>   Sometimes characters might find themselves without food and fluids and 8NV worth of food per day to avoid the threat of starvation. In very hot climates characters need two or three times as much water to avoid dehydration. A character can go without water for one day plus a number of hours equal to their CON score. After this, the character must make a CON check each hour [TN10 (+1 for each previous check)] or take 1d6 points of CHP damage. A character can go without food for six days, in growing discomfort. After this, the character must make a CON check each day [TN10 ( +1 for each previous check)] or sustain 1d3 points of CHP damage. If a character eats at least 8NV worth of food during this time, this time is reset. Damage from thirst or starvation cannot be recovered until the character receives water or food, as needed.</text>
		<header level = "1">Suffocation and Drowning</header>
		<text>   A character in an airless environment (underwater, vacuum) can score. After this period of time the character must make a CON check [TN10] every round to continue holding their breath. Each round, the TN of the CON check increases by 1. When the character fails one of these CON checks they begin to suffocate or drown. In the next round the character falls unconscious. In the following round, the character is considered dying. In the third round after failing the check the character dies of suffocation or drowning.</text>
		<header level = "1">Smoke</header>
		<text>   Characters breathing heavy smoke or similar toxic gases must check)], each round or spend that round choking and coughing. Characters who choke for 2 consecutive rounds take 1d6 points of damage. Smoke also obscures vision, giving one-half concealment (20% miss chance) to characters within it.</text>
		<header level = "1">Strangulation</header>
		<text>   When a character is strangled by an instrument or an attacker, of the same size category or one size category larger or smaller. The strangling attempt incurs an Attack of Opportunity. To begin the choke, the attacker must succeed at an opposed grapple check. If the grapple succeeds, the attacker can choose to deal normal unarmed damage as well as choke the target. The target can hold his of her breath for a number of rounds equal to their CON score. After this period of time, the target must make a CON check [TN10 ( +1 for each previous check)] every round to continue holding their breath. The target begins to suffocate on a failed check (see Suffocation and Drowning). If at any time the target breaks free or slips free of the grapple the stranglehold is broken (although any damage that was dealt remains). Note that a grappled target who is not pinned can use a melee attack to strangle their attacker.</text>
		<header level = "1">Falling</header>
		<text>   A character takes 1d6 points of damage for every 10&#x27; of a fall, Reflex Saving Throw [TN10 (, +1 for each 10&#x27; fallen)], this damage is halved. If the Saving Throw fails full damage is applied. A character can make an Acrobatics check [TN15] to treat a fall as if it were 10&#x27; shorter when determining the damage and Reflex Saving Throw TN required by the fall.</text>
		<header level = "1">Falling Objects</header>
		<text>   Objects that fall upon characters (or creatures or vehicles) on Table: Damage from Falling Objects. Objects deal the initial damage given in Table: Damage from Falling Objects if they fall 10&#x27; or less. An object deals an additional 1d6 points of damage for every 10&#x27; increment it falls beyond the first (to a maximum of 200d6 points of damage). Objects of Fine size are too small to deal damage, regardless of the distance fallen. A successful Reflex Saving Throw indicates that the target takes half damage. The size of the falling object determines the Saving Throw TN. If the Saving Throw fails by 10 or more, and the object is at least three size categories larger than the character, the character is pinned under the fallen object. A pinned character cannot move but is not helpless. The character can make a STR check to lift the object off of themselves or an Acrobatics check [TN25] to get out from underneath. The GM can modify the TNs for these checks based on the circumstances.</text>
<table>
<tr><header textAlign="center">Object Size</header><header textAlign="center">Examples</header><header textAlign="center">Initial Damage</header><header textAlign="center">Reflex Save TN</header><header textAlign="center">STR Check TN</header></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Fine</text><text textAlign="center">Penny</text><text textAlign="center">0</text><text textAlign="center">—</text><text textAlign="center">—</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Diminutive</text><text textAlign="center">Paperweight</text><text textAlign="center">1</text><text textAlign="center">0</text><text textAlign="center">—</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Tiny</text><text textAlign="center">Wrench</text><text textAlign="center">1d3</text><text textAlign="center">5</text><text textAlign="center">—</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Small</text><text textAlign="center">Vase</text><text textAlign="center">1d4</text><text textAlign="center">10</text><text textAlign="center">5</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Medium</text><text textAlign="center">Briefcase</text><text textAlign="center">1d6</text><text textAlign="center">15</text><text textAlign="center">10</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Large</text><text textAlign="center">Garbage can</text><text textAlign="center">2d6</text><text textAlign="center">20</text><text textAlign="center">20</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Huge</text><text textAlign="center">Oil barrel</text><text textAlign="center">4d6</text><text textAlign="center">25</text><text textAlign="center">25</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Gargantuan</text><text textAlign="center">Piano</text><text textAlign="center">8d6</text><text textAlign="center">30</text><text textAlign="center">30</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Colossal</text><text textAlign="center">Vehicle</text><text textAlign="center">10d6</text><text textAlign="center">35</text><text textAlign="center">40</text></tr>
</table>
		<header level = "1">Poison</header>
		<text>   When a character takes damage from an attack with a poisoned or is otherwise poisoned the character must make a Fortitude Saving Throw. If the character fails, they take the poison&#x27;s full initial damage (usually ability damage). If they succeed, they take half of the initial damage, rounded up. The character faces secondary damage 30 seconds later. This secondary damage also requires a Fortitude Saving Throw to avoid by half.</text>
		<text>   Poisons are detailed in the Craft (Chemical) Skill description by application to a weapon. Poisonous gases must be inhaled to be effective. Poisonous solids are usually ingested with food or drink.</text>
		<text>   A character has a 5% chance (roll a d%) to expose themselves to otherwise readies it for use. Additionally, a character who rolls a 3 on an attack roll with a poisoned weapon must succeed at a Reflex Saving Throw [TN15] or accidentally poison him or herself with the weapon.</text>
		<text>   Creatures with natural poison attacks are immune to their own immune to poison. Certain kinds of creatures are immune to poison, as detailed in their descriptions, though it is conceivable that a special poison could be synthesized specifically to harm them.</text>
		<header level = "1">Disease</header>
		<text>   When a character is exposed to a treatable disease, the victim must make this roll when they come into contact with an infectious carrier, touches an item smeared with diseased matter, consumes food or drink tainted with a disease, or suffers damage from a contaminated attack. If the character succeeds the disease has no effect on them—the character&#x27;s immune system fights off the infection. If the character fails the Saving Throw they take damage after an incubation period; once per day thereafter, the character must succeed at a Fortitude Saving Throw to avoid secondary damage. Two successful Saving Throws in a row indicate that the character has fought off the disease and recovers, taking no more damage.</text>
		<text>   The characteristics of some treatable diseases are summarized</text>
<table>
<tr><header textAlign="center">Disease</header><header textAlign="center">Type</header><header textAlign="center">Fort Save TN</header><header textAlign="center">Incubation Period</header><header textAlign="center">Initial Damage</header><header textAlign="center">Secondary Damage</header></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Anthrax</text><text textAlign="center">Gas/Liquid</text><text textAlign="center">16</text><text textAlign="center">1d2 days</text><text textAlign="center">1 CON</text><text textAlign="center">1d4 CON*</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Smallpox</text><text textAlign="center">Gas/Contact</text><text textAlign="center">15</text><text textAlign="center">2d4 days</text><text textAlign="center">1 STR and 1 CON</text><text textAlign="center">1d2 STR and 1d2 CON</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Pneumonia</text><text textAlign="center">Gas</text><text textAlign="center">12</text><text textAlign="center">1d4 days</text><text textAlign="center">1 STR</text><text textAlign="center">1d3 STR and 1d3 CON</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Hantavirus</text><text textAlign="center">Liquid</text><text textAlign="center">14</text><text textAlign="center">1 day</text><text textAlign="center">1d2 STR</text><text textAlign="center">1d2 STR* and 1d2 CON*</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Necrotizing Fasciitis</text><text textAlign="center">Contact</text><text textAlign="center">13</text><text textAlign="center">1d6 days</text><text textAlign="center">1 CON</text><text textAlign="center">1d3 CON*</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">West Nile virus</text><text textAlign="center">Liquid</text><text textAlign="center">12</text><text textAlign="center">1d4 days</text><text textAlign="center">1 DEX and 1 CON</text><text textAlign="center">1d2 DEX and 1d2 CON*</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Gastroenteritis</text><text textAlign="center">Solid</text><text textAlign="center">13</text><text textAlign="center">1 day</text><text textAlign="center">1 STR and 1 DEX</text><text textAlign="center">1 STR and 1d3 DEX</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Bubonic Plague</text><text textAlign="center">Contact</text><text textAlign="center">17</text><text textAlign="center">1d6 days</text><text textAlign="center">1d3 CON</text><text textAlign="center">1d6 CON and 1d3 STR</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Cholera/Dysentery</text><text textAlign="center">Solid</text><text textAlign="center">14</text><text textAlign="center">1 day</text><text textAlign="center">Sickened</text><text textAlign="center">1 DEX and 1 STR</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Food Poisoning</text><text textAlign="center">Solid</text><text textAlign="center">15</text><text textAlign="center">1d4 days</text><text textAlign="center">Sickened</text><text textAlign="center">1d2 DEX</text></tr>
</table>
		<text>   The disease&#x27;s method of delivery—ingested, inhaled, or via an inhaled can also be ingested (and vice versa).</text>
		<text>   The amount of time before initial damage takes effect if the</text>
		<text>   The damage the victim takes after the incubation period.</text>
		<text>   The amount of damage the character takes one day after taking taken each day the Saving Throw fails.</text>
		<header level = "1">Acid</header>
		<text>   Corrosive acids deal damage each round of exposure. The amount</text>
<table>
<tr><header textAlign="center">Acid Strength</header><header textAlign="center">Splash Attack*</header><header textAlign="center">Total Immersion*</header></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Mild</text><text textAlign="center">2d6</text><text textAlign="center">4d6</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Potent</text><text textAlign="center">4d6</text><text textAlign="center">8d6</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Concentrated</text><text textAlign="center">6d6</text><text textAlign="center">12d6</text></tr>
</table>
		<text>   Acid damage from an attack reduces hit points. A character fully exposure than a character splashed with acid. The fumes from most acids are inhaled poisons. Those who come within 5&#x27; of a large body of acid must make a Fortitude Saving Throw [TN15] or take 1 point of temporary CON damage. A second Saving Throw must succeed 1 minute later to avoid taking another 1d4 points of CON damage.</text>
		<header level = "1">Electricity</header>
		<text>   Electrical hazards come in many forms, including stun guns,Electricity Damage gives damage values for various electrical hazards based on relative voltage. A character can make a Fortitude Saving Throw to reduce the damage by half. If that character is grounded or is otherwise insulated from the current, a successful Saving Throw indicates that no damage is suffered.</text>
<table>
<tr><header textAlign="center">Type</header><header textAlign="center">Examples</header><header textAlign="center">Damage</header><header textAlign="center">Fort Save TN</header></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Jolt</text><text textAlign="center">Car battery, stun gun</text><text textAlign="center">1d3</text><text textAlign="center">10</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Low voltage</text><text textAlign="center">Fuse box, electrical socket</text><text textAlign="center">3d6</text><text textAlign="center">15</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">Medium voltage</text><text textAlign="center">Industrial transformer, electric fence</text><text textAlign="center">10d6</text><text textAlign="center">20</text></tr>
<tr>
<text textAlign="center">High voltage</text><text textAlign="center">Power line, electric chair, lightning</text><text textAlign="center">15d6</text><text textAlign="center">25</text></tr>
</table>
		<header level = "1">Weightless &amp; Microgravity</header>
		<text>   Weightless and microgravity environments function very weight a character is carrying in a weightless or microgravity environment, they are never encumbered. Their movement cost to walk or move while crouched is doubled.</text>
	</item>
</body>