<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<body>
	<item>
		<header level = "0">Miscellaneous Actions</header>
<box>
<text>Miscellaneous Actions  Some actions don&#x27;t fit neatly into the above categories. Some of the options described below are actions that take the place of or are variations on the actions described earlier. For actions not covered in any of this material, the GM determines how long such an action takes to perform and whether doing so provokes AoO from threatening enemies.</text>
</box>
		<header level = "1">Use Feat or Skill </header>
		<text>   Certain feats let a character take special actions in combat.character a bonus when attempting something they can already do. Some feats aren&#x27;t meant to be used within the framework of combat. The individual feat descriptions tell a character what they need to know about them.</text>
		<text>   Most uses of skills in a combat situation are attack actions butskill provides the time required to use it.</text>
		<header level = "1">Attacks of Opportunity</header>
		<text>   The melee combat rules assume that combatants are activelyspecial for their character to be on the defensive. Sometimes, however, a combatant in a melee lets their guard down and doesn&#x27;t maintain a defensive posture as usual. In this case combatants near him or her can take advantage of this lapse in defense to attack for free. These attacks are called AoO.</text>
		<text>   A character can use a melee weapon to make AoO whenever thecan make AoO with unarmed attacks if the character&#x27;s unarmed attacks count as armed.</text>
		<text>   A character threatens the squares into which they can make aGenerally, that&#x27;s all squares adjacent to the character&#x27;s position. An enemy that takes certain actions while in a threatened square provokes an AoO from the character. A character can only make AoO with melee weapons, never with ranged weapons. Facing and the penalty that comes with it apply with AoO.</text>
		<text>   Two actions can provoke an AoO:</text>
<list type="unordered">
<text>Moving out of a Threatened Square When a character moves out of a threatened square that character generally provokes an AoO. There are two important exceptions. A character doesn&#x27;t provoke an AoO if the character withdraws. If the character doesn&#x27;t start in a threatened square, but moves into one, the character may stop there without provoking an AoO, although further movement does provoke an AoO.</text>
<text>Performing an Action that Distracts the Character Some actions when performed in a threatened square provoke AoO because they make a character divert their attention from the fight at hand. Using a ranged weapon, in particular, provokes AoO.</text>
</list>
		<text>   An attack of opportunity is a single unmodified melee attack,not have to make an AoO if they don&#x27;t want to. Making an AoO takes no Combat Points.</text>
		<header level = "1">Extra Effort</header>
		<text>   An Extra Effort action is an action where a character pushesmore accomplished in a single round. The character receives 5 extra Combat Points for the round. The following round they are considered flat-footed, have a −4 attack penalty for all attacks, receive half their normal Combat Points (rounded down), and may not take the extra effort action. After the character goes through one round in this state, they return to normal.</text>
	</item>
</body>