<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<body>
    <item>
        <header>Leveling Characters</header>
        <text>   A character receives 6 Character Option Points per level. Characters receive 6 Character Option Points, the base amount of XHP, and skill points, as well as two feats, when they gain a level. They can elect to spend Character Option points to increase the amount of XHP, Skill points, Base Attack bonus, or Base Save Bonus they receive when they level up.
        </text>
        <text>   When playing a game that starts at a level higher than level 1, it is highly recommended that you level the character a single level at a time, going through the normal leveling procedures for each level.
        </text>
        <header level="1">Experience Points</header>
        <text>   The Experience Point amount required to reach a specific level are calculated using this formula:</text>
        <text textAlign="center"><font fontName="secondary">((Level - 1) × (Level - 1)) × 500</font>
        </text>
        <box>
            <header>Character Level Examples</header>
            <text>Below are some examples of various analogs to levels in Ops and Tactics. This is by no means an exhaustive list.</text>
            <text><b>Level 1-2</b> Lightly Skilled Combatants(Rookie Police Officers, Rank Private to Private First Class in Armed Forces)</text>
            <text><b>Level 3-5</b> Moderately Skilled Combatants(Veteran Police Officers and Field Training Officers, Rank Corporal to Sergeant First Class in Armed Forces)</text>
            <text><b>Level 6-7</b> Very Skilled Combatants(S.W.A.T. Team Police Officers, Rank Master Sergeant to Sergeant Major in Armed Forces, Special Forces Groups)</text>
            <text><b>Level 8-10</b> Highly Skilled Combatants(Black Ops Groups, John Wick, Solid Snake, Big Boss, Tequila Yuen, Vincent, Barry Burton, Leon Kennedy, Nicholas J. Fury, Rally Vincent)</text>
            <text><b>Level 11+</b> Extremely Skilled Combatants(Tier 1 Operator Groups, Bean Bandit)</text>
        </box>
    </item>
</body>