<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<body>
    <item>
        <header>Linguistics (None) Trained Only</header>
        <text>   This skill allows a character to speak, read, and write a language. The Linguistics skill doesn't work like a standard skill.
        </text>
        <list type="unordered">
            <text>A character automatically knows how to read and write their native language; the character does not need ranks to do so.</text>
            <text>To read, write and speak a language costs 1 rank.</text>
            <text>A character never makes Linguistics checks. A character either knows how to read and write a specific language or doesn't.</text>
            <text>A character may choose any language, modern or ancient. The GM may rule that a character can't learn a specific language due to the circumstances of the campaign.</text>
        </list>
        <header level="1">Language Groups</header>
        <text>   There are thousands of languages to choose from when a character buys ranks in Linguistics. A few are listed here, sorted into their general language groups. A language's group doesn't matter when a character is buying ranks in Linguistics. This list is by no means exhaustive—there are many more language groups and most groups contain more languages than those listed here.
        </text>
        <list type="unordered">
            <text><b>Greek</b></text>
            <text><b>Gaelic</b></text>
            <text><b>Chinese</b> Cantonese, Mandarin,</text>
            <text><b>Germanic</b> English, German</text>
            <text><b>Indic</b> Hindi, Punjabi</text>
            <text><b>Pashto</b></text>
            <text><b>Japanese</b></text>
            <text><b>Korean</b></text>
            <text><b>Romantic</b> French, Italian, Latin*, Portuguese, Spanish</text>
            <text><b>Semitic</b> Arabic, Hebrew</text>
            <text><b>Slavic</b> Czech, Polish, Russian</text>
            <text><b>Turkish</b></text>
        </list>
        <text>*This is an ancient language. In the modern world it is spoken only by scholars, or in some cases by small populations in isolated corners of the world.</text>
    </item>
</body>