<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<body>
    <item>
        <header>Perception</header>
        <text>  This skill allows a character to notice fine details and alert them to danger. Perception covers all five senses, including sight, hearing, touch, taste, and smell.</text>
        <text>   Perception has a number of uses, the most common of which is an opposed check versus an opponent's Stealth check to notice the opponent and avoid being surprised. If you are successful, you notice the opponent and can react accordingly. If you fail, your opponent can take a variety of actions, including sneaking past you and attacking you.</text>
        <text>   Perception is also used to notice fine details in the environment. The TN to notice such details varies depending upon distance, the environment, and how noticeable the detail is. The following table gives a number of guidelines.
        </text>
        <table>
            <tr>
                <header>Perception</header>
                <header textAlign="center">TN</header>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Gunfire</text>
                <text textAlign="center">-40</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Hear the sound of battle</text>
                <text textAlign="center">-20</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Notice the stench of rotting garbage</text>
                <text textAlign="center">-15</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Detect the smell of smoke</text>
                <text textAlign="center">0</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Hear the details of a conversation</text>
                <text textAlign="center">0</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Notice a visible creature</text>
                <text textAlign="center">0</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Determine if food is spoiled</text>
                <text textAlign="center">5</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Hear the sound of footsteps</text>
                <text textAlign="center">10</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Hear a gun being loaded and/or cocked</text>
                <text textAlign="center">10</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Hear the details of a whispered conversation</text>
                <text textAlign="center">15</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Find the average concealed door</text>
                <text textAlign="center">15</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Hear the sound of a key being turned in a lock</text>
                <text textAlign="center">20</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Notice a typical secret compartment or a simple trap</text>
                <text textAlign="center">20</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Notice a pickpocket</text>
                <text textAlign="center">Opposed by Stealth</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Notice a creature using Stealth</text>
                <text textAlign="center">Opposed by Stealth</text>
            </tr>
        </table>
        <text textAlign="center">Table 46: Perception TN</text>
        <table>
            <tr>
                <header>Perception Modifiers</header>
                <header textAlign="center">TN</header>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Distance to the source, object, or creature</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+3 per 10 feet</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Through a closed door</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+5</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Through a wall</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+10 per foot of thickness</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Favorable conditions</text>
                <text textAlign="center">-2</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Unfavorable conditions</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+5</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Terrible conditions</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+10</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Creature making the check is distracted</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+5</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Creature making the check is asleep</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+10</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Creature or object is camouflaged</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+15</text>
            </tr>
        </table>
        <text textAlign="center">Table 47: Perception TN Modifiers</text>
        <text>   Favorable and unfavorable conditions depend upon the sense being used to make the check. For example, bright light might increase the TN of checks involving sight, while torchlight or moonlight might give a penalty. Background noise might reduce a TN involving hearing, while competing odors might penalize any TN involving scent.</text>
        <text>   Terrible conditions are like unfavorable conditions, but more extreme. For example, candlelight for TNs involving sight, a roaring engine for TNs involving hearing, and an overpowering stench covering the area for TNs involving scent.
        </text>
        <text><b>Special</b></text>
        <text>   Creatures with the scent special quality have a +8 bonus on Perception checks made to detect a scent.
        </text>
        <text><b>Try Again</b></text>
        <text>   Yes. You can try to sense something you missed the first time, so long as the stimulus is still present.
        </text>
        <text><b>Time</b></text>
        <text>   Most Perception checks are reactive, made in response to observable stimulus. Intentionally searching for stimulus costs 6 CP.
        </text>
    </item>
</body>