<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<body>
    <item>
        <header>Speechcraft (CHA)</header>
        <text>The character is skilled at detecting falsehoods and true intentions, threaten and persuade others, solve arguments, and gather valuable information from people.
        </text>
        <header level="1">Lying</header>
        <text>With a successful Speechcraft check, you can convince your opponent that what you are saying is true. Speechcraft checks to lie are modified depending upon the plausibility of the lie.
        </text>
        <table>
            <tr span="2">
                <header textAlign="center">Lie Modifier</header>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>The target wants to believe you</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+5</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>The lie is believable</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+0</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>The lie is unlikely</text>
                <text textAlign="center">-5</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>The lie is far-fetched</text>
                <text textAlign="center">-15</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>The lie is impossible</text>
                <text textAlign="center">-25</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>The target is drunk or impaired</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+5</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>You possess convincing proof</text>
                <text textAlign="center">up to +10</text>
            </tr>
        </table>
        <text textAlign="center">Table 53: Speechcraft, Lie Modifiers</text>
        <header level="1">Secret message</header>
        <text>   You can use the Speechcraft skill to pass a hidden message to another character without others understanding your true meaning. This check is TN15 for simple messages and TN20 for complex messages. If you are successful, the target automatically understands you, assuming you are speaking in a language that it understands. If your check fails by 5 or more, you deliver the wrong message. Other creatures that hear the message can decipher the message by succeeding at an opposed Speechcraft check against your Speechcraft result.
        </text>
        <header level="1">Diplomacy</header>
        <text>   You can also use this skill to persuade others to agree with your arguments, to resolve differences, and to gather valuable information or rumors from people. This skill is also used to negotiate conflicts by using the proper etiquette and manners suitable to the problem.</text>
        <text>   You can change the initial attitudes of non-player characters with a successful check. The TN of this check depends on the creature's starting attitude toward you, adjusted by its CHA modifier.
        </text>
        <table>
            <tr>
                <header>Starting Attitude</header>
                <header textAlign="center">Diplomacy TN</header>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Hostile</text>
                <text textAlign="center">30 + character's CHA modifier</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Unfriendly</text>
                <text textAlign="center">25 + character's CHA modifier</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Indifferent</text>
                <text textAlign="center">20 + character's CHA modifier</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Friendly</text>
                <text textAlign="center">15 + character's CHA modifier</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Helpful</text>
                <text textAlign="center">5 + character's CHA modifier</text>
            </tr>
        </table>
        <table>
            <tr span="2">
                <header textAlign="center">Diplomacy Modifiers</header>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Give simple advice or directions</text>
                <text textAlign="center">-5</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Give detailed advice</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+0</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Give simple aid</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+0</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Reveal an unimportant secret</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+5</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Give lengthy or complicated aid</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+5</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Give dangerous aid</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+10</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Reveal secret knowledge</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+10 or more</text>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <text>Give aid that could result in punishment</text>
                <text textAlign="center">+15 or more</text>
            </tr>
        </table>
        <text textAlign="center">Table 54: Speechcraft, Diplomacy TN and Modifiers</text>
        <text>   If you succeed, the character's attitude toward you is improved by one step. For every 5 by which your check result exceeds the TN, the character's attitude toward you increases by one additional step. A creature's attitude cannot be shifted more than two steps up in this way, although the GM can override this rule in some situations. If you fail the check by 4 or less, the character's attitude toward you is unchanged. If you fail by 5 or more, the character's attitude toward you is decreased by one step.</text>
        <text>   If a creature's attitude toward you is at least indifferent, you can make requests of the creature. This is an additional Speechcraft check, using the creature's current attitude to determine the base TN, with one of the following modifiers. Once a creature's attitude has shifted to helpful, the creature gives in to most requests without a check, unless the request is against its nature or puts it in serious peril. Some requests automatically fail if the request goes against the creature's values or its nature, subject to GM discretion.
        </text>
        <header level="1">Confuse</header>
        <text>   You can also use this skill to utterly puzzle all targets through the use of words and bearings. All hostile targets within 50' of the character, who have a have INT score above 2, and are able to see, hear, and understand the character are affected. To confuse, the character makes a Speechcraft check [TN18]. If they succeed, the target can try to resist by making a Will Save [TN(10 + 1 for every 1 point the character succeeded over the Confuse TN]. If the targets fail, they are considered Confused for 1d6 rounds. The effect ends immediately if the target is attacked. The character cannot take 10 on this check.
        </text>
        <header level="1">Captivate</header>
        <text>   You can also use this skill to captivate targets through sheer force of personality, a winning smile, and fast talking. All targets within 50' of the character, who have a have INT score above 2, and are able to see, hear, and understand the character are affected. To captivate, the character makes a Speechcraft check [TN14]. If they succeed, the target can try to resist by making a Will Save [TN(10 + 1 for every 1 point the character succeeded over the Confuse TN]. If the targets fail, they are considered Stunned, and receive a -4 to all perception checks for 1d3 rounds. The effect ends immediately if the target is attacked. The character cannot take 10 on this check.
        </text>
        <header level="1">Bolster</header>
        <text>   You can also use this skill to restore the morale of those who can hear you. All friendly targets within 50' of the character, who have a have INT score above 2, and are able to see, hear, and understand the character are affected. To bolster, the character makes a Speechcraft check [TN18]. If they succeed, all friendly and neutral targets that are shaken, rattled, stunned, unnerved, cowering, dazed, frightened, or panicked return to normal. The character cannot take 10 on this check.
        </text>
        <text><b>Time</b></text>
        <text>   Attempting to deceive someone takes at least 1 round, but can possibly take longer if the lie is elaborate (as determined by the GM on a case-by-case basis) Delivering a secret message generally takes twice as long as the message would otherwise would take to relay. To influence a creature's attitude takes 1 minute of continuous interaction. Making a request of a creature takes 1 or more rounds of interaction, depending upon the complexity of the request. Confusing, Captivating, and Bolstering targets takes 8 CP.
        </text>
        <text><b>Try again?</b></text>
        <text>   If you fail to deceive someone, any further checks made to deceive them are made at a −10 penalty and may be impossible (GM discretion). Secret messages can be relayed again if the first attempt fails. You cannot use Speechcraft to influence a given creature's attitude more than once in a 24 hour period. If a request is refused, the result does not change with additional checks, although other requests might be made. You can attempt to intimidate, confuse, or captivate an opponent again, but each additional check increases the TN by 5.You can attempt to bolster again, but each additional check increases the TN by 2 This increase resets after one hour has passed.
        </text>
    </item>
</body>