<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<body>
    <item>
        <header>Treat Injury (WIS)</header>
        <text>   The character knows how to use first aid kits to restore health, treat poison, and stabilize characters.
        </text>
        <text><b>Long Term Care [TN20]</b> With a first aid kit this check allows a patient to restore HP and Ability Points at an advanced rate, 3HP/3AP extra per full day of rest. A new check is required each day. You can tend to as many patients as you have ranks. The patient must spend all their time resting and the user must dedicate 30 minutes of care per day per patient.
        </text>
        <text><b>Restore Hit Points [TN20]</b> With a first aid kit you can restore 1d4 HP to a character. This may be done only once per day per character. This costs 12 CP.
        </text>
        <text><b>Stop Bleeding [TN10]</b> With a first aid kit or applicable supplies you can stop a character from bleeding for 5d4 minutes. This costs 8 CP.
        </text>
        <text><b>Revive a Dazed, Stunned, or Unconscious Character [TN17]</b> With a first aid kit you can remove the dazed, stunned, or unconscious condition from a character. You can't revive a character that is at −1 or lower HP without stabilizing them first. This costs 8 CP.
        </text>
        <text><b>Stabilize Dying Character [TN15]</b> With a first aid kit you can tend to a dying character. The character stops losing HP. This costs 8 CP. Unlike the other actions, this action cannot be performed without a first aid kit.
        </text>
        <text><b>Surgery [TN25]</b> With a surgery kit you can conduct field surgery, allowing you to realign broken bones, remove bullets or shrapnel, and stitch up grievous wounds. Surgery restores 4d6 HP and removes all bleed damage. Undergoing surgery causes fatigue for 24 hours, minus 2 hours for every point above the TN the surgeon achieves. Surgery requires 1d4 hours plus one for each point the character's HP has fallen below 0.
        </text>
        <text><b>Treat Poison [TN15]</b> With a first aid kit, you make a check when a poisoned character makes a Fortitude Save against a poison's secondary effect. If you succeed, you add your Treat Injury rank as a bonus to their Fortitude Save. This costs 8 CP.
        </text>
        <text><b>Try Again?</b></text>
        <text>   Yes for restoring HP, reviving dazed, stunned, or unconscious characters, stabilizing dying characters, stop bleeding and surgery. No for all other uses of the skill.
        </text>
        <text><b>Time</b></text>
        <text>   Treat Injury checks take different amounts of time based on the task at hand.
        </text>
    </item>
</body>