<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<body>
    <item>
        <header>Using Skills</header>
        <text>   To make a skill check, roll <font fontName="secondary">3d6+skill modifier</font></text>
        <text>   The skill modifier is equal to the sum of the skill ranks, ability modifier, and any miscellaneous modifiers.</text>
        <list type="unordered">
            <text><b>Skill Ranks</b> A character's rank in a skill is based on the number of skill points the character has invested in the skill. Some skills may be used even if the character has no ranks in the skill; doing this is known as making an untrained skill check. When making a skill check, a character adds the skill's rank to the roll as part of the skill modifier. Ranks indicate how much training or experience a character has with a given skill.</text>
            <text><b>Ability Modifier</b> The ability modifier used in the skill check is the modifier for the skill's key ability (the ability associated with the skill's use). The key ability of a skill is noted in its description.</text>
            <text><b>Miscellaneous Modifiers</b> Miscellaneous modifiers include bonuses provided by feats, and penalties such as the ones associated with the non-proficient use of armor, among others.</text>
        </list>
        <header level="1">Opposed Checks</header>
        <text>   Some skill checks are opposed checks. They are made against a randomized number, usually another character’s skill check result.</text>
        <text>   For ties on opposed checks, the character with the higher key ability score wins. If those scores are the same, roll again.</text>
        <header level="1">Taking 10</header>
        <text>   When your character is not being threatened or distracted, you may choose to take 10. Instead of rolling for the skill check, calculate the result as if you had rolled a 10. For many routine tasks, taking 10 makes them automatically successful. Distractions or threats (such as combat) make it impossible for a character to take 10.</text>
        <header level="1">Assisting</header>
        <text> A character can assist another character in their skill checks when applicable. To assist a character, the DC of the task is divided by 4, and the assisting character rolls their skill check in the applicable skill. If the character succeeds, the original character making the check gets a +1 bonus. For every full success beyond the original, the original character gains an additional +1 bonus.</text>
        <box>
            <text>Example: <i>If the assist TN is 4 and the assisting character rolls a 12, the original character gains a +3 bonus on the check from the assistance.</i></text>
        </box>
    </item>
</body>
